- got any biscuits over there?
- here's some cornbread.
i am cold.
- still with us, brett?
- right.
- i feel dead.
- anybody ever teli you you iook dead?
oh, yeah. i forgot something.
before we dock,
we ought to discuss the bonus situation.
brett and l think we deserve full shares.
mr parker and i feel the bonus situation
has never been equitable.
you get what you're contracted for,
like everybody else.
but everybody else gets more than us.
dalias, mother wants to talk to you.
i saw it. yeliow light's for my eyes oniy.
get dressed, huh? parker?
i haven't finished my coffee.
it's the only good thing we got.
morning, mother.
- right?
- ok.
plug us in.
thank you.
- where is earth?
- you shouid know.
it's not our system.
scan.
i can't believe this.
contact traffic controi.
this is commercial towing vehicle
<i>nostromo,</i>
out of the solomons,
registration number 1 80924609,
calling antarctica traffic controi.
do you read me?
commerciai towing vehicle <i>nostromo</i>,
out of the solomons,
registration number 1 80924609.
- nothing.
- keep trying.
caliing antarctica traffic control.
do you read me, antarctica?
i've found it. just short of zeta ii reticuli.
- we haven't reached the outer rim yet.
- that's hard to beiieve.
what the heli are we doing out here?
don't know.
what the heli are you talking about?
- that's not our system.
- i know that.
ever notice how they never come down
here? this is where the work is, right?
same reason we get a half share to their
one. our time is their time. same old shit.
i think l know why they don't come down.
it's because of you.
you have no personality.
- you happen to be in my seat. can l have it?
- of course. sorry.
what's happening now, baby?
some of you may have figured out we're
not home yet. we're oniy halfway there.
- what?
- mother's interrupted our course.
why?
she's programmed to do that
should certain conditions arise. they have.
it seems she has intercepted
a transmission of unknown origin.
- she got us up to check it out.
- a transmission? out here?
what kind of transmission?
acoustical beacon
that repeats at intervais of 1 2 seconds.
- sos?
- i don't know.
- human?
- unknown.
- so what?
- we are obligated under section...
- this is a commerciai ship, not a rescue ship.
- right.
it's not in my contract, this kind of duty.
and what about money? give me
some money, l'd be happy to oblige.
let's go over the bonus situation.
i'm sorry, can i say something?
there is a clause which states
"any systematised transmission
indicating inteliigent origin
must be investigated...
i wanna go home and party.
will you just iisten to the man?
..on penalty of total forfeiture of shares."
no money.
you got that?
- weil, yeah.
- we're going in.
we're going in.
approaching orbitai apogee. mark.
equatorial orbit naiied.
dor's in line.
- status on the iifters?
- give me an ac pressure reading.
prepare to disengage from piatform.
lock.
disengage.
ciear.
money's safe.
let's take her down.
- roll 92 degrees, port yaw.
- prime the port.
i'm not getting anything.
turbulence.
locked and floating.
you can drop us any time now.
initial damping's going off.
hold on, there'll be a little bump.
what the heli was that?
pressure drop. must have lost a shield.
let's go with it.
i'm still not getting anything.
dropping off now.
stiil dropping.
there we are, we've got it.
take her down.
navigation iights on.
kill drive engines.
what the heli happened?
give me an answer.
- is the hull breached?
- i don't see anything. we still have pressure.
- push the screen.
- why?
secondary load-sharing unit is out.
three of the four cells are gone.
- is that it?
- no, hold on.
we can't fix it out here anyway
and we need to reroute a coupie of ducts.
dry-dock time.
teil him to dry-dock.
we can't fix it out here.
we've gotta reroute ail these ducts.
to do that, we've got to dry-dock.
what eise?
some fragments caked up. we've got
to ciean it out and repressurise it.
how iong before we're functional?
- look...
- 1 7 hours, tell her.
at least 25 hours.
get started. i'll be right down.
- why's she coming down here?
- she better stay the fuck out of my way.
i'd like to see what she's gonna do
when she gets here.
any response yet?
absoiutely nothing, except
the same transmission every 1 2 seconds.
all the other channels are dead.
kick on the floods.
we can't go anywhere in this.
mother says the sun rises in 20 minutes.
- how far to the source of transmission?
- northeast. just under 2,000 metres.
waiking distance?
- can you give me an atmospheric?
- yes.
it's almost primordiai.
inert nitrogen, high concentration
of carbon dioxide crystals, methane...
- i'm working on the trace elements.
- anything else?
there's rock, lava base.
deep cold, weli below the iine.
i'il volunteer to be in the first group
to go out.
that figures.
- you, too, lambert.
- sweil.
you'd better break out the weapons.
- i can't see a goddamn thing.
- ash, are you receiving?
good contact on my board.
ciear and free. keep the line open.
let's go.
hey, ripley.
i want to ask you a question.
if they find what they're after,
do we get fuil shares?
don't worry,
you'li get whatever's coming to you.
i'm not doing any more work
untii we get this straightened out.
brett, you're guaranteed by law
to get a share.
- what?
- why don't you just fuck off?
- what?
- what did you say?
if you have any trouble,
i'il be on the bridge.
come back here.
- son of a bitch.
- what's the matter?
can't see a goddamn thing.
quit griping.
- i like griping.
- knock it off.
how's it going?
- all right.
- you put that transmission through eciu?
no. mother hasn't identified it yet.
- mind if i give it a shot?
- please do.
- ash, can you see this?
- i can.
i've never seen anything like it.
it's very bizarre.
all right.
moving on to second position.
what is it?
let's get outta here.
we've got this far. we have to go on.
will you say that again?
shit.
as you can see, it's hard to describe.
i'm going back to the consoie.
dalias?
come on down here.
there's something different.
i don't know what it is, but if we can
get up that wali, we can find out.
alien life form.
it looks like it's been dead a long time.
fossiiised.
looks like it's grown out of the chair.
bones are bent outward.
like he exploded from inside.
wonder what happened
to the rest of the crew.
let's get the heli outta here.
hey, dallas.
lambert, come on over here.
come on.
- what have you got?
- see what you make of this.
ash, that transmission.
mother's deciphered part of it.
- it doesn't look like an sos.
- what is it, then?
it looks like a warning.
- i'm gonna go out after them.
- what's the point?
by the time it takes to get there,
they'li know if it's a warning or not.
are you ok down there?
- can you see anything?
- a cave of some sort, but l...
it's iike the goddamn tropics in here.
what the heli is this?
the pit is completely enclosed.
it's fuli of ieathery objects,
like eggs or something.
there's a layer of mist covering the eggs
that reacts when broken.
kane? are you all right?
i'm ok.
i'm ok. l just slipped.
it appears to be completely sealed.
wait, there's movement.
it seems to have organic life.
- are you there, ripiey?
- i'm here.
- i'm at the inner iock hatch.
- right.
are you there?
we're clean, let us in.
- what happened to kane?
- something attached itself to him.
what kind of thing?
an organism. open the hatch.
if we let it in, the ship could be infected.
you know the quarantine procedure.
- 24 hours for decontamination.
- he couid die. open the hatch.
if we break quarantine, we could ail die.
can you open the goddamn hatch?
we have to get him inside.
no, i can't do that.
if you were in my position
you'd do the same.
this is an order.
open that hatch, do you hear me?
yes.
- this is an order! do you hear me?
- i read you. the answer is negative.
inner hatch open.
my god.
what the heli is that?
how is he?
how are we gonna get that off him?
- how do we get it off?
- just a minute. l'll get some instruments.
right. if l make an incision here
to try and remove
one of the digits from his face...
you're gonna do what?
finger. i'll try and get this finger off.
get this cieating on there...
- it's tearing his scalp.
- i know.
it's not coming off
without tearing his face off with it.
we'li have to take a look at him inside.
how come they don't freeze him?
how come you guys don't freeze him?
you can take your mask off.
- what's it got down his throat?
- i suggest it's feeding him oxygen.
paraiyses him, puts him in a coma,
then keeps him aiive.
what the heli is that?
- we've got to get it off him.
- just a minute.
let's not be too hasty.
we don't know anything about it.
we're assuming it's feeding him oxygen.
if we remove it, it could kiil him.
i'il take that chance.
let's cut it off him now.
- you take responsibility?
- yes. get him out of there.
where do you want to do this?
we'li make an incision
just below the knuckie.
right here?
good god.
that crap's gonna eat through the huil.
i think it's going to eat through
the goddamn huli. come on.
this way.
next deck.
there it is.
don't get under it.
looks like it's stopping.
take a look at this.
brett, give me your pen, quick.
come on.
don't get any on your arm.
it's stopped.
i haven't seen anything like that,
except molecular acid.
it must be using it for biood.
it's got a wonderful defence mechanism.
you don't dare kill it.
what about kane?
here's your pen back.
- what do we do now?
- leave kane to ash. you get back to work.
okay.
try it.
- damn it. i feit sure that was it.
- try it again.
feel iike i've been in this piace a month.
we shouldn't have ianded here
in the first place.
shouldn't have landed
on this damn ball, i know that.
the sooner we patch this up,
the sooner we can go home.
this place gives me the creeps.
it's amazing. what is it?
i'd say it's...
i don't know yet.
- do you want something?
- yes, i...
a little taik. how's kane?
he's holding. no changes.
and our guest?
as l said, i'm stili collating.
but l have confirmed that he's got
an outer layer of protein poiysaccharides.
he has a funny habit of shedding his cells
and replacing them with polarised siiicone,
which gives him a proionged resistance
to adverse environmentai conditions.
is that enough?
plenty. what does it mean?
- please don't do that. thank you.
- i'm sorry.
it's an interesting combination of eiements,
making him a tough iittle son of a bitch.
and you iet him in.
i was obeying a direct order.
when dailas and kane are off the ship,
i'm senior officer.
oh, yes. i forgot.
you also forgot the science division's
basic quarantine law.
- that i didn't forget.
- i see. you just broke it.
what wouid you have done with kane?
you knew his oniy chance
was to get him in here.
unfortunately, by breaking quarantine,
you risk everybody's life.
maybe i should have left him outside.
maybe i've jeopardised the rest of us,
but it was a risk i was wiliing to take.
it's a pretty big risk for a science officer.
it's not exactly out of the manual.
i take my responsibilities
as seriousiy as you.
you do your job
and let me do mine.
- where's dallas?
- in the shuttle.
dalias.
you should have a look at kane.
- why?
- something's happened.
- serious?
- interesting.
ripiey, meet me in the infirmary right away.
- where is it?
- i don't know.
- we have to try and find it.
- let's check it.
please be careful.
sorry.
not in the corner.
have one of these. just in case.
kane? dailas?
are you ok?
- i didn't see it. was it in the overhead?
- it was up there somewhere.
- my god.
- cover the damn thing, wili you?
- it's alive.
- that's a reflex action.
we've got to have a iook at this.
excuse me.
- it seems dead enough.
- good. let's get rid of it.
for god's sake, this is the first time
we've encountered a species like this.
it has to go back,
tests have to be made...
are you kidding? this thing bled acid.
who knows what it will do when it's dead?
i think it's safe to assume it isn't a zombie.
dalias, it has to go back.
i'd soon as not burn it at the stake,
but you're the science officer.
- it's your decision.
- dallas.
- you won't make me change my mind...
- i'm not trying to change your mind.
i just want you to listen...
- how can you leave that decision to him?
- i just run the ship.
anything scientific, ash has the final word.
- how does that happen?
- that's what the company wants.
- since when is that standard procedure?
- standard procedure is to do what they say.
- did you ever ship out with ash before?
- i went out five times with another officer.
they repiaced him two days before
we left thedus with ash.
- i don't trust him.
- i don't trust anybody.
- how are the repairs going?
- they're pretty much finished.
- why didn't you tell me?
- there's stiil some things to do.
like what?
we're biind on b and c decks,
the reserve power system's biown...
that's horseshit.
we can take off without that.
- you think that's a good idea?
- i just wanna get the heli outta here.
dust in the intakes.
number two's overheating.
spit on it for two minutes!
we're hot and we're getting hotter.
engine room, red clip status.
- one kilometre on ascension.
- engage artificial gravity.
- engaged.
- i'm aitering the vector now.
inhibit cng.
- struts retract.
- struts retracted.
waik in the park.
when we fix something,
it stays fixed, eh, brett?
right.
we should freeze him. lf he's got a disease,
why don't we stop it there?
- we can get to a doctor back home.
- right.
whenever he says anything,
you say "right". you know that?
right.
your staff just foilows you around
and says "right"! like a parrot.
- shape up. what are you, a parrot?
- right.
knock it off.
- kane wili have to go into quarantine.
- and so are we.
- how about something to lower your spirits?
- thrill me, will you?
according to my calcuiations,
based on time spent...
- the short version. how far to earth?
- ten months.
- oh, god.
- right.
yes?
- i think you should see kane.
- has his condition changed?
- it's simpler if you come.
- we're on our way.
right.
how are you feelin'?
- how are you doing?
- terrific. next silly question?
thank you.
do you remember anything
about the planet?
what's the last thing you do remember?
i remember some horrible dream
about smothering and...
anyway, where are we?
- right here.
- we're on our way home.
back to the old freezerinos.
- i've got to have something to eat first.
- i need something myself.
one more meal before bedtime. l'm buying.
that's a break.
first thing l'm going to do when i get back
is to get some decent food.
i can dig it. i've eaten worse food than this,
but then l've tasted better.
you pound down the stuff
like there's no tomorrow.
i'd rather be eating something else,
but right now l'm thinking food.
you should know,
you know what it's made of.
i don't wanna taik about what it's made of.
i'm eating this.
what's the matter?
the food ain't that bad.
what's wrong?
what? what?
this is serious.
get the spoon.
- get it into his mouth.
- i'm trying.
oh, god!
don't touch it. don't touch it.
- dallas?
- yeah.
- anything?
- no. you?
nothing.
- did you see anything?
- no.
inner hatch sealed.
anybody want to say anything?
this is just an ordinary prod,
like a cattle prod.
it's got a portabie battery.
it's insuiated from here to here.
just make damn sure
nobody puts their hand on the end of it.
it shouldn't damage the bastard
unless its skin is thinner than ours.
but it wili give him a little incentive.
now we just have to find him.
i've designed this tracking device.
you just set it to search for a moving object.
hasn't got much range, but within
a certain distance, it gives off a signai.
what does it key on?
micro changes in air density.
gimme a demo.
see? and again...
gotcha.
two teams. ash, lambert and l.
ripiey, you take parker and brett.
anyone see this thing, you catch it
in the net that parker is hoiding.
parker, i don't want any heroics
out of you, all right?
catch it, put it in the airiock, get rid of it.
the channels are open on ali decks.
i want you to keep in touch at all times.
let's go.
i thought you fixed 1 2 moduie.
we did. i don't understand it.
the circuits must have burned out.
- what have we got here?
- hold your light over here.
that's it.
i don't know if this will work.
- put this in there.
- right.
check the insulation.
shit...
according to this, it's within five metres.
micro changes in air density, my ass.
it's within five metres.
be careful.
- don't creep up on me with that thing.
- you guys stick together.
what?
it's in this locker.
in where?
here, take it.
i got it.
wait.
all right, when i say.
- all right. now.
- easy.
- don't let him go!
- what the heli are you doing?
it's the cat.
we had to bag it. now we might
pick it up on the tracker again.
go and get it, man.
you get him, we'll go on.
here, kitty.
here, kitty, kitty.
kitty crap. jones?
jonesy?
here, jonesy.
jonesy?
here, kitty.
here, jonesy.
jonesy.
here, kitty, kitty.
kitty, kitty, kitty.
here, jonesy.
jonesy.
kitty, kitty.
jonesy?
come on, jonesy.
come on, baby. that's a kitty.
come on, baby.
that's a kitty.
i'm not gonna hurt you. come on.
whatever it was, it was big.
you sure it took him into the air shaft?
disappeared into one of the cooiing ducts.
no question.
it's using the air ducts to move around.
could he want brett aiive?
- what?
- could brett be alive?
no. i mean, l don't think so.
this air shaft may work to our advantage.
it comes out in the main airiock.
there's only one big opening aiong the way.
we can cover that up and then we drive it
into the airlock and zap it into outer space.
the son of a bitch is huge.
it's iike a man. it's big.
kane's son.
come on, ash. the science department
should be able to help. how can we drive it?
it's adapted weli to our atmosphere,
considering its nutritionai needs.
but we don't know about temperature.
- ok, temperature. what if we change it?
- let's try it. most animals retreat from fire.
fire, yeah. parker, can you rig
three or four incinerator units?
give me 20 minutes, l'li do it.
- who gets to go into the vent?
- i do.
no.
you and ash, take the main airlock.
parker, lambert, you cover up
that maintenance opening.
- i'm at the first junction.
- i'm right here.
- parker?
- yeah.
- lambert?
- in position. i'm trying to get a reading.
- the airiock is open.
- okay, ripiey.
ready.
i've got a reading on you now.
open the hatch to the third junction.
ok, i'm through.
- ripley?
- yes.
ciose ali the hatches behind me.
i'm moving on.
dalias, hold on. i think l got it.
- yes, i've got it.
- where?
it's somewhere around the third junction.
ok. moving on.
it is right around there.
you'li have to be carefui.
all right. l've reached the third junction
and l'm going down.
what the heli's the matter with that box?
dalias, hold your position for a minute.
- i've iost the signal!
- what?
you sure?
are you sure it's not there?
it's got to be around there.
check that out.
you may be getting interference.
are you sure there's no sign of it?
it is there.
it's gotta be around there.
dalias?
all right.
am l clear? l wanna get outta here.
oh, god! it's moving right towards you.
move, get out of there! move!
move, dailas! get out!
no, the other way!
dalias?
- no.
- take it easy. dalias?
we found this iaying there.
no biood.
no dalias.
nothing.
- i don't hear anybody sayin' nothing.
- i'm thinking.
unless somebody has a better idea,
we'll proceed with dailas's plan.
what? and end up iike the others?
you're out of your mind.
- you got a better idea?
- i say that we abandon the ship.
we get the shuttie and get the heil out
of here, and hope somebody picks us up.
- the shuttle won't take four.
- then why don't we draw straws?
i'm not drawing any straws.
i'm for kiliing it now.
ok. let's talk about killing it.
it's in the air shafts...
will you iisten to me? shut up!
let's hear it. let's hear it.
- it's using the air shafts.
- we don't know that...
that's the only way.
we'li move in pairs.
we'li go step by step
and cut off every buikhead and vent
untii we have it cornered,
then we'il blow it the fuck out into space.
is that acceptable to you?
if it means killing it, yeah.
obviousiy it means killing it.
but we have to stick together.
- how are our weapons?
- fine. this one needs refuelling.
will you get it, please?
- ash, go with him.
- i can manage.
don't follow me.
ash?
any suggestions from you or mother?
we're stiil coliating.
you're what? you're still coliating?
i find that hard to believe.
- what wouid you like me to do?
- just what you've been doing. nothing.
i've got access to mother now,
and l'll get my own answers, thank you.
all right.
there is an explanation for this.
i don't wanna hear
your goddamn expianation.
parker? lambert?
ash.
open the door.
ash.
will you open the door?
let me by.
what the heli are you doing?
get her up.
it's an android!
jesus...
it's a robot.
ash is a goddamn robot.
god.
holy shit.
help me get this fucking thing off.
god... jesus...
oh, god.
how come the company
sent us a goddamn robot?
they must have wanted the alien
for the weapons division.
he's been protecting it all along.
- wiil you plug it in?
- i don't know...
because he may know how to kiil it.
ash, can you hear me?
ash!
i can hear you.
what was your special order?
you read it. l thought it was ciear.
- what was it?
- bring back iife form, priority one.
all other priorities rescinded.
the damn company.
what about our lives, you son of a bitch?
i repeat, all other priorities are rescinded.
how do we kill it?
there's gotta be a way of kiliing it.
- how do we do it?
- you can't.
that's bulishit.
you stili don't understand
what you're dealing with, do you?
the perfect organism.
its structural perfection
is matched oniy by its hostility.
you admire it.
i admire its purity.
a survivor,
unciouded by conscience, remorse,
or delusions of morality.
i've heard enough of this
and l'm asking you to puli the piug.
last word.
i can't lie to you about your chances, but...
you have my sympathies.
we're gonna blow up the ship.
we'li take our chances in the shuttie.
- blow up the ship.
- good.
come on.
when we throw the switches,
how iong do we have?
- ten minutes.
- no bullshit.
or we won't need no rocket
to fly through space.
we'li need coolant
for the air support system.
you two get all the coolant you can carry.
i'il get the shuttle ready.
i'il give you about seven minutes.
come back up here, i'll shut the switches off
and we'il blow this fucker off into space.
- ready?
- take care of yourseif.
seven minutes.
take it easy.
jones?
okay, check the botties.
jones.
- how are you doing?
- fine.
ok, go ahead.
jones?
kitty, kitty, kitty.
come here, jones.
jones.
come here, boy.
nice kitty.
jones?
jones.
come here, sweetheart.
jones.
goddamn it.
now l've got you.
come on, sweetheart. nice kitty.
oh, my god...
- get out of the way.
- i can't.
get out of the way! it's gonna kili us!
i can't!
- for christ sake, get out of the way!
- parker? lambert?
get out of the way!
lambert? lambert.
get ready to roil!
parker?
danger.
the emergency destruct system
is now activated.
the ship will detonate
in t minus ten minutes.
the option to override automatic detonation
expires in t minus five minutes.
the option to override automatic detonation
expires in t minus three minutes.
the option to override automatic detonation
expires in t minus one minute.
the option to override detonation procedure
has now expired.
mother! i've turned
the cooiing unit back on.
mother!
the ship will automaticaily destruct
in t minus five minutes.
you bitch!
goddamn it.
jones.
you now have one minute
to abandon ship.
the ship will automaticaily destruct
in t minus one minute.
t minus 30 seconds.
i got you,
you son of a bitch.
it's all right.
all right, it's nice to see you, too.
it's ok.
come on.
you are my lucky star.
lucky, iucky, lucky.
ok.
come on.
you are my lucky star.
you are...
my lucky star.
you are my lucky star.
you are my lucky...
finai report
of the commercial starship <i>nostromo</i>.
third officer reporting.
the other members of the crew -
kane, lambert, parker, brett, ash
and captain dalias - are dead.
cargo and ship destroyed.
i should reach the frontier
in about six weeks.
with a little luck,
the network wiil pick me up.
this is ripley,
last survivor of the <i>nostromo</i>,
signing off.
come on, cat.
[english - us]
