enemy at the gates
i am a stone.
i do not move.
very slowly, i put snow in my mouth.
then he won't see my breath.
i take my time.
i let him come closer.
i have only one bullet.
i aim at his eye very gently.
my finger presses on the trigger.
i do not tremble.
i have no fear.
i'm a big boy now.
ready, vassili?
now, vassili. fire!
fire, vassili! fire!
come on, pick your feet up.
get on your feet.
prepare to board the train.
you there, come along with me now.
this way, pal.
all civilians, get out!
make way, let the civilians off.
this is a military convoy.
no one stays on board
but our valiant soldiers.
this is a convoy to stalingrad.
only for the soldiers of the red army.
no one stays on board
but our valiant soldiers.
all aboard!
autumn, 1942.
europe lies crushed
beneath the nazi jackboot.
the german third reich
is at the height of its power.
hitler's armies are charging
through the heart of the soviet union
towards the oil fields of asia.
one last obstacle remains.
a city on the volga where
the fate of the world is being decided.
stalingrad.
the red army and all citizens
of the soviet union
must defend every inch of soviet soil.
must fight to the last...
glorious comrade stalin has ordered
not another step backwards,
so the people of the soviet union
shall be free.
let's go forwards, comrades.
not a step backwards.
listen to these letters sent by russian
mothers to their sons on the front.
volodya, our child,
i know that it is for our motherland...
i know it is for our motherland
that you are giving your life.
everyone here knows
that you will not fall back.
everyone here is proud of you.
your father is dead.
your brothers are dead.
avenge us on the hordes of fascists.
nobody move! stay on the boat!
get back or i'll shoot.
get back from the rails or we'll shoot.
shoot the traitors!
prepare to disembark!
come on, come on! move!
come on, comrades. come on!
move or you'll be shot!
over here, stretcher.
- the one with the rifle shoots.
- one out of two gets a rifle.
the one without follows him.
when the one with the rifle gets killed,
the one who is following
picks up the rifle and shoots.
the one with the rifle shoots.
the one without follows him.
when the one with the rifle gets killed,
the one who is following
picks up the rifle and shoots.
the one with the rifle shoots.
soldiers of the glorious red army,
from now on,
it is either victory or death.
- those who retreat...
- i need a rifle.
- ...will be shot.
- i need a rifle.
there will be no mercy
for cowards and traitors.
it's hopeless, comrades. get back.
fall back! fall back!
it's no good. get back. get back.
in the name of the soviet union,
not a step backwards, or we shoot!
- no retreat. not a step back.
- no mercy.
deserters will be shot.
- fire!
- fire!
no mercy for cowards.
russians, surrender.
you will see your home again.
this is not your war.
join your german comrades.
they understand your suffering
and will care more for you
than your own officers,
who are only sending you to your death.
the third reich is not your enemy.
the enemy is bloodthirsty stalin
and his bolshevik gang...
fire!
you'll get us caught,
comrade commissar.
with your permission,
comrade commissar.
which one do you think
i should i aim at first?
you should wait till there's an explosion.
- do you know how to shoot?
- a little.
damn!
don't shoot. don't shoot.
he's looking at us.
thank you, comrade commissar.
danilov. political officer,
second class, 21 st infantry.
vassili zaitsev.
on this day, september 20th, 1942,
a young shepherd boy from the urals
arrived in the city of stalingrad
on the banks of the volga.
his name is vassili zaitsev.
like thousands before him, he came
to answer comrade stalin's call.
armed only with a rifle, he quickly
made the fascist invader realize
that from now on he would be punished
for every step he took in the motherland,
that from here on
the only way was back.
what do you think?
i think comrade commissar
has been overgenerous.
let me go!
by order of comrade stalin,
no civilian can leave the city.
get back there!
move back!
stand away, or we will open fire.
stand away!
keep back!
get back or we shoot.
back! keep back, there!
make way for comrade stalin's envoy.
i carried out my orders.
i sent in all of my boys.
but the germans engulfed us.
they have artillery, aircraft, tanks.
- and me, what did i have?
- a sacred duty to resist.
i have to report to the boss.
perhaps you would prefer
to avoid the red tape.
my name is
nikita sergeyevich khrushchev.
i've come to take things in hand here.
this city is not kursk,
nor is it kiev, nor minsk.
this city is stalingrad.
stalingrad!
this city bears the name of the boss.
it's more than a city, it's a symbol.
if the germans capture this city,
the entire country will collapse.
now, i want our boys
to raise their heads.
i want them to act like they have balls.
i want them to stop shitting their pants.
that's your job.
as political officers,
i'm counting on you.
you, what's your suggestion?
shoot all the other generals who have
retreated and their chiefs of staff, too.
make some examples.
deport the families of the deserters...
that's all been done.
give them hope.
here, the men's only choice
is between german bullets and ours.
but there's another way,
a way of courage.
a way of love of the motherland.
we must publish the army newspaper
again, we must tell magnificent stories,
stories that exalt sacrifice, bravery.
we must make them believe
in a victory.
we must give them hope, pride,
a desire to fight.
yes.
we need to make examples,
but examples to follow.
what we need are heroes.
do you know any heroes around here?
yes, comrade. i know one.
that's me. vassili zaitsev. that's me.
no, you're not dreaming. it's your name.
we made the front page.
they haven't changed a word.
do you have any idea what this means?
it's not the back page.
it's not the second page.
- it's the front page. the front page!
- front page.
they're going to reprint
our article everywhere,
in the caucasus, in the crimea,
even in the urals.
tomorrow morning, stalin himself
will be sitting over breakfast,
reading my words,
memorizing your name.
we're famous, vassili.
khrushchev loved the article.
he's promoted me to the general staff
and you to sniper division.
- well, that's good.
- it's very good.
- it's very good. it's great!
- it's very great!
- it's great!
- it's great!
it's great for both of us
because we did it together. together.
well, now, admittedly,
i did all the hard work.
you know, you're very lucky
i can't fight back.
- why's that?
- because khrushchev told me
to make sure nothing happens to you.
- you're too important.
- i'm too valuable.
yes. careful of my glasses, please,
they're new.
sorry, sir.
- i'm famous.
- i'm famous.
- we're famous.
- i'm famous.
vassili, the young shepherd
from the urals,
killed his 12th german officer today.
used to hunt wolves,
now he shoots fascists.
- today vassili zaitsev shot his 23rd...
- one more colonel shot by...
he is an example to us all.
today vassili zaitsev
killed his 32nd general.
...thirty-sixth german officer...
...the germans you have killed?
today vassili zaitsev killed...
...eleven dog tags retrieved
by sniper vassili zaitsev...
more and more men and women,
fighters from all branches
of our armed forces,
volunteer to join the sniper division
and learn the skills of vassili zaitsev.
i am a stone.
i breathe slowly.
i aim at the eye.
so it is you.
the great vassili zaitsev.
my mother makes the best potatoes
and bacon in town.
sounds good.
when she sees you,
she won't believe her eyes.
- how many today?
- only two.
and the last one,
why didn't you shoot him?
he was only a foot soldier.
it wasn't worth giving away my position.
bless you.
we know how much we owe you.
we pray for you every day.
every evening we listen to them
talk about you on radio moscow.
thanks.
you've certainly managed well
down here.
my parents used to store furniture
down here before the war.
sacha, drop that right now.
it's loaded.
- this way, comrade commissar.
- thank you, comrade.
good evening.
comrade zaitsev.
my god, where does
all this mail come from?
from all over the country,
mrs. filipov, from all over.
this one's from the workers
of the kuzbass.
they want to name their mine
after vassili.
right, let's start with the miners.
come on, let's get to work.
- dear comrades from the kuzbass...
- kuzbass.
...i thank you for your letter of praise.
- praise?
- r-a-i-s-e.
and
i hope that i can live up
to your expectations.
a-t-i-o-n-s.
expectations.
you're interested in german literature,
mrs. filipov?
it's all right. it's our neighbor.
right. where were we?
- tania, we have guests.
- expectations. your offer to name...
i recognize you.
it's vassili zaitsev.
i saw your picture in the paper.
thank you for everything you're doing.
- and this is his friend, commissar...
- danilov.
danilov.
tania's like a daughter to me.
she used to take care of sacha
when i worked at the factory.
she even taught him german.
all these books are hers.
- they're yours?
- she studied german at the university.
- which university?
- moscow.
moscow.
- shouldn't we...
- yes, let's continue.
your offer to name your mine
after me is
a great honor.
h-o-n.
- yes, i know, honor.
- very good.
shouldn't we try and make the point
that i'm not the only one fighting?
that's an excellent idea, vassili.
excellent.
we can take it even further, though.
yeah, we can take it further.
your battle for the production of coal
is as worthy as mine.
there's no "k" in coal.
just one "i."
that's it.
tell me if i'm going too fast.
- no, you're not going too fast.
- are you sure?
i just thought...
ls there any other improvements?
why don't you get some rest?
these letters can wait until tomorrow.
we should carry on. we're not tired.
thank you, mrs. filipov.
these people took the trouble
to write to us.
tomorrow, we may not be around
to write back.
i was expecting someone else.
certainly not someone so prestigious.
i imagine you have your reasons
for getting yourself involved
in this hellish situation.
my army is not designed
for this kind of fighting.
yesterday, yet again,
i had to promote 25 sergeants
to replace the officers shot down
by their sharpshooters.
those snipers are demoralizing
my people.
this city is no more
than a heap of ruins.
but the führer's persisting.
he has made it a personal matter
between stalin and himself.
we should trust the führer's instinct.
he always managed
to lead us to victory.
we shall be back home for christmas.
how are you going to go about
finding this young russian?
i'll fix it so that he's the one
who finds me.
vassili! vassili!
- come on! time to get up.
- what?
they have a problem in the
department store sector.
they need us. come on.
look, vassili, he's hiding
in the department store, over there.
so far this morning, he's knocked off
five officers plus two machine gunners.
look! third floor.
- fourth window from the left.
- fourth window from the left.
see him?
yeah, i see him.
- there, you got him!
- great shot.
let's go get his dog tag.
goodbye, comrade commissar.
thank you for your hospitality,
mrs. filipov.
you can borrow whatever you like.
i'm not sure what they would say
to me at headquarters
if i came back with an armful
of goethe and schiller.
there's some marx, too.
you were assigned to civil defense
at the 12th district?
no, i volunteered.
it's such a coincidence
meeting you like this.
comrade khrushchev was telling me
just yesterday
how desperately we're in need
of operators who speak german.
i can't. our militia is responsible for
all the people in this neighborhood.
we're already desperately short of men.
we can take care of that.
we'll give you a dozen soldiers
for every one that speaks german.
i'd rather stay and fight.
serving the headquarters is fighting.
you'd be far more useful there.
you stay here. you cover us.
- all right.
- we go.
take care.
ludmilla, come on.
take the stairway.
- it's a trap.
- i know.
move back.
he's still here.
- they're coming straight for us.
- ludmilla, stay where you are.
he's over there somewhere.
we have to get out of here!
- we have to get out of here!
- just stay where you are!
- what are we gonna do?
- ludmilla, stay where you are!
fuck this, i'm going.
ludmilla, no!
what does this mean?
"a little shepherd from the urals
receives a new sniper's rifle."
"a mosin nagant 7.62,
with its 3.5-power pu telescope,"
"pride of precision of soviet production."
- i've seen that rifle close up.
- have you?
i even touched it.
i know him well, vassili zaitsev.
ludmilla and anton were killed today.
- and it was my fault.
- no. i'm sure that's not true.
there was a german sniper.
i walked them right into his trap.
- what else can you tell me?
- he didn't relocate.
a sniper who doesn't relocate
isn't normal.
he was very good.
it wasn't just his shooting,
it was his instinct.
he was a step ahead of me all the time.
that's because
he knows everything about you.
his name is konig. major konig.
they've sent him here to...
to find you.
at first, we weren't sure
if the information was reliable.
it seems he's come all the way
from berlin to stop you.
you've caused them
so many sleepless nights,
they've sent their top marksman
after you.
- so, what do we know about him?
- he's a major in the wehrmacht.
he's director of their sniper school
in zossen.
koulikov studied under him
at zossen before the war.
he knows all his tricks. from now on
he'll go with you everywhere.
a nobleman from bavaria
who hunts deer
against the shepherd boy from the urals
who poaches wolves.
it's more than a confrontation
between two nations.
it's the essence of class struggle.
i'm glad you're so happy.
he had all the advantages.
next time you'll be even.
no one shoots like you, vassili.
she's been transferred.
i'll see if they're ready for you next door.
hello.
you look very smart
in your new uniform.
make sure they don't take it back
once you've finished.
they probably will.
i've heard the rumor
about the german.
- and i wanted to wish you luck.
- thank you. i'll need it.
from what comrade danilov tells me,
you're going to win.
it's time.
vassili?
- vassili? vassili?
- come to my arms.
look in my direction, here.
here, vassili.
put your cap back on.
you'll look more heroic.
- this way, comrade zaitsev.
- i love this little fellow.
vassili, is it true that
you volunteered for the front?
- vassili?
- vassili?
how old are you, vassili?
do you know what this duel
means for our country?
is it true you killed your first wolf
when you were five?
vassili, tell us, how many fascists
have you killed today?
are you proud to be challenged
by the best sharpshooter in germany?
it's a sign the germans
are starting to shit their pants.
go on, my boy, tell us
how are you going to deal with him?
- or rather, no.
- one more question, please.
tell it to the boss.
he likes good hunting stories.
look at him with pride,
because he's looking at you.
the whole country is looking at you.
forgive me, forgive me, grandfather.
so it's not the wolf that chooses
the hunting ground, but the hunter.
and i'm sure your grandfather
taught you that.
except, in this case, i'm the game.
however, today what we're going to do
is lure the wolf out of his lair
to where we want him to be.
you're the one whose life is valuable,
you go first.
no. no. we take it in turns.
next time it's your turn to go first.
and then it's you, volodya.
son of a bitch!
these are new pants. i just took them
off a captain from the 251 st yesterday.
sixteen months i spent in germany
at the school in zossen.
of course, those were the days
when we were friends with the krauts.
when our joseph and their adolf
were walking hand in hand.
from here to the wire,
- hundred and fifty-five.
- whatever.
that'll make them send out a repair guy.
let's relocate.
hey, volodya.
after the germans invaded us, it wasn't
the same atmosphere any more.
they threw my arse in prison.
"what were you doing in germany?"
"excuse me," says i, "but it was
comrade stalin who sent me there."
"don't bring our glorious leader
into your treachery."
"confess, spy bastard, confess."
and bang! bang, bang, bang!
well, there wasn't a sickle,
but there was a hammer.
and bang, it knocked out all my teeth.
that's right, boy, have no illusions.
that's the land of socialism
and universal bliss for you.
hey, it's your repair guy.
i got him.
- it's about soup time, isn't it?
- i'm going.
well, get a move on, volodya.
and try not to spill it all
on your way back, you marxist bastard.
here's the enemy sniper activity
reported during
the past 24 hours, major.
two sentries shot
in the train station sector,
one artillery observer
in the northern sector,
one lieutenant from the 24th panzer
division in the factory sector,
three telephone repair men
in the workers' housing sector.
they also tell me we've just taken
a prisoner who may interest you.
- i hope he's still able to speak.
- excuse me, sir?
nothing. thank you.
so tell us, volodya.
which building is he in?
there is no way i know that.
he moves around all the time.
- he jumps from one to the next.
- on which floor?
- i don't know.
- we'll see about that.
undress him.
put him in one of our uniforms.
you see? they're stubborn.
that's the good thing
about the germans.
man, you got to admit,
when they get an idea in their heads...
right.
- let's see if our customer has arrived.
- you ready?
and now, our famous shepherd
from the urals
who major konig thinks is an idiot, gets
up to make sure he has hit his target.
major konig sees him,
aims for his helmet,
fires, reveals his position,
and is shot in turn.
except major konig doesn't fire,
because major konig isn't there.
koulikov?
don't you think that was strange?
that last one?
they sent him out
to get shot like the others.
it's not natural.
not without artillery,
without trying to cover him.
no. no, i'm the one who was stupid.
they don't give a shit
about telephone guys.
i mean, it's like us with the ukrainians.
they'd never bother a major
over a few dead grunts.
tomorrow, we'll kill us some generals.
whose turn is it?
mine, i think.
you're such a cheater.
you can't fool papa koulikov.
no, no, no. it's my turn to go first.
and it's your turn
to get a hole in your breeches.
to victory.
this sniper business
has been dragging on too long.
what's that little fellow of yours up to?
he's probing, comrade khrushchev.
he's testing the german
for weaknesses.
he's meticulous in his preparation.
vodka is a luxury we have.
caviar is a luxury we have.
time is not.
he's aware of that,
comrade khrushchev, we both are.
i assure you he will succeed.
good. it seems your destinies
are entwined.
they're keeping you busy?
i picked this up from the kitchen.
it's from the reception the other day.
i thought mrs. filipov might like it.
she'll be thrilled.
that's very sweet of you.
there's plenty more if you're hungry.
you're jewish, aren't you?
there's nothing in our religion
that says you can't eat sturgeon.
my father had a premonition
all this would happen.
you mean the war?
he understood
that the hatred of the jews ran deep.
he was saving up
to buy some land in palestine.
he said it was the only land
that we truly belonged in.
the only land we had a duty to defend.
he insisted i learn to use a rifle.
i learn to shoot.
i know that in times of war
personal feelings should be put aside,
- but i have a favor to ask you.
- of course. anything you want.
i want to be reassigned.
what's happened, tania?
he shot him.
he shot him even though
he jumped first.
shot him on the run.
it was an impossible shot.
i've never seen anything like it.
you've promised people
a victory i can't deliver.
i don't stand a chance against this man.
you mustn't talk like that, vassili.
what if i told you we've found
a way to track his movements?
we've got someone, vassili.
someone close to him
passing us information.
next time you will be
one step ahead of him.
i promise.
now i have a favor to ask.
from me?
it's about tania.
come in.
he doesn't even know you exist,
but at that moment you're closer to him
than anyone else on earth.
you see his face through the sight.
you see whether
he shaved that morning or not.
you can see whether he's married by,
you know, whether
he has a wedding ring on.
it's not like just firing at a distant shape.
it's not just a uniform. it's a man's face.
those faces don't go away.
they come back
and they get replaced by more faces.
did danilov ask you to tell me this?
he likes you very much. i think
he'd try anything to change your mind.
did he tell you why
i asked for the transfer?
no.
this morning a list arrived
at headquarters.
it was a list of civilians
who'd been rounded up
and sent to germany in a convoy
that left stalingrad three weeks ago.
my parents were amongst them.
after 30 kilometers,
the german soldiers stopped the train
and forced everyone out.
in the middle of a bridge,
they bound them together,
two by two.
mothers with daughters.
husbands and wives.
they lined them up against the railing.
and then they fired a single shot
at each pair to save bullets.
it worked.
the bodies of the ones who died
dragged the others under the water.
i know they died together.
they would never have let themselves
be separated.
that's koulikov's rifle. it's a good rifle.
thank you.
i know how he leaves the shelter.
he goes through the tractor factory.
the tractor factory is big.
i know exactly where.
he crawls through a gutter
under a grate where the vats are.
then he goes out from the workshop.
in between the two
there's a place where he's in the open.
it's under a long iron foot walk.
good luck, comrade.
i know exactly
where he's waiting for me.
he'll be on the foot walk over the gutter.
we'll take him out from behind.
we'll get to the other end of
the workshop through these pipes.
follow me.
- you go that way. i'll go around this way.
- okay.
shit!
- it's okay.
- you should go back.
- no.
- go back.
- i'll be all right.
- no, you go!
keep your legs in.
come on. come on. come on.
comrade stalin is asking
for one last effort.
the fate of the motherland is at risk.
the fate of all those
you love and cherish.
it's for them that we fight today.
listen to me, tania. the germans
are throwing everything at us.
if they're lucky, one in ten of these
soldiers will come back alive.
you're highly educated.
you know languages.
every intercept you translate
saves hundreds of lives.
every message you decode
kills thousands of theirs.
you have a duty to survive.
vassili was born to fire a gun.
that's what he knows.
you and i were born
for a different purpose.
if vassili were here,
he would tell you the same thing.
where is he? where's vassili?
keep your head down.
- tell me where he is.
- stay into that pipe.
tania, stay in. stay in. get your head in.
slow down.
don't shoot.
he's over there.
you see the pillar in front of you?
i need you to move round behind it.
go!
tania, i need you to find
a large piece of glass.
piece of glass.
you see the kiln?
behind me, to the left of the factory.
- yes? i can't hear you.
- yes.
yes.
do you see the two louvers?
yes.
do you see the one
with the broken slat?
- yes.
- this is what i want you to do.
- are you ready?
- yes.
three, two, one.
hello, sacha.
he was right where you said he'd be.
nearly there.
he's very clever.
tell me about him.
why was it his grandfather who taught
him how to shoot and not his father?
his father's dead. his mother, too.
- does he talk about his father?
- no, he didn't know him.
did he go to school?
he knows how to write.
he answers lots of letters.
- is it girls who write to him?
- everyone writes to him.
and is there a girl
he loves in his village?
- not in his village. here!
- does she love him?
yes. because he's handsome,
because he's brave.
and she's very beautiful.
i know her well.
she's from my neighborhood.
she went to the university.
they are handsome together.
later the two of them will get married.
at least, i think so.
and you, sacha,
why are you helping the germans?
because they're stronger.
because they're going to win the war.
and because you like chocolate.
all these people here
know they're gonna die,
so each night
when they make it back, it's a bonus.
excuse me!
so every cup of tea, every cigarette,
becomes a little celebration.
because for a lot of us,
it may be our last night.
it's just something
you have to accept here.
everyone has their time.
in the forest,
the wolf lives for three years,
the donkey for nine.
sorry, but that's got to be
a proverb from the urals.
it makes no sense to me whatsoever!
the donkey lives longer
because he's more useful.
it makes absolute sense.
there aren't any donkeys in the forest.
you made it up.
so,
i'm a donkey.
people like you and danilov
have to survive this.
people who've read books,
had an education.
- we'll need you when the war's over.
- and if you survive?
what will the useless
vassili zaitsev do then?
i want to work in a factory.
my granddad took me to a factory once.
there was this man there
high up on a foot walk.
he wasn't wearing blue like the others.
the people he was supervising over,
they didn't really understand
what they were doing,
but for him up there
it was simple, it was clear.
and i thought,
"one day, i could be that man."
sad to have a dream
you know won't happen.
why shouldn't it?
you'll outlive us all.
you'll be the oldest donkey in the forest.
one hundred and fifty meters stand
between the germans and the volga.
today the whole world is watching
these 150 meters.
they are
what make stalingrad the capital
of the war.
your friend, tania.
have you seen her?
she stays over there now
with the snipers.
tell the major we're sending in
all our sharpshooters
to support the attack on the factory.
tell him vassili will be there.
- i need to talk to you.
- sure.
danilov.
you have to stop writing about me.
i'm not gonna get him
because i'm not good enough.
sooner or later he's gonna find me,
he's gonna kill me.
i've warned you before
not to talk like this.
this time it's different.
you've built me up and up
into someone i'm not.
i can't carry that weight any more.
i want to fight.
i want to fight just as a regular soldier.
i understand.
the thing is, vassili,
you're not a regular soldier,
- you're an extraordinary soldier.
- no. i'm what you've made me.
nothing more.
why are you telling me this now?
what's happened?
what's changed?
did you speak to tania for me?
yes.
well, will she reconsider?
i don't know.
she should. she'll be much safer.
she should. you know that.
yeah.
it'll be easier to get her reassigned
than you.
you see, the germans are preparing
another offensive in the city centre.
the propaganda battle's crucial
for morale.
we need you more than ever.
sacha? hold on. sacha?
- tell him what you know, sacha.
- hello, sacha.
there was dust on the major's boots.
sacha has the major convinced
he's gone over to the other side.
i don't need to tell you
the risks he's taking.
the dust was yellow.
there's only one place
where there's dust like that.
in the back of the chemical factory,
a big heap along the tracks.
well done.
sacha, wait for me outside then.
danilov, you had no right to use him.
no, i didn't use him, vassili.
he did it of his own accord.
do you know why?
because he believes in you!
tomorrow morning, we're gonna
take back the chemical factory.
sacha has informed the major
you'll be there.
so now you know
where you have to wait for him.
- in the middle of an assault.
- i'm following orders.
i suggest you do the same.
now, i'm aware of the risks.
you'll be fine.
comrade.
that's the germans up there.
yesterday, it was the russians.
we're not very far now.
sacha,
you're playing a very dangerous game.
i want you to win.
see there? keep going along the river.
it's safe for a while.
he's dead.
we found this on his corpse.
your reason for being here
has ceased to exist.
pardon me, herr general.
but i do not believe...
there's a plane bound for berlin
tomorrow evening. you will be on it.
until then i must ask you
for your dog tags.
imagine how russian propaganda
would profit from your death.
if you fall, you will fall unknown.
you've already had a near miss.
also, please take this war merit cross.
it was awarded posthumously
to a lieutenant
of the 116th infantry division,
who fell here
during the first days of the battle.
he was my son.
if the landing is captured,
everything's lost.
come here.
what did i tell you?
you've been playing your fiddle
too much.
if it's confirmed that he's dead,
we're sunk.
- well, you're sunk.
- it isn't true.
it was intercepted
from their staff headquarters.
what do they have to do?
dangle his body in front of our men?
they're lying.
that's good.
very good.
write it then.
vassili zaitsev is not dead!
this is what he had for breakfast
this morning.
this is a picture of him
reading today's newspaper.
you're the poet.
what? you won't give up the riverbank.
i don't care if you've lost half your men.
lose the other half or lose yourself!
is he back?
he should be back soon.
the german attack cut the lines,
that's why he's late.
can we go outside?
i wrote to my mother about you.
she wanted me to tell you
that once this war was over,
if there's anything you needed,
anything at all,
our family will be there for you.
you know i'm here for you.
they're saying vassili is dead.
vassili zaitsev will never see
his loved ones again.
surrender. this is your only hope.
you're upset?
because zaitsev is dead?
you don't have to hide it.
there's no shame in it.
you're russian like he is.
don't listen to them.
it's just propaganda.
he isn't dead.
and do you know why?
because i haven't killed him yet.
i'm going to tell you a little secret.
only you,
because i know i can trust you.
but you must swear to me
that you won't tell another soul.
you swear?
i found a terrific spot.
it's by the exit from the train station.
i'll hide in the water tower.
tomorrow i'll wait for him there.
you'll see. he'll be there.
he always is.
i also want you to swear to me
that from now on you'll stay home
where you belong.
do you swear?
yes?
good.
we know he's alive,
we know he won't fail us,
we know because
he is a part of us now.
vassili is eternal.
where have you been?
we've looked everywhere for you.
didn't you hear? i was dead.
at least, noble sniper zaitsev
vassili was dead.
the real one.
me.
i was asleep. and i missed my chance.
then i was curled up in a corner hiding
from a man who wants to kill me.
i'll talk to khrushchev.
he'll send you back to your old division.
- where's tania?
- she's at the shelter.
- i've been to the shelter.
- i told her you weren't dead.
the major said so.
he said the other germans were lying.
he told me you were waiting for him
at the station.
vassili.
my little sacha.
i knew it.
- vassili.
- tania.
i knew you weren't dead.
- how?
- because we've only just met.
i prayed for the first time
since i was a little girl.
when i opened my eyes,
sacha was standing there
waiting to give me the good news.
i think he loves you even more than i do.
to the proper military authority.
i'm calling to
the commandant's attention,
the recent changes noticed
in the attitude
towards fighting
of soldier, vassili zaitsev.
he has attempted, on several
occasions, to escape his duties,
voiced doubts
on the chances of our victory,
and made defeatist comments in public.
the inexplicable duration of his duel
with a nazi sharpshooter
can only be explained by his lack
of belief in the communist ideal.
good morning, sacha.
once again,
he knew exactly where to find me.
don't you think that's strange?
apart from me, only you knew.
i don't hold it against you, sacha.
you've done a very brave thing.
you've chosen your camp.
i respect that.
but it isn't my camp.
we're both soldiers.
we're both enemies,
so i know you understand.
i'm annoyed with you, little sacha,
for not staying at home
as i made you swear to do.
i'm annoyed with you for obliging me
to do what i'm going to have to do.
i've never seen anyone frown
so much in their sleep.
- how long have you been watching me?
- all night.
you've been snoring away happily
for hours.
i don't snore, do i?
like a pig!
- i suppose i talk in my sleep as well?
- yes.
there's something i should tell you.
on the train coming here,
we were in the same car.
no.
i saw you.
you were reading and you fell asleep.
i didn't dare look at you,
you were so beautiful.
you were scary.
afterwards, i couldn't stop thinking
about you.
it made me smile.
and then i thought of all the men
who would get to hold you,
who'd make you laugh,
how lucky they were.
and now i'm the one lying next to you.
- was i snoring?
- like a pig.
what?
oh, my god!
tania, no.
- no, get off me!
- tania, no.
- get off me!
- it's what he wants.
- get off me!
- this is what he wants.
- get off me!
- no. he'll kill you.
- let me go!
- he'll kill you,
- and then i'll run after you...
- let me go!
- ...and he'll kill me, too.
- let me go!
this is what he wants. i'll get him.
i promise i'll get him.
i'll get his rifle for you, i promise, tania.
i need you.
you have to leave now, mrs. filipov.
stalingrad may fall.
the last of the boats are leaving.
the germans will be here any moment.
he's brought you a pass.
you'll be safe on the other side.
you have to gather your things,
and we'll help you carry them
to the landing stage.
i'm not leaving. this is my home.
this is my sacha's home. i can't leave.
i have to tell you something,
mrs. filipov.
something very difficult to understand.
it's about sacha.
he's gone over to the germans.
he's betrayed his country.
he's with the enemy now.
he won't be coming back.
oh, my god.
he's become a traitor.
the poor little thing.
what has he done?
so he's going to stay over there?
yes. he's going to stay over there.
i shouldn't be saying this,
comrade commissar,
but maybe it's for the best.
if the germans have won, he'll be safe.
i know it's wrong,
but perhaps he's made the right choice.
- tania!
- tania!
i need a doctor. a doctor!
i have a pass. i have a pass.
you must let her cross.
please.
- it's useless. she'll never make it.
- no.
no, she will. she's my daughter.
she's my daughter, i beg of you.
all right. all right, you two,
put this one on the boat.
where is he? where's the major?
a few inches from your face.
i've been such a fool, vassili.
man will always be man.
there is no new man.
we tried so hard to create
a society that was equal,
where there'd be nothing
to envy your neighbor.
but there's always something to envy.
a smile, a friendship.
something you don't have
and want to appropriate.
in this world, even a soviet one,
there will always be rich and poor.
rich in gifts,
poor in gifts.
rich in love,
poor in love.
tania isn't coming back.
she's dead, vassili.
she was cut down by shrapnel.
it was quick.
i don't think she even saw it coming.
she was on her way back to you,
as soon as she had seen mrs. filipov
to the boats.
she was coming back for you.
she was right.
you're a good man, vassili.
i want to help you, vassili.
let me do one last thing.
something useful for a change.
- let me show you where the major is.
- no, don't do that. don't do that!
today, february the 3rd, 1943,
is an ominous day for hitler
and the endless columns of hundreds
of thousands of german prisoners.
it is an unforgettable day of hope
for our motherland,
for the people of
the soviet union, and...
today after 180 days of growing combat
in the martyred city of stalingrad,
and as a result of the valor
and self-sacrifice of our soldiers,
the commander
of our glorious red army
received the unconditional surrender
of the german fascist invasion.
i cannot find the matching name
in the book.
could you check again, please?
this is the address of this hospital
- and this is her name.
- she's not here, comrade.
yes. this is our address,
- but she's not here.
- we don't have her any more.
this is the address of this place...
- i'm so sorry.
- ...so she's obviously been here.
- she wrote to me.
- ...three times in the books,
but she's not here.
believe me. there is no
tania chernova. i can't help you.
subtitled by
yify collection