(woman singing)
<i>look at the light</i>
<i>coming out of the earth</i>
(man singing)
<i>show me a man</i>
<i>who's gentle and kind</i>
<i>and i'll show you</i>
<i>a loser</i>
<i>now show me a man</i>
<i>who takes what he wants</i>
<i>look at that boy</i>
<i>sitting on the moon</i>
<i>look how exciting</i>
<i>so the poets say</i>
<i>when you're a fool in love</i>
<i>and nothing goes</i>
<i>the way you plan</i>
<i>and no one cares</i>
<i>and no one understands</i>
<i>that you're a fool</i>
<i>and you're in love</i>
<i>never another spring for you</i>
<i>never a robin</i>
<i>to sing for you</i>
<i>you're out there</i>
<i>on your own</i>
<i>when you're a fool in love</i>
<i>a fool in love</i>
<i>seems like the skies</i>
<i>are always gray</i>
<i>you turn around</i>
<i>there's someone in your way</i>
<i>and it's you</i>
<i>and you're in love</i>
<i>sometimes you think</i>
<i>that your luck has changed</i>
<i>and a rainbow explodes</i>
<i>across the sky</i>
<i>but when you're</i>
<i>a fool in love</i>
<i>you'll be a fool</i>
<i>till the day you die</i>
<i>a fool in love</i>
i know we haven't
been together that long,
but these last ten months
have just been
the happiest of my life.
you're not only
the person i love,
you're also my best friend,
and i want to spend
the rest of my life with you.
will you marry me?
yes.
seriously.
do you think that sounds good?
no!
really? 'cause i think
that kinda sums up...
no!
oh? oh, sorry. sorry.
sometimes these catheters
can pinch a little bit.
well, thanks for listening.
i really appreciate it.
you've got a real
gentle touch there, doctor.
she won't be able to say no.
actually, i'm a nurse.
doctor'll be right in.
good luck, greg.
thanks, kim.
good luck, buddy.
okay, it's time for
our problem of the week.
i want you to
pick out your problem,
a problem that's been
bothering you all week.
with your eyes still closed,
i want you to picture
that problem in your mind.
pretend that it's right there
in front of you.
not only are you
my best friend,
but you're also the person
i wanna spend
the rest of my life with.
i love you.
will you marry me?
now i want you to scare
your problems away.
i want you to say boo.
all: boo.
boo!
all right, you guys are great.
very good. i will see you guys
after lunch, all right?
hey, pam, isn't that
your special friend outside?
yeah, i think so.
why don't you go talk to him?
you think i should?
all: yeah.
come here.
hi, sweetie.
how you doing?
what's going on?
i was in the neighborhood,
got off work early.
thought maybe you wanted
to get a bite to eat.
that's very sweet.
what a nice surprise.
oh, shoot, i forgot to
change my shoes.
you don't have to change.
i can't resist a man
in nurse's shoes.
i know, but i got sneakers
in my backpack.
it'll just take a second.
pam: okay.
honey.
pam...
yeah?
... i love you.
i love you too.
come on, sweetie.
i got a half hour before
i have to be back,
so you wanna go have lunch?
what are you doing?
nothing.
i just love you so much.
these last ten months
have been the happiest
of my life.
yeah, they've been amazing.
what's going on?
nothing. i just feel like
we're so close.
you're my best friend,
and you're also
the woman that i love, and...
are you okay, sweetie?
you're acting so weird.
i'm fine. i just got
a crick in my neck.
i was doing c. p. r.
on a 300-pound crack addict
this morning.
oh, my goodness!
pam: do you want me to massage
your neck or something?
no, no, no, i'm fine,
i'm good.
a back rub? are you sure?
honey, look, your kids,
they're trying to
tell you something.
look!
what? hold on.
it's my sister. hello? hi!
<i>i'm engaged!</i>
you're engaged!
that's wonderful.
congratulations!
oh, my god, you're
getting married in two weeks.
that's a little soon.
wow, mom and dad really
don't know bob very well.
dad was okay with this?
<i>well, bob asked dad.</i>
wow, that was very
thoughtful of him.
i can't believe he knew
to ask dad's permission.
yeah.
i'm just here with greg.
he's gonna take me
out for lunch. he's okay.
okay, yeah,
i know you gotta go.
i love you.
okay, talk to you soon. bye.
so what's going on? what?
debbie's marrying that guy?
yeah, in two weeks.
dr. bob of denver.
isn't that great?
yeah, yeah, that's...
didn't they just meet
like a few months ago?
well, yeah, but,
you know, he asked her,
and she said yes.
actually, he asked my dad.
he said yes.
then he asked debbie.
yeah, i overheard that.
so, what, like he had to
ask his permission?
no, no, he didn't have to.
bob just understood
that dad appreciates
that kind of thing.
anyway, deb said
dad's crazy about him.
evidently, bob bought him,
like, the perfect gift
that just won him over.
you know?
really? a gift?
pam: are you sure it's okay
to x-ray this?
g reg: yeah, it's not gonna
mutate or anything.
sir, that's not gonna fit.
wait. hang on a second.
the bag's too big, guy.
you gotta check it.
over here.
raise your arms, sir.
look. i've got an
engagement ring
for my girlfriend in the bag.
i can't open it here.
don't you think
i can just carry it on?
hey, pal, if it ain't fitting
through the frame, you ain't
carrying it on the plane.
check it.
wait, wait! excuse me!
don't worry.
it'll be waiting for you
on the other side.
(man singing)
<i>baby, hurry</i>
<i>don't make me worry</i>
woman on pa: weicome to
<i>new york's la guardia airport.</i>
(baby crying)
excuse me. hi.
you lost my bag,
and there's a two-carat
diamond ring inside it.
i didn't
lose your anything, sir.
but put your local address
on this form, and we'll
ship it when it surfaces.
and what if it doesn't?
am i supposed to
spend the entire weekend
with just the clothes
on my back?
pam: it's a great gift.
i just thought you were gonna
get them champagne.
trust me. i think your dad
is gonna be very
psyched about this gift.
well, don't forget
he's retired, though.
the guy was in the rare-flower
business for 30 years.
i think he still maintains
an interest.
you make it sound like
they're really hard to please.
no, not at all!
he's the sweetest man
in the whole world.
just relax!
he's gonna love you.
i promise.
g reg: as much as he loves
dr. bob?
take it easy on the sarcasm.
h umor is entirely wasted
on my parents.
g reg: what, are they amish?
(pam ch uckling)
g reg: okay, no jokes.
what are you doing?
what?
i told you my dad sees smoking
as a sign of weakness.
okay, all right,
i'll leave them in the car.
no, no, no, no,
he'll check there. oh, gosh.
what...
yeah, the roof is probably
a better idea.
okay. and,
we're not living together.
i thought you said
you told him.
well...
hi, daddy! hi!
sweet pea!
i missed you so much, pamcake.
i missed you too, flapjack.
oh, boy, oh, boy!
both: short stack,
short stack, coming up.
where's my "wittle" girl?
mommy! mom!
you look so beautiful.
pam: so do you. look at you.
oh, i'm sorry.
mom, dad, this is greg.
hi, greg. i'm pam's father,
jack byrnes.
great to finally meet you.
good meeting you.
and i'm dina.
welcome to oyster bay.
oh, thanks.
what are you driving there,
a ford?
yeah, it's a taurus.
we were gonna get a mid-size,
but i figure, hey,
we pull down decent bucks.
might as well go all out,
pop for the full-size.
sure. interesting color.
you pick it?
oh, no, the guy
at the counter. why?
well, they say geniuses
pick green.
but you didn't pick it.
dina: jack!
yucky. what smells
of old sour milk?
poor greg got
spit up on by a baby.
dina: he didn't.
yeah, he did, ma,
at the lost luggage counter.
the airline lost his bag.
they didn't!
yeah.
yeah, they did.
what about you, honey?
no, no, no. i carried on.
that's my girl.
it'll turn up, i'm sure.
and anyway, greg, meanwhile,
anything you need, just ask.
that's right.
<i>mi casa es su casa.</i>
thanks, jack. you too.
yeah.
this is so nice.
jack: we like it.
g reg: beautiful.
now, greg, you have
a very unique last name.
we were curious,
how do you pronounce it?
just like it's spelled.
f-o-c-k-e-r.
focker.
focker.
mmm-hmm.
oh, i'll get it, honey.
oh, thanks, mom.
there he is.
there's our little guy.
pam: jinxy, come here, boy.
come here, baby.
come to daddy, jinxy.
come on. come on, jinxy.
jinxy!
come here. come to daddy.
come on.
taught him that in one week.
this is pam's cat, jinxy.
jinxy, say hello to greg.
hi, jinx.
wave to greg.
hello, jinx.
attaboy. that took me
another week.
oh, my gosh.
pam, i didn't know
you had a cat.
yeah, i left him here
when i moved to chicago.
your daddy's found
his new best friend.
you won't believe it.
he even taught him
to use the potty.
he did? dad, that's kind of
weird, isn't it?
what's so weird about it?
now we don't have to smell
kitty litter all the time.
that's right.
that's incredible.
how did you teach
the cat to use the toilet?
that was easy, greg.
i just designed a litter box
to put inside the toilet,
and then once he got
used to it, i took it away.
yeah, makes sense.
but i don't think he likes it.
i mean, every chance he gets,
he tries to dig,
squat and bury.
i had to move all
my potted plants
off the floor.
plus, you got another
guy around the house
to leave the seat up.
he can't lift the seat, greg.
he lacks the strength
and the opposable thumbs.
yeah.
right. opposable...
i didn't think about that.
jinx is strictly a house cat.
can't let him outside
because he lacks
outdoor survival skills.
okay.
jack: one of those things,
isn't it, sweetheart?
i don't think greg will be
playing with jinxy too much.
he hates cats.
pam, i don't hate cats.
i don't hate cats.
i just happen to be
more of a dog lover.
yeah, yeah.
i am too.
well, that's okay
if you hate cats, greg.
no! i don't.
i don't hate cats at all.
jack: that's okay.
just be honest about it.
there's some things i hate.
i'm being honest.
really? like what?
honey, why don't we let
the kids freshen up, huh?
greg, you come with me.
we'll get you something
to wear from jack's closet,
okay?
okay.
honey.
yeah?
i'm so happy you're home,
sweetheart.
me too, daddy.
hey, listen,
be nice to this one, okay?
i kind of like him.
okay, i'll try.
thank you.
jack: shirt fit okay, greg?
fantastic. thanks, jack.
good. tom collins coming up.
you know, i wish you
hadn't told your parents
i hate cats.
but you do hate cats.
yeah, but you didn't
have to tell them
right when we met.
i know. i'm sorry.
lt just kind of slipped out.
get your red-hot pupus.
my goodness, what is that?
that's just a little
something from me.
go ahead. open it up.
look, honey,
greg brought us a present.
jack: lsn't that nice?
look at this.
it's a flower pot
with the dirt in it.
actually, the real gift
is what's planted in the soil.
the bulb of a jerusalem tulip,
which i was told is one of
the rarest and most beautiful
flowers in existence.
right, the jerusalem...
from the
"jerusales tulipesias"
genus. yes.
anyway, the guy said
with regular watering,
it should bloom in
about six months, so...
we'll look forward
to that, greg.
(clears th roat)
so, greg, how's your job?
good, pam. thanks for asking.
i recently got
transferred to triage.
is that better than a nurse?
no, mom, triage
is a unit of the e. r.
it's where
all the top nurses work.
well...
no, they do.
not many men
in your profession, though,
are there, greg?
no, jack, not traditionally.
pam, honey, did you know that
your father started
his own business?
really? dad, that's great.
wow!
yes, i thought with
my knowledge and experience,
why should i allow
retirement to stop me?
i really admire that.
yeah.
so what is it?
what's the new venture?
let me ask you
a question, greg.
let's just say you have kids
and you wanna
get out of the house,
spend a night on the town.
so, you hire a baby-sitter,
someone you think
you can trust.
references, work experience,
it all checks out fine.
but then how do you
really know for certain
that your loved ones are safe
with this stranger?
i mean, can you ever
really trust another
human being, greg?
sure, i think so.
no, the answer is you cannot.
let me show you something.
take a look at this, greg.
what's this look like to you?
this looks like a teddy bear.
smile, you're on
"nanny camera."
yeah! i've seen these things
advertised on tv.
no, not like this,
you haven't. take a look.
oh, my gosh. hi!
where's the other camera?
right here in this
decorative artifact.
wow, that's great.
jack: our cameras are
motion-activated,
so they begin taping as soon
as they sense any movement.
we can hide them in anything.
we hide them in mirrors,
lamps, televisions,
you name it.
so no matter where you go,
we'll be watching you.
so, jack, couldn't this maybe
be construed as illegal?
you know, invasion of privacy?
trust me, greg, when you
start having little fockers
running around,
you'll understand the need
for this level of protection.
lmpressive, isn't it?
quite.
i'll get that.
i'll get it.
honey, i'll get it.
okay.
any problem
with the documents?
okay. i'll meet you at the
oyster bay drugstore
in about 20 minutes.
now you gotta be more careful
when you call here.
if anybody else answers,
just use a southern accent
and ask for the
vegetarian special, okay?
that wasn't the airline,
was it?
nope, wrong number.
we're all out of collins mix,
so i'm gonna make
a run for the store.
that's funny. i thought
i just bought some.
you know how that stuff,
it just goes,
so i'll be back in a jiff.
well, why doesn't
greg go with you?
sweetie, you'll need something
in case your suitcase
doesn't show up.
i'm sure it'll show up.
yeah.
you don't wanna take a chance.
you don't have a toothbrush.
go on, sweetie.
dina: yeah.
okay, unless you
want some privacy.
why would i need privacy?
no, i didn't think you would.
okay, let's head out.
dina: good.
bye.
have fun, you guys.
pam, he seems wonderful.
he is. we have
the best time together.
good.
now, have you two been...
mother!
thinking about
anything permanent.
i don't know.
i mean, we haven't
really discussed it,
but i definitely
have a feeling this is it.
dad seems to like him.
don't you think?
absolutely.
big day, saturday.
n ice car.
yes. this car is...
you got... what do you use?
unleaded? regular unleaded?
premium.
hey, you know, jack,
now that we have
a second to talk,
i just want you to know
how much pam means to me.
i know that we haven't
been together that long,
but the time that we have
spent together has been
really incredible.
greg, how come
you don't like cats?
i don't not like cats.
(stammering)
i just prefer dogs.
i mean, i'm just more of
a dog kind of, you know...
come home, wagging their
little tails, happy to
see you kind of...
you need that assurance?
you prefer an
emotionally shallow animal?
i...
you see, greg,
when you yell at a dog,
his tail will go between his
legs and cover his genitals,
his ears will go down.
a dog is very easy to break,
but cats make you
work for their affection.
they don't sell out
the way dogs do.
huh.
you like peter,
paul, and mary?
yes, i do. i'm a big fan.
(man singing on radlo)
<i>puff, the magic dragon</i>
<i>dragon</i>
<i>lived by the sea</i>
great song.
yeah, one of my favorites.
who would've thought
it wasn't really
about a dragon, huh?
what do you mean?
you know,
the whole drug thing.
no, i don't know.
why don't you tell me?
some people think that
to "puff the magic dragon"
means to...
they're really...
to smoke
a marijuana cigarette.
well, puff's just the name
of the boy's magical dragon.
right.
are you a pothead, focker?
no! no.
what? no, no, no, no, jack.
no, i'm not.
i pass on grass all the time.
i mean, not all the time.
yes or no, greg?
no. yes. no.
hey, greg, i'll meet you
back out front in
about 12 to 15 minutes.
okay.
hey. hi.
hey, how you doing?
do you have any of
those nicotine patches?
no. we have the gum.
great.
you chew it.
thank you. yes, okay.
and what's your most expensive
bottle of champagne?
mumm's. it's on sale
for $13.95.
really? that's it?
you don't have,
like, a nice, like, $80
or $100 bottle of something?
you can get
a whole bunch of mumm's.
focker.
hey, jack. ready to go?
i've been ready, yeah.
they ran out of collins mix.
you been waiting here long?
no, i was just
reading up about...
pumps.
pumps?
yes. breast pumps.
i grew up on a farm.
(woman singing)
<i>danke schoen</i>
get your hot buns,
hot patooties.
wow, dina,
everything looks fabulous.
it's such a treat for me
to have a home-cooked
meal like this.
dinner at my house
usually consisted of
everybody in the kitchen
fighting over containers
of chinese food.
you poor thing.
what, there wasn't
enough food to go around?
no, there was. we just
never really sat down
like a family like this.
greg, would you
like to say grace?
well, greg's jewish, dad.
you know that.
you're telling me
jews don't pray, honey?
unless you have
some objection.
no, no, no, no, i'd love to.
pam, come on, it's not like
i'm a rabbi or something.
i said grace
at many a dinner table.
okay.
o dear god,
thank you.
you are such a good god to us,
a kind and gentle
and accommodating god.
and we thank you, o sweet,
sweet lord of hosts,
for the
smorgasbord you have so aptly
lain at our table this day
and each day... by day.
day by day by day.
o dear lord,
three things we pray.
to love thee more dearly,
to see thee more clearly,
to follow thee more nearly...
day by day... by day.
amen.
amen.
greg, that was lovely.
thank you, greg.
that was interesting too.
oh, that's a lovely vase.
that's great.
let me guess, jack.
is that one of your
secret cameras too?
greg, that's an urn
which holds the remains
of jack's mother.
oh, i'm sorry. i'm so sorry.
that's all right.
you didn't know, greg.
i'm...
that's our gran-gran.
we like to think of her
as watching over us as we eat.
love you, ma. miss you.
miss you every day.
oh, honey, why don't you
read greg your poem?
no, he doesn't
want to hear that.
what? no! what poem?
you see, when jack
had to retire
for health reasons...
that's a bunch of malarkey.
honey, i'm fine.
the doctor thought it would be
therapeutic if he
sort of expressed his emotions
in an artistic way.
honey, you wrote
the most beautiful poem
about your mother.
please, we really
wanna hear it.
poem, poem.
please!
all right.
it's a work in progress.
i'm still not happy with it.
as soon as it's ready,
then i am going to
glaze it onto a plate,
and put it next to the urn.
n ice.
it's very special.
"my mother" by jack byrnes.
"you gave me life,
you gave me milk,
"you gave me courage.
"your name was angela,
the angel from heaven,
"but you were also
an angel of god,
and he needed you too.
"selfishly i tried
to keep you here
"while the cancer
ate away your organs
"like an unstoppable
rebel force.
"but i couldn't save you,
and i shall see your face
"nevermore, nevermore,
"nevermore,
"until we meet...
in heaven."
daddy, that's beautiful.
lt always gets me.
amazing.
so much love,
yet also so much information.
lt takes a lot out of him.
greg, would you
like some yams?
thank you. yeah.
you must've had vegetables
fresher than that, growing up
on a farm, greg.
dad, greg grew up in detroit.
he told me he grew up
on a farm.
do they have
many farms in detroit?
no, dina, no, not a lot.
ln fact, jack,
i should clarify this.
i didn't actually grow up
on a farm, per se.
the house we grew up in
was originally erected
in the early dutch farm,
colonial style.
so that,
plus we had a lot of pets...
which one did you milk then?
dad!
honey, he said he pumped milk.
what have you ever milked?
a cat.
a cat?
i milked a cat once.
you wanna hear a story?
sure.
my sister had a cat,
and the cat birthed
a litter of kittens.
must've been 30 of them,
and there was
this one little runt,
this little sweet
little-engine-that-could runt
who wanted to get up there
and couldn't really
get access to the...
to the teat.
teat?
dad.
what have you.
i went in and just simply,
you know...
lnto a little saucer,
then took the saucer
and fed it to geppetto.
that's what i named him.
i had no idea
you could milk a cat.
yeah, you can
milk anything with nipples.
i have nipples, greg.
could you milk me?
okay, could we change
the subject perhaps?
champagne, champagne.
yes.
i thought
maybe we could celebrate
with a little bubbly.
that'd be great.
good idea.
"l have nipples.
can you milk me?"
well, in a funny way,
you've already
seen deb's ring.
that's true.
would anybody care for
a bottle of oyster bay drug
and sundry's finest champagne?
that is so sweet of you, greg.
isn't that a nice gesture?
that's very nice.
how could i have seen
debbie's ring, mom?
well, when i gave bob the okay
to propose to deb,
i put him in touch
with my diamond guy,
and he picked out
the same design
kevin gave you.
kevin, your old boyfriend?
thanks, dad.
well, yeah,
kevin was pam's fiancé.
(gasps)
oh, my god.
jinxy, no!
pam: oh, god.
shit.
greg, sweetie, how you doing?
g reg: just fine,
considering i desecrated
your grandma's remains,
found out you were engaged
and had your father ask me
to milk him.
at least back then
he was still talking to me.
i can't believe
you didn't tell me
you were that close.
who, daddy and me?
no, kevin and you.
do we have to know everything
about each other's pasts?
you never told me about
your cat-milking days
in motown.
that was a long time ago, pam.
yeah, okay, well, so was this.
kevin's and my connection
was more physical
than anything else.
physical? like what?
like you worked out together?
no, no, it was nothing,
nothing. it was
a stupid sexual thing.
i'm gonna go throw up now.
greg, listen.
kevin and i were only engaged
for a month before i realized
that i'd made a mistake.
i gave back the ring,
i moved to chicago,
and i met and fell in love
with you, okay,
so can we please drop this?
okay.
good.
i just feel like this is
not going well at all.
i feel like your dad hates me.
he doesn't hate you, sweetie.
come on. just give him
a chance, all right?
maybe he's nervous too, huh?
i thought he would
love my gift, you know,
being this big flower guy,
but it's like
he didn't even show
the slightest bit of interest.
listen to me. forget the gift.
you are the most adorable,
loving, sweetest man
in the whole world,
and i love you.
and very soon my parents
are gonna see that
and grow to
love you too, okay?
okay?
speaking of growing
to love you...
honey, it's late. come on.
i know it's late.
but mr. winky
is still on chicago time,
and we both know
there's only one way
to make mr. winky go away.
(knock on door)
and there it is.
what's with the robe?
it's pam's. my pajamas
are in the suitcase
with everything else.
hey, i'll lend you
a pair of jack's. okay, honey?
sure.
you don't have to
do that, dina.
dina: no, no, no.
no, that's fine. we have to.
thank you.
dina: you're welcome.
look, greg, i just wanna say,
don't worry about
what happened tonight.
oh, thanks, jack.
still, i feel horrible.
i mean...
well, it was a horrible thing.
but let's just put
all that behind us and
enjoy our weekend together.
okay. okay.
thank you, daddy.
(lmltating tral n)
thank you.
thanks, mom.
these'll do just fine.
good night.
jack: n ight-night.
good night.
good night, sweetie.
see you in the morning.
have a nice sleep.
okay, you too.
no, greg, we made up
the pullout for you
down in the den.
okay, 'cause pam said i should
sleep in debbie's room.
well, debbie'll be
sleeping here tomorrow.
this way, you'll have
more privacy, you'll have
your own bathroom.
just try not to
flush the toilet.
it's always a little quirky.
okay.
one more thing.
i'm a realist. i understand
it's the 2 1 st century,
and you've probably had
premarital relations
with my daughter.
but under our roof,
it's my way or
the long lsland expressway.
is that understood?
of course, yeah.
good. keep your snake
in its cage for 72 hours.
okay.
man on phon e: weicome to
<i>atlantic american airways'</i>
<i>lost luggage department.</i>
<i>at atlantic american airways,</i>
<i>customer satisfaction</i>
<i>always comes first.</i>
<i>we are experiencing</i>
<i>heavy call volume.</i>
<i>your call is</i>
<i>very important to us.</i>
<i>it will be answered</i>
<i>in approximately 27 minutes.</i>
<i>please press "1 " if you'd</i>
<i>like to talk to</i>
<i>a representative.</i>
<i>we are closed for the night.</i>
<i>please call back...</i>
sorry.
i don't know what it is,
but there's just something
about him that's a little off.
oh, yeah, yeah. jack, you know
we've been through this
with every boyfriend
pam has had since,
what, middle school.
i think greg...
he's a lovely young man.
and, honey, pam thinks
he might be the one.
she said that?
she said those exact words?
i didn't tape record her,
jack, but that's
the impression.
what kind of a family
doesn't have time
to sit down for dinner?
fugitives.
please try to enjoy
the weekend, honey.
both our daughters
are in love.
that's what
i'm worried about.
geez, i just
realized something.
what?
pam's middle name.
martha.
oh, no.
both: pamela martha focker.
(g roans)
(door creaking)
"operation ko samui"?
jack: looking for something,
greg?
jesus, jack, you scared me.
i heard a noise,
so i came down to see
if everything was okay.
everything's fine. i just...
i'm sorry. i saw a light on,
and i kinda stumbled in.
i didn't realize...
that's okay.
see anything interesting?
no, not at all. i mean...
i mean, this is great, though.
i love this... what you...
it's a cozy little nook.
i noticed you were looking
at that when i came in.
yeah.
it's an antique
polygraph machine.
is that what that is?
i've seen these before,
but i never saw one
actually up close.
you know what?
why don't you try that on?
oh, that's okay.
come on. we'll have some fun.
i'll show you how it works.
i shouldn't.
why should you be afraid?
you have nothing to hide.
no, i know.
i know you know,
so there shouldn't be
any problem.
no, there's no problem.
so, try it on.
okay.
i'll help you.
don't worry.
you'll enjoy this.
all right.
looks complicated.
now these aren't
they're...
you'd be surprised
how accurate they are.
they can tell fairly easily
if someone's lying or not.
now i'm gonna ask you
some questions,
and all you have to do
is answer "yes" or "no".
okay.
all right.
let's give it a whirl.
did you fly
on an airplane today?
yes, i did.
no peeking.
did we eat pot roast
for dinner tonight?
yes.
was it undercooked?
no, it was rare.
lt was a little rare
for my taste.
but i wouldn't...
i'm just kidding,
i'm just...
(both laug hing)
relax. relax.
the needles are jumping.
have you ever watched
pornographic videos?
no.
i mean, well, i don't...
yes or no?
hey!
hey.
what's the matter?
you can't sleep?
no, i'm just going over
some of my answers
from the polygraph test
your dad gave me.
oh, no, he didn't.
yeah, he did.
well, did you lie to him?
no! i mean, well,
he asked me if we were
living together and...
what'd you tell him?
nothing. your mother walked in
and yanked the little thingies
off before i had to answer.
is this how you'd react if
i told you he shoved bamboo
shoots up my fingernails?
or does he hook
all your boyfriends up
to his little machine?
well, he doesn't
need a machine.
he's a human lie detector.
what?
greg, my father was never
in the rare flower business.
that was just his cover.
he was in the c.i.a.
for 34 years.
how could you
not tell me this?
i wanted to, honey,
but it was strictly
on a need-to-know basis.
so, what? he's in the c.i.a.?
he was a spy? he is a spy?
no, he was more like
a psychological profiler.
they used him to interrogate
suspected double agents
in the company.
oh, that's great. yeah.
i was scared of your dad
back when i thought
he was a florist.
it's wonderful to know that
i've actually got a c.i.a.
spy-hunter on my ass.
would you stop?
you're doing great, okay?
this is a lot to take in,
honey. i'm sorry.
it's just weird.
i know, but you're doing fine.
i promise.
no!
what's wrong, sweetie?
i forgot.
i'm not supposed to
let the snake out of my cage.
your what?
i told your dad
i wouldn't touch you
for 72 hours.
okay, i'm not in
junior high anymore, so...
no. seriously.
i want to try to
respect his rules, okay?
okay. fine.
why don't you go ahead
and get some sleep, and i'll
see you in the morning.
okay.
(gasps)
morning, greg.
good morning.
pam told me she let you in
on a little secret
of mine last night.
yes, she did.
well, as long as you can
keep your mouth shut
for the rest of your life,
you're in no immediate danger.
i won't tell.
i'm just being humorous.
that was funny.
but the fact is, greg,
with the knowledge
you've been given,
you are now on the inside
of what i like to call
"the byrnes family
circle of trust."
i keep nothing from you,
you keep nothing from me
and round and round we go.
okay. understood.
okay, good. come on.
let's go inside
and have breakfast.
(singing)
<i>jinxy cat, jinxy cat,</i>
<i>where are you?</i>
<i>i love you</i>
jack: jinxy. jinxy.
not at the table,
honey, please.
attaboy!
jack: hey, hey, look who's up!
hi, sweetie.
you must be greg.
hello.
look, somebody had
a visit from the hair fairy.
yes.
n ice 'do, nice 'do.
i'll do the intros. greg.
this is my sister, debbie.
hi. n ice to meet you.
the bride to be.
congratulations.
and her fiancé, dr. bob.
you can call me bob... m. d.
these are his parents,
linda banks...
hi. how are you?
n ice to meet you.
and the world-famous
plastic surgeon, dr. larry.
now, cut that out.
you know, greg's in medicine,
too, larry.
really? what field?
n ursing.
that's good.
no, really. what field?
n ursing.
hey, why don't
i get you a chair, greg?
thank you. thanks.
so, you didn't want to
go for the m. d.?
no, i actually thought
about becoming a doctor, but
i decided it wasn't for me.
just as well.
boards are killer.
actually, greg aced his mcats.
you serious?
no, i did okay.
he did more than okay.
trust me.
why did you take the test
if you weren't planning on
going to med school?
well, i wanted to keep
my options open,
but in the end, nursing was
a better fit for me.
lt gives you the freedom
to work in several
different areas of medicine.
plus, i can focus 100%
on patient care,
as opposed to being a doctor
where you have to
deal with the bureaucracy.
uh-oh. wasn't your friend andy
supposed to be here by now?
bob: oh, my god!
i thought deb told you.
dr. andy threw out his back.
he can't make the wedding.
oh, damn.
now i have to reconfigure
the whole procession.
bob, why doesn't greg stand in
for andy, be the usher?
no, pam, no.
that'll be fine.
bob, greg'll be
your second usher.
good.
yeah. yeah, yeah, okay, sure.
good. let's all finish up
and get ready to go
because we have a pre-activity
briefing in about 32 minutes.
all: thirty-two minutes!
you know what? in that case,
i'd better get upstairs
and pay a little visit
to the shower fairy.
dina, thank you
so much for breakfast.
hey, you okay?
why didn't you wake me up?
because i thought
you'd like to sleep late.
not when i'm a guest.
it's okay.
don't worry about it.
no, it's not okay.
tell that to dr. torquemada
in there with
the grand inquisition.
go take a shower, get dressed
and come back down.
get dressed in what?
borrow some more
of dad's clothes.
no, i don't... come on.
why not, honey?
i just... no, i don't feel
comfortable wearing
your dad's underwear.
okay, well, go wake up denny
and borrow some of his.
you want me to go wake up
your brother who i never met
and ask if i could have
some of his clothes?
okay, all right.
where's denny's room?
top of the stairs, turn right.
denny?
hello? hello?
hey! what the hell
you doing in here?
hi. i'm greg, pam's friend.
what? were you just
sniffing my boxers, dude?
no, dude, no. no, she said
i could come up here,
maybe borrow
some clothes from you.
do me a favor. close the door.
okay.
quick.
tell anybody i wasn't here?
no, they think you're asleep.
yeah, so, it's all good.
you scared me.
dad keeps you guys under
a pretty close watch, huh?
no, it's not that bad.
your little pamcake's
got it a lot worse than i do.
you need some clothes.
yes, that would be great.
glad to hook you up.
all right?
cool.
like what you done
with the crib.
lil' kim.
she's phat.
p-h, phat.
yeah, i think these ought to
do it. all right,
here you go, chief.
all right!
enjoy!
thanks a lot, denny.
no problem.
and don't worry about
the little covert op,
all right?
i'll keep it on the lowdown.
down low.
no doubt.
(jack lmltating a trumpet)
people, people, come get
your revised itineraries.
larry, linda, debbie,
bob, honey.
now, i'm gonna activate
the alarm. it'll go off
in t minus 16 seconds.
i don't think i need a jacket.
it's cold out, honey. hold on.
here, take denny's jacket.
hey, denny, i'm lending greg
your jacket, okay?
whatever.
let's go.
denny, how's the tux fit?
dad...
what's that?
it's a sculpture
i found in greg's jacket.
this isn't a sculpture, denny.
this is a device
for smoking marijuana.
really?
not mine. it's not.
hey, jack. how you doing?
i like the top hat.
complements you.
can i talk to you
for a minute?
sit down.
did i not clearly explain
the circle of trust
to you, greg?
yeah, i think i got it.
then is there something
you wanna tell me?
i don't think so.
didn't we have
a discussion yesterday
in the car about this?
yes! you mean...yes!
you mean me and pam.
yes, i would love to
talk to you about that.
we're not talking about pam.
we're talking about you.
see, if i can't trust you,
greg, then i have no choice
but to put you right back
outside the circle.
and once you're out,
you're out.
there's no coming back.
well, i would definitely like
to stay inside the circle.
well, then, tell me the truth.
okay.
jack, i don't know
what we're talking about.
all right, now look, focker,
i'm a patient man.
that's what 19 months
in a vietnamese prison camp
will do to you.
but i will be watching you,
studying your every move.
and if i find that you are
trying to corrupt
my firstborn child,
i will bring you down, baby.
i will bring you down
to chinatown.
where are we?
i thought we were going
to kevin's house.
we are, sweetie.
this is kevin's new house.
pam: wow!
larry: this is a crazy house.
bob: not bad, huh, dad?
maybe he uses marijuana
for medicinal purposes.
people do that nowadays.
honey, this kid
has been lying to us
from the moment we met him.
hey, you.
get in some quality time
with the boys?
yeah, it was fun.
listen, i hope this lunch
isn't too weird for you.
why would "b. b. q.
at best man's" be weird?
oh, my god, greg.
i was sure i told you.
kevin is bob's best man.
this is his place.
g reg: kevin, your ex-fiancé?
all: hey!
welcome, everybody.
i don't understand.
how does he know bob?
well, they went to
lacrosse camp together,
and kevin was the one
who introduced bob to debbie.
lacrosse camp?
i was really lucky i was able
to salvage this wood
from an old seamen's
chapel in nantucket.
(all gasping)
wow!
kevin, the house is amazing.
this is where
the light comes in.
maybe you should have
gotten married here.
all right, the sun is out,
the grill is hot,
and the pool is luke.
if i can interest you
in a swim and a little b. b. q.,
just follow me.
all right, kevo.
right on schedule.
wow.
bring it on.
lt must cost a fortune
to heat this place.
kevl n: wait till you see
the rest of the house.
you okay, sweetie?
yeah.
i'm really sorry.
i don't know why
i thought you knew.
it's not a big deal.
if i can handle
a weekend without
sex and cigarettes,
i think i can handle
an afternoon
with your ex-fiancé.
okay. thank you.
now, for the floor that
you're walking on, i chose
this bolivian wormwood.
i think it works well in here.
i have the viking range here
and the twin sub-z's.
yeah, they open up
right there.
oh, i get it. like hidden.
yeah, kind of blend in.
great.
are you a homeowner, greg?
no, no, i rent.
so, things are going real,
real well for you,
aren't they kevo?
gosh, things have been going
so great lately.
i got in early
on some wireless i. p. o.s,
and the stuff just
skyrocketed from there.
wow.
what about you, greg?
what line of work are you in?
i'm in health care.
yeah, so you know
what i'm talking about.
there are a lot of benjamins
to be made now
with biotech stuff.
i don't have to tell you that.
how's your portfolio?
i'd say strong
to quite strong.
you gotta strike
while the iron's hot.
now's the time.
greg's a male nurse.
that's right. thank you, jack.
well, that's great.
that's great to give
something back like that.
i'd love to find time
to do volunteer work.
just the other day
i saw this golden retriever
that...
he had like a gimp,
and he couldn't really...
lt made me feel terrible.
i wish there was
something i could do.
yeah, well, i get paid,
but also it feels,
you know, good too.
so it's kind of
an everybody wins.
what are you? you're like
a wall street trader?
an investment guy?
no.
i mean, i'm willing to be
painted with that brush.
yes, that's my day job.
we have time?
we got time, don't we, jack?
i want to show you what
i'm really interested in.
come on. let's go.
wow!
lt looks like somebody
got an "a" in wood shop.
yeah, it's always been kind of
a hobby. i whittled that out
of beech wood.
it's beautiful.
yeah.
so what got you into
"carpentering"?
carpentry?
i guess i'd have to say jesus.
he was a carpenter, and l
just figured if you're gonna
follow in someone's footsteps,
who better than christ?
greg's jewish.
are you?
yeah.
well, so was j. c.
wow. you're in good company.
right.
well, i'm gonna
head to the pool,
but why don't you show
greg and pam the gift?
g reg: wow, he made a gift.
pam: greg.
now, i put a fresh coat
of lacquer on this
this morning,
so bear with me
with the fumes.
wow. kev.
isn't that something?
that's incredible.
thank you.
roses. deb's favorite.
yes, right.
it's beautiful.
pam: the little holes
are for candles.
kevl n: well, exactly.
and then later,
they'll collect rainfall.
they make a tiny birdbath.
that's great.
it's beautiful. what is it?
it's an altar.
or you might call it
a chuppah.
isn't that sweet? wow.
i'm gonna take it over
to the byrneses',
and tomorrow robert and
deborah will meet beneath it
to become man and wife.
and later, when they
purchase a home,
maybe it will grace
their garden.
well, that's my sappy,
romantic idea.
must have taken
forever to build.
no, not too bad.
about 70 hours.
which isn't bad, considering
i carved it all by hand
from one piece of wood.
jack on i ntercom: hey, kevo.
<i>12: 15. time to start</i>
<i>the barbecue, big guy.</i>
okay, mr. b.
i better get back
to playing host.
okay, you guys, grab
your suits, and i'll meet you
down at the pool.
you know, i think i'm gonna
take a pass on the swimming.
oh, no, you can't.
i don't even have
a suit with me.
the airline lost my bag and...
<i>pamcake, let's go.</i>
<i>mom's got your suit here.</i>
coming, dad.
you better get going.
gosh, she's great.
congratulations, man.
thank you.
and, by the way,
she just had the nicest
things to say about you.
really?
yeah.
(sighs)
gosh. yeah, we had
some good times together.
boy, she is a tomcat.
so, let me hook you up
with some trunks, gregger.
i'm not gonna swim.
no, come on.
i'm not taking no
for an answer.
kevl n: cold buffet is
on the left, wine
and champagne on the right.
coming through here.
yeah, that'd be gre...
hey, there he is!
get out here.
g-man, we got salmon,
we got swordfish.
what's it gonna be?
how about a little of both,
k-dog? i'm pretty hungry.
i think they call that
"the munchies."
jack: let's go. hit the ball,
kev! show them what you got!
(all ch eering)
kevl n: come on, greg. damn!
come on, team.
he's got nothing.
come on, greg.
service.
come on, greg.
(all screaming)
n ice serve, pal.
kevl n: all right.
set!
oh, greg! come on!
n ice shot, maverick!
sweet setup, lceman.
n ice one, n urse.
kevl n: glenn, glenn, glenn.
you gotta rush the net
on defense.
don't be afraid of the ball.
it's greg.
h uddle up, team.
greg, not glenn.
greg is afraid of the ball.
come on. this is unacceptable.
he's gotta go for the ball.
here's what we gotta do.
kevl n: let's go!
we're getting cold in here.
we're getting creamed.
if florence n ightingale
over here would play defense.
larry, i missed one shot.
lt was a big shot.
larry, keep floating
where you are.
you're doing great.
denny, take the deep shots.
okay.
greg, nobody's expecting
much out of you,
so if i set you up
with the ball, can you
jump up and spike it?
no.
yeah. i'd have to be
pretty high, but yeah.
i bet you would, panama red.
all right, everybody,
look sharp. break!
let's play some ball.
pam: all right, here we go.
let's go. come on.
greg! set!
you gotta spike those, focker!
you gotta spike those!
look how bob did that.
n ice play, bob.
thanks, jack.
fire it up there, focker!
let's do it!
way to go, deb!
jack: greg!
honey! god!
what the hell's
the matter with you?
it's only a game, focker!
oh, honey! i'm coming!
get some ice.
my eye! oh, my eye!
focker!
god!
jack: pam, help your sister,
please.
i'm sorry, deb.
deb, you can totally see
voit backwards
on your forehead.
denny, get outta here!
you the bandleader?
yes, sir.
go over the song selection
with bob.
bob? bob!
yeah, jack.
are you a mr. focker?
yes.
okay. sign here, please.
great. thank you.
hey, your suitcase.
you go through it,
make sure it's all there?
yeah, it's fine.
good.
what's up?
i just wanna make sure you're
okay since hitting the spike
heard around the world.
oh, yeah. i'm really sorry
about that.
it's okay.
i don't know what
got into me, lceman.
"lceman"?
i'm sorry. ls that
a special thing between
you and kevin?
stop it.
stop what, lceman?
<i>top gun was</i>
a very popular movie
when kevin and i dated.
all right? that's it.
hey, lceman.
i have no problem with that.
do you want to be maverick?
is that what
this is all about?
i can't be maverick.
kevin's maverick.
he used to be,
but we can change that.
can he be goose?
no, because goose
dies in the end.
very sad.
honey, i don't really...
greg, shut up.
okay.
jesus, dad,
you ever think of knocking?
not in my own den.
what are you two
doing in here?
i'd say rounding second base.
this is greg's room, dad.
not anymore.
we're gonna use it
for storage.
greg will stay in
debbie's room, and she'll
bunk up with you tonight.
fine. come on, greg.
okay. i'll be right up.
i'll meet you upstairs.
oh, good.
they found your suitcase.
yeah.
hey, jack, i don't quite know
what happened back
at the tux shop,
but if i've given you
the wrong impression regarding
pam in any way, i'm sorry.
okay? i have nothing but
the best intentions
with pam, and i just...
actually, there's something
in the suitcase here that i'm
planning on giving her
that i think symbolizes
the level of
my commitment to her.
and i wouldn't feel right
asking her to wear it without
her father's permission.
jack?
did you flush this toilet?
maybe. you know what?
maybe jinx flushed it.
i saw little jinxy
come in last night,
and he took a little squat
and relieved himself.
jinx knows not to
use that toilet, and even if
he did, he'd never flush it.
what does it matter?
the matter, greg, r. n.,
is that when this toilet
is flushed, it runs,
and when you have
a septic tank
that's nearly full
and a toilet that's been
running all night,
then you could have
a hell of a problem.
mr. byrnes?
man: this is not part of
my job description.
n ice stench.
you're really on
a roll there, bud.
bite me, denny!
ln 20 hours, i'm having
a wedding here, so i need
my cesspool pumped now!
not tomorrow. now!
dad, what's going on?
oh, my god!
what's that smell?
that smell, bob, is our shit.
focker flushed the toilet
in the den, so the septic tank
is overflowing.
jack, i told you.
lt wasn't me. it was jinx.
focker, i'm not
gonna tell you again!
jinx cannot flush the toilet.
he's a cat, for chrissakes!
the animal doesn't even
have thumbs, focker.
hey, look at this!
kevo!
over by the tree, right?
no. no, no, no.
not on the lawn!
stay where you are.
not on the lawn!
pam: kevin, no!
no, no, no, no!
no, no, no!
what the heck?
(man singing)
<i>i got my mojo workin'</i>
<i>just won't work on you</i>
<i>i got my mojo workin'</i>
<i>just won't work on you</i>
i know that's what
i said i wanted,
'cause that's what i wanted.
lt is a black
samsonite suitcase.
what i'm saying is,
do you think it's possible
that the samsonite people,
in some crazy little scheme
to actually turn a profit,
made more than one?
<i>woman: i don't think so.</i>
you don't?
<i>i am going to need your</i>
<i>baggage claim number again.</i>
jinx, stop.
i know i signed for it.
<i>i'm looking at your</i>
<i>signature right here,</i>
<i>mr. focker.</i>
do me a favor. could i talk
to your supervisor?
<i>excuse me?</i>
what's your name?
<i>joy.</i>
okay, let me
talk to your supervisor.
<i>my supervisor is on a break.</i>
when he gets back,
have him give
me a call right away.
it's a very important bag.
<i>i'm sure it is, sir.</i>
jinx.
don't ask me what it's for.
i need you to do this thing.
please, i'm in
a time situation here,
so just do it. i'll hold on.
man:
<i>so the name's "greg focker"?</i>
i don't know. greg or gregory.
run both names.
jinx.
come on. no. jinx.
come here. jinxy.
mew, mew, mew. no. no.
jinx. oh, shit.
greg didn't ace his
med school boards. he never
even took the goddamn mcats.
oh, jack, that's what you had
your sources check out?
what this poor boy
did on some test scores?
i bet he doesn't even have
a real nursing degree.
a lot of these
hospital workers
are just pill poppers
looking for easy access
to ludes.
we already know that
he's been puffing
the magic dragon.
i knew the little crack
was lying.
jinxy. come here.
come here, little jinxy.
(singing)
<i>jinxy cat,</i>
<i>jinxy cat i won't hurt you</i>
the fact is, greg lied to you.
he did not lie to me, dad.
he lied to you
and i thought you
should know the truth.
i love you too much
to see you get hurt.
i don't care what your
information says, dad.
greg took the mcats. okay?
(speaking in thai)
holy...
shit!
no, no, no. no, no, no.
no!
ho...
holy...
no! oh! oh, my god!
all right, everybody.
all right, stand back.
stay back. stay back.
watch out. watch out!
dina: oh, jack! oh, god!
larry: we've got a fire!
somebody call 911 right away!
h urry up!
dina: jinxy! jinxy!
we checked every yard,
every car on the street.
nobody's seen him.
he's not up in
any of the trees, jack.
we checked all the bedrooms.
jinx isn't up here.
yeah, none of the neighbors
have seen him either.
you tried to milk him,
didn't you,
you sick son of a bitch!
dad, stop it. that's enough.
honey, please calm down.
how can i calm down
if we're 15 minutes away
from the wedding rehearsal
and the ring bearer's missing?
what do you mean,
"the ring bearer"?
your daddy didn't tell you?
he taught jinx to walk down
the aisle with this
little pillow.
oh, no. no, you didn't, dad.
yeah, yeah. you put this
around the neck, and these
ribbons are for the rings.
bob: that's adorable, jack.
oh, for chrissakes!
that's great, dad.
yeah, but now we have to
postpone the rehearsal.
bob, you ride with me.
larry, you come with your car.
we're gonna canvass
the neighborhood.
dee, ask o'boyle to wait.
if we're not back in an hour,
we'll reschedule the rehearsal
for the morning.
jack!
no! we cannot
cancel the rehearsal
for some stupid cat!
stupid cat? how could you
say that? that cat's been
like a brother to you!
we're supposed to let him
wander the streets without
food, water or toilet?
dad, greg'll find him.
what?
yeah, what?
oh, that's wonderful.
fine. fine. okay. denny?
denny? denny? denny!
dad, i'm right here.
okay. you're gonna fill in
as the ring bearer for now.
no. i'm not wearin'
that stupid pillow thing
on my head.
oh, yes, you damn well will!
jinx! jinx! here, jinx.
you just go and wander
the streets without food,
water or toilet? fucker!
actually, you may be in luck.
they brought in a himalayan
a little while ago.
there he is.
holy shit, that's jinx.
jinxy!
no, let me see
that photo again.
you gotta picture him
without that stupid santa cap.
come on, jinxy. jinxy!
no.
you see, in the picture,
your cat has
an all-black tail.
yeah.
and this one has a white tip.
no, i'm sorry about that,
chief.
looks just like him.
almost.
except for that tail.
dearly beloved...
priest: dearly beloved,
we are gathered here
on this beautiful day
to join dr. robert banks...
dearly beloved,
we are gathered here
on this beautiful day
to join dr. robert banks
and deborah byrnes
in holy matrimony.
this is a special day...
he found him!
it's him! it's him!
i gotta see this.
look, dad, it's jinx.
my little baby!
we found you. we found you.
greg, thank you so much.
this is so great.
debbie: where did you
find him?
gave us a little scare, huh?
jinxy.
<i>for once in my life</i>
<i>i got someone who needs me</i>
to greg.
hooray!
dina: honey, where is greg,
anyway?
he's in the restroom.
yes, i tried there.
i've tried every shelter
on the north shore, okay?
he's a brown-and-black
himalayan with
an all-black tail.
mr. jinx. yeah, okay.
you go check.
i'll call you back.
it's the man of the hour.
hey!
sorry, folks.
had to pay a little visit
to the urinal fairy.
greg, nice work
with the cat today.
thanks, jack.
i'm just glad
i could help out.
we never did get to finish
that little "convo"
back at the den.
so, when you have a minute,
there is still something i'd
like to talk to you about.
we'll get right to it
as soon as we get back.
you have my word.
i'm gonna hold you to that.
circle of trust.
guess who's back
in the circle of trust.
(meowing)
<i>pull the string</i>
<i>and i'll wink at you</i>
<i>i'm your puppet</i>
look at jack!
oh, poor kevin looks lonely.
maybe i should ask him
to dance. what do you think?
sure. i bet he could whittle
a private little dance floor
for the two of you.
i'm serious.
i saw some beech wood outside.
he's very handy.
he's an extremely handy
and crafty craftsman.
i shouldn't paint him
with that brush, but...
come on. seriously. seriously.
part of you wishes
you ended up with him.
yes, he's very talented,
but it would've
never worked out.
why not?
i was never in love
with kevin.
i'm in love with you.
that's a good explanation.
think so?
thought you'd like that.
i do.
i'm glad.
no, jinx. mr. jinx.
i called you like
half an hour ago.
okay, i already...
i already described it...
airline.
messages.
it's brown...
with a little bit
of black trim.
yes.
<i>man: please enter your</i>
<i>four-digit code.</i>
<i>jack, hi. it's hank macatee</i>
<i>from next door.</i>
<i>you'll never guess who</i>
<i>wandered over here</i>
<i>this afternoon. mr. jinx.</i>
<i>yeah, he's not wearing</i>
<i>his collar, but i'm sure</i>
<i>it's jinxy.</i>
<i>thought you might be worried,</i>
<i>so just give me a jingle</i>
<i>when you guys get home,</i>
<i>and i'll bring</i>
<i>the little rascal over.</i>
okay, well, if you could just
keep checking, please,
and i'll call you back later.
thanks.
any luck?
no, they're still looking.
hey, jack,
this is a great party.
i guess sometimes these things
sort of come together
in their own kooky
sort of way.
yeah, it's kind of like
the way you found jinxy.
you found him
at that animal shelter?
yeah, right.
well, the important thing is
he's home now.
yes.
yeah. you know,
there's something about
that ball of fur
that just puts
a big smile on my face.
yeah.
you haven't seen any of his
latest tricks, have you?
no.
well, when we get back,
i'll show you.
we don't have to do it
tonight. he's had a long day.
he's probably tired.
i wouldn't want to...
no, i think he'd like to
show you tonight.
why don't you give me the key
and let me drive?
hey, larry. you know what?
why don't i drive?
oh. it's a very expensive car.
good idea.
i've always wanted to
test-drive a benz.
be my guest, focker.
hey, sweetie,
what are you doing?
larry said i could drive.
let's go. h urry, hurry.
all right. bye, guys. see you.
thanks for driving.
(tl res screeching)
drives a little better
than your taurus, huh, greg?
yeah.
come on. get in the car,
honey. let's go. h urry up.
okay, okay.
whoa, nellie!
larry: everybody comfortable
back there?
(brakes screeching)
you're a real wild man
at that wheel there.
you got your seat belts
on back there?
get your seat belts on.
oh, jesus, focker!
you're driving like a maniac!
focker, take it easy!
benz drives like a dream, lar.
let's not make it
a nightmare, huh?
oh, there's jack.
hey, jackie.
(both eng i n es revving)
wanna play, pops? let's play.
okay, now, greg? greg?
greg, no!
is everything okay, honey?
yeah, just trying
to make good time.
what the heck
is the matter with you?
all right. we're gonna
be home. we're gonna get home.
it's not the autobahn.
come on, greg!
jesus!
ll n da: maybe you should drive
after all, honey.
we're okay.
all right.
oh, no. no, please.
yes!
bob: jack just turned.
you were supposed to
make that left at the light,
focker.
i think i'm gonna be sick.
den ny: where does he think
he's going?
bob: home, home, home.
mr. toad's wild ride.
who gave him the keys?
okay, we're out.
yeah, we've had
enough excitement.
larry: i wonder if he
has a license.
bob: yeah, a license to kill.
come on, everybody.
hey, nice driving, mario!
you're a lunatic!
come on, linda!
hey, hey!
(debbie screaming)
larry: what in the world...
oh, my...
oh, the dress!
lt was the cat! goddamn you!
dad, dad!
jinx, i'm gonna...
calm down!
jack: where's the cat?
bob: cat got out!
cat got out, jack!
you spray-painted his tail
to make him look like
jinxy didn't you, focker?
greg, what's he
talking about?
hank macatee called me
a couple of hours ago
and told me he found jinxy.
he took his collar
and put it on an impostor.
then he spray-painted
his tail, and then he tried to
beat us back here
so that he could get rid
of the evidence.
oh, no.
please tell me
that's not true, greg.
lt was just a temporary
solution until i could find
the real jinx.
how could you do
something like that?
i'm sorry.
what are you going to
tell me next?
that you set kevin's
altar on fire?
oh, my god.
well, it wasn't intentional.
i was chasing jinx up
onto the roof.
i had a smoke,
and i think i might have
lit something that...
i don't know what happened.
he put so much goddamn lacquer
on that thing.
lt was an accident
waiting to happen.
this is very
disappointing, greg.
get out of my house, focker,
and take your friend with you.
so you lied to me
about everything, huh, greg?
you lied about the cat,
about the fire,
about the mcats.
i didn't lie about the mcats.
don't you see
what's happening here?
your dad has
totally turned you against me.
i didn't turn her against you.
you did that to yourself.
jack, please. you didn't
like me from the second
i walked in here.
i'm a very accepting person,
focker.
all i ask for is honesty.
oh, honesty?
you wanna talk
about truth and honesty, jack?
okay, let's talk a little
truth and honesty. let's talk
a little "operation ko samui,"
jack.
what's he talking about, dad?
yeah, that's weird,
because i thought there
weren't any secrets inside
the circle of trust, jack.
i don't know what
you're talking about.
you don't?
what's the matter?
cat got your tongue?
hey, pam, guess what.
daddy's planning a little
covert operation in thailand
for the day after the wedding.
you are?
round and round we go, jack.
hey, i bet everybody would
love to hear about
your rendezvous
in the parking lot of
the oyster bay drug
and sundry.
you know what
i'm talking about.
where the guy gave you
the passports
and the documents.
or how about your
little phone call in thai?
jack can't talk thai.
oh, no, dina. jack can
talk thai. jack talk
thai very well.
i'm sorry, pam,
but your dad is not retired.
he's still very much
in the c.i.a.
daddy. what...
he's right.
he's right. my cover's blown.
i am planning a secret
operation the day
after the wedding.
what?
a surprise honeymoon
for deb and bob.
you stupid son of a bitch!
you just blew it!
what?
ko samui is an island
off the coast of thailand!
that guy i was meeting in
the parking lot is
thor svenson, my travel agent.
he was giving me their visas.
wow, thailand.
thanks a lot, j. b.
that's something.
don't mention it. i just...
you know, if this nursing
thing doesn't work out,
focker,
i'd say you definitely
have a career in espionage.
thanks, greg.
well, i guess i'm gonna go
to the airport now.
i guess you're
gonna stay here.
pam, i...
gaylord m. focker?
gaylord? gaylord?
yeah, that's me.
i thought your name was greg.
lt is.
that's not what it says
on the form.
i know.
it's my legal name.
nobody's called me by it
since i was in third grade.
(den ny laug hing)
dellvery man: whatever.
wait, wait, wait, wait.
so your name's gay focker?
(all laug hing)
denny.
i'm sorry. it's just it's not
a normal name.
come on.
now look what you've done.
oh, pammy.
don't go away.
you're in luck. there is room.
and without a saturday
stay-over, that fare
difference will be $1, 137. 11.
did you want me to
book you the seat?
okay. all right.
did you want to
check any bags today?
we should be all right
with only one usher,
don't you think?
i'm not so sure, jack.
thought you might
like to see this.
how did you get this?
oh, i have my sources too.
i called gaylord,
a. k.a. greg's parents
in detroit.
they saved his sat scores too,
in case you're interested.
oh, honey. that doesn't matter
if he did well on some test.
what does that prove?
look at this place!
he almost destroyed
the wedding
because he lied!
i love you, daddy,
but you can be
a real jerk sometimes.
so what if he took the mcats?
he's still not good enough
for pam.
who is, jack?
nobody has ever been
good enough for your pam.
i mean, do you realize
that you never even
warmed up to kevin
until she broke up with him?
maybe it's time you think
about what pam wants.
greg, it's me.
i'm sure you're
in the air by now,
so i guess you'll just
get this when you get home.
listen, i am so sorry.
i acted like a complete idiot,
and i hope that
you can forgive me.
i mean, i don't care about
the fire or the cat or...
i mean,
i can't believe you
actually spray-painted a cat.
that's actually really gross,
but the point is that...
that i understand
why you did it,
and i love you.
i want you to know
that i really love you, and...
when you get this,
will you please call me?
okay. bye.
marty, listen,
i need a commercial flight
i. d. scan.
lnterstate from
new york la guardia
to chicago.
four-hour sweeps,
backwards and forwards.
last name: foxtrot, oscar,
charlie, kilo, echo, romeo.
first name: golf, alpha,
yankee, lima...
<i>man: gaylord focker on</i>
<i>atlantic american</i>
<i>flight 27, departs 2:35.</i>
<i>affirmative.</i>
twenty-three minutes. thanks.
stewardess: enjoy your flight.
woman: thanks.
hello.
i'm sorry. we're only boarding
rows nine and above right now.
you'll have to wait.
well, i'm in row eight.
please step aside, sir.
it's just one row.
don't you think
it's okay if i...
we'll call
your row momentarily.
step aside, sir.
<i>thank you for waiting.</i>
<i>we'd like to continue</i>
<i>boarding the aircraft now.</i>
<i>we're now boarding all rows,</i>
<i>please. all remaining rows.</i>
hello.
enjoy your flight.
(car horns hon king)
excuse me.
okay, where's the fire?
woman: will you hand me
that pillow over there?
i'm sorry, sir. you're gonna
have to check that.
i got it.
no, i'm sorry.
that bag won't fit.
no, i'm not... hey.
i'm not checking my bag, okay?
there's no need
to raise your voice, sir.
i'm not raising my voice.
this would be
raising my voice to you, okay?
i don't want to check my bag.
by the way, your airline,
you suck at checking bags.
because i already
did that once,
and you lost it,
and then i had everything
screwed up very badly
for me. okay?
i can assure you that your bag
will be placed safely
below deck
with the other luggage.
oh, yeah? how do you know
my bag will be safe below
with the other luggage?
are you physically gonna
take my bag beneath the plane?
are you gonna go with the guys
with the earmuffs
and put it in there?
no.
no? okay.
then shut your pie hole
and listen to me
when i say that i am finished
with the checking-of-the-bags
conversation!
sir, we have a policy
on this airline that if
a bag is this large, we...
get your grubby little paws
off of my bag, okay?
it's not like i have a bomb
in here. it's not like
i want to blow up the plane.
i wanna stow my bag
according to your
safety regulations.
sir, sir...
if you would take a second
and take the little sticks
out of your head
and clean out your ears,
maybe you would see
that i'm a person
who has feelings,
and all i have to do
is do what i wanna do!
all i wanna do is hold onto
my bag and not listen to you!
the only way that i would
ever let go of my bag would be
if you came over here now
and tried to pry it
from my dead,
lifeless fingers.
okay? if you can get it
from my kung fu grip,
then you can have it.
okay? otherwise,
step off, bitch.
(gasps)
get off of me!
get off of me!
you got him?
yeah.
hey. hey!
you can't leave
your vehicle unattended.
tow it.
i've got a plane full
of people saying you
threatened that stewardess.
i was not threatening her.
i was trying to get my bag
into the overhead
storage thing.
you were acting like a maniac,
and you threatened her
with a bomb!
i said i didn't have a bomb!
you said "bomb."
i said, "it's not like
i have a bomb."
you said "bomb"
on an airplane.
what's wrong with saying
"bomb" on an airplane?
you can't say "bomb"
on an airplane.
bomb, bomb, bomb, bomb,
bomb, bomb, bomb, bomb,
bomb! you gonna arrest me?
you assaulted
an airline employee...
what if i was a bombardier?
i got enough to put you away
for a few years!
bomb, bomb, bomb!
norm. take five.
we got a specialist here.
bye, norm.
oh, shit. how'd you get here?
i'm everywhere, focker.
i didn't do anything, jack.
yeah, i know.
well, then tell these guys
that i'm not a terrorist.
listen, focker. i'm not gonna
tell anybody anything until
you answer some questions.
unless you want to spend
the next couple of years
of your life in prison,
you better goddamn
well tell me the truth.
no more lies. you understand?
no more lies.
did you do this?
just answer the questions.
did you have me
taken off of that airplane?
just answer the question.
put your hands
over there. that's it.
you're sick, you know that?
is your name
gaylord focker? yes or no?
yes.
are you a male nurse?
yes.
are you a pothead?
no.
have you ever smoked pot?
yes.
did you spray-paint
the tail of a cat to
pass him off as mr. jinx?
yes.
did you do that because
you desperately were
seeking my approval?
yes.
because you
love my daughter pam?
yes.
do you wanna marry her?
do you want to marry her?
i did, until i met you.
what does that mean?
i love your daughter, jack.
i love her more than anything.
but frankly, sir,
i'm a little terrified
of being your son-in-law.
this whole weekend
has given me a lot of doubts
about whether or not
i could even survive
in your family.
i think you've got
some serious issues.
if i lighten up,
would you consider
marrying my daughter?
would you lighten up a lot?
yeah.
yes or no?
yes.
would you let me and pam
live our lives and
not interfere all the time?
i promise not to interfere
in your lives all the time.
will you stop making fun of me
for being a nurse?
could you at least try,
maybe, to consider
another profession?
jack, yes or no?
ever?
no!
okay, yes.
would you let me and pam sleep
in the same room?
don't push it, focker.
you're in a real mess.
if you married my daughter,
would you support her
in the way
that she deserves
to be supported?
yes.
would you be honest
and faithful to her?
yes.
will you devote yourself
entirely to her
for the rest of your life?
of course.
gaylord focker,
will you be my son-in-law?
(door opening)
greg?
i thought you were
going back to chicago?
yeah, well, we had
a little plane trouble.
plus, your dad caught up
with me at the airport.
no. don't worry.
it's okay. we worked out
a lot of our issues.
you and my dad worked out
a lot of your issues?
yeah. first he gave me his
little human lie detector
thing, but i passed.
good.
yeah, and...
then he proposed.
are you feeling all right?
listen. this weekend
was a nightmare.
i had this whole
elaborate plan,
and then somewhere between
giving your sister a black eye
and setting the house on fire,
it kind of went off track.
i just... i love you.
i love you so much.
i think he's
about to do it, jack.
come on, honey.
give them some privacy.
...and i think if
we can get through
what we got through in
the last 48 hours, we could
get through anything.
i think so too.
and, greg, i don't...
wait. hang on a second.
mr. jinx? mew, mew, mew, mew.
mew, mew, mew, mew.
that's a ring.
i like to think of it
as a little circle of trust.
pam?
will you marry me?
yes.
yes.
attaboy, greg!
that "circle of trust" thing?
that's mine.
well, looks like we got
another wedding to plan.
yep. just gotta do
one more thing.
what's that?
meet his parents.
jack...
honey, relax.
i'm sure they're wonderful,
fascinating people.
good night, jack.
i mean, they'd have to be,
right, to name their son
gaylord focker?
(sighs)
do you, deborah byrnes,
take robert banks to be
your lawfully wedded husband?
debbie: yes. i mean, i do.
i now pronounce you
man and wife.
let's just see if you
really can flush the toilet,
jinxy.
i knew it.
<i>oh! shit!</i>
i knew it.
<i>damn it!</i>
that's my future son-in-law.
what do you think?
<i>hello, jack.</i>
<i>oh, look at that.</i>
<i>nice jack. hi.</i>
<i>what's that, jack? what?</i>
<i>you're a big, bad c.i.a. man,</i>
<i>huh?</i>
<i>did they teach you that</i>
<i>in the c.i.a.?</i>
<i>they teach you that?</i>
<i>oh, yeah. what's that,</i>
<i>jack? what?</i>
<i>yeah, you thought puff was</i>
<i>just the name of</i>
<i>the boy's magical dragon?</i>
<i>not too quick on</i>
<i>the uptake, huh, jack?</i>
<i>why don't you ask denny who's</i>
<i>puffing the magic dragon?</i>
<i>not onto that one, huh?</i>
<i>surprising for a big</i>
<i>c.i.a. pulse detector.</i>
<i>hey, hey,</i>
<i>check my pulse</i>
<i>on this question, jack.</i>
<i>do i think</i>
<i>you're a psycho? yes.</i>
<i>what? oh, you like</i>
<i>my little gift?</i>
<i>what? the jerusalem what?</i>
<i>what? i can't hear you.</i>
<i>jerusalem toodle-oo-poosey,</i>
<i>poosley-loo?</i>
what? what?
<i>oh, you don't know</i>
<i>shit about flowers.</i>
<i>what's that?</i>
<i>you want me to what?</i>
<i>you have another question?</i>
<i>sure. i got</i>
<i>one question for you.</i>
<i>it's can you deal with that?</i>
(man singing)
<i>when you're a fool in love</i>
<i>seems like the skies</i>
<i>are always gray</i>
<i>you turn around</i>
<i>there's someone in your way</i>
<i>and it's you</i>
<i>and you're in love</i>
<i>never another spring</i>
<i>for you</i>
<i>never a robin</i>
<i>to sing for you</i>
<i>you're out there</i>
<i>on your own</i>
<i>when you're</i>
<i>a fool in love</i>
(woman singing i n french)
(man singing)
<i>never another spring for you</i>
<i>you're out there</i>
<i>on your own</i>
both:
<i>when you're a fool in love</i>
