♪ yo ho
yo ho
♪ a pirate's life for me
♪ we extort, we pilfer
we filch, we sack
- ♪ drink...
- quiet, missy!
cursed pirates sail these waters.
you don't want to bring
them down on us, do ya?
mr. gibbs, that will do.
she was singing about pirates!
bad luck to be singing about pirates
with us mired in this unnatural fog,
mark my words.
consider them marked.
- on your way.
- aye, lieutenant.
it's bad luck to have
a woman on board too.
even a miniature one.
i think it'd be rather exciting
to meet a pirate.
think again, miss swann.
vile and dissolute creatures,
the lot of 'em.
i intend to see to it that any man
who sails under a pirate flag
or wears a pirate brand
gets what he deserves.
a short drop and a sudden stop.
lieutenant norrington,
i appreciate your fervor,
but i'm concerned about the effect
this subject will have upon my daughter.
my apologies, governor swann.
actually, i find it all fascinating.
yes. that's what concerns me.
look! a boy!
there's a boy in the water!
man overboard!
man the ropes!
fetch a hook!
haul him aboard!
he's still breathing.
mary, mother of god!
what happened here?
most likely the powder magazine.
merchant vessels run heavily armed.
lot of good it did them.
everyone's thinking it,
i'm just saying it.
pirates!
there's no proof of that!
it was probably an accident.
rouse the captain.
- aye, sir.
- heave to and take in sail.
- launch the boats.
- heave to!
elizabeth, i want you
to accompany the boy.
he'll be in your charge.
take care of him.
it's ok.
my name's elizabeth swann.
will turner.
i'm watching over you, will.
you're a pirate!
has he said anything?
his name's william turner.
that's all i found out.
take him below.
elizabeth!
are you all right?
are you decent?
yes.
yes?
still in bed at this hour?
it's a beautiful day.
i have a gift for you.
- oh, it's beautiful!
- isn't it?
may i inquire as to the occasion?
does a father need an occasion
to dote upon his daughter?
go on.
actually, i...
i had hoped you might wear it
for the ceremony today.
ceremony?
captain norrington's promotion ceremony.
i knew it!
commodore norrington,
as he's about to become.
a fine gentleman, don't you think?
he fancies you, you know.
elizabeth?
how's it coming?
it's difficult to say.
i'm told it's
the latest fashion in london.
well, women in london
must've learned not to breathe!
my lord, you have a visitor.
ah, mr. turner.
good to see you again.
good day, sir.
i have your order.
well...
the blade is folded steel.
that's gold filigree
laid into the handle.
if i may?
perfectly balanced.
the tang is nearly
the full width of the blade.
impressive. very impressive.
very nice.
commodore norrington's going
to be very pleased with this.
do pass my compliments
onto your master.
i shall.
a craftsman is always pleased
to hear his work is appreciated.
elizabeth!
you look absolutely stunning.
will.
it's so good to see you.
i had a dream about you last night.
about me?
is it entirely proper for you...?
about the day we met.
do you remember?
how could i forget, miss swann?
how many times must i ask you
to call me elizabeth?
at least once more, miss swann.
as always.
now, you see?
at least the boy
has a sense of propriety.
we really must be going.
come on.
good day, mr. turner.
come along!
good day...
...elizabeth.
hold up there, you!
it's a shilling to tie up
your boat to the dock.
and i shall need to know your name.
what do you say to three shillings,
and we forget the name?
welcome to port royal, mr. smith.
two paces... march!
right about... face!
present... arms!
this dock is off-limits to civilians.
i'm terribly sorry, i didn't know.
if i see one,
i shall inform you immediately.
apparently, there's some high-toned
and fancy to-do up at the fort, eh?
how could it be two upstanding
gentlemen, such as yourselves,
did not merit an invitation?
someone has to make sure this dock
stays off-limits to civilians.
it's a fine goal, to be sure.
but it seems to me, a...
a ship like that...
...makes this one here
a bit superfluous, really.
oh, the dauntless is the power
in these waters, true enough,
but there's no ship that can match
the interceptor for speed.
i've heard of one.
it's supposed to be very fast,
nigh uncatchable.
the black pearl.
there's no real ship
that can match the interceptor.
the black pearl is a real ship.
no. no, it's not.
yes, it is. i've seen it!
you've seen it?
- yes.
- you haven't seen it!
- yes, i have!
- you've seen a ship
with black sails,
that's crewed by the damned,
and captained by a man so evil
that hell itself spat him back out?
no.
but i have seen a ship
with black sails.
oh... and no ship that's
not crewed by the damned,
and captained by a man so evil
that hell spat him back out
could possibly have black sails,
therefore couldn't possibly
be any other ship
than the black pearl,
is that what you're saying?
no.
like i said,
there's no real ship
that can match the interceptor...
hey!
you!
get away from there!
you don't have permission
to be aboard there!
sorry. it's such a pretty boat.
ship!
what's your name?
smith!
or smithy, if you like.
what's your purpose in port royal,
mr. smith?
yeah, and no lies!
all right then.
i confess.
it is my intention to commandeer
one of these ships, pick up a crew
in tortuga to rape, pillage, and pilfer
my weasely black guts out.
i said, no lies!
i think he's telling the truth.
if he were telling the truth,
he wouldn't have told us.
unless he knew you wouldn't believe
the truth, even if he told it to you.
may i have a moment?
you look lovely, elizabeth.
yes.
i apologize if i seem forward,
but i must speak my mind.
this promotion throws into sharp relief
that which i have not yet achieved.
a marriage to a fine woman.
you have become a fine woman, elizabeth.
i can't breathe.
yes, i...
i'm a bit nervous myself.
and then they made me their chief.
elizabeth?
elizabeth!
the rocks!
sir, it's a miracle she missed them!
- will you be saving her, then?
- i can't swim!
pearl of the king's navy, you are!
do not lose these!
what was that?
make way!
i got her!
she's not breathing!
move!
i never would've thought of that.
clearly you've never been to singapore.
where did you get that?
on your feet.
elizabeth!
- are you all right?
- yes, i'm fine.
- shoot him!
- father! commodore...
...do you intend to kill my rescuer?
i believe thanks are in order.
had a brush with the east india
trading company, did we?
pirate?
hang him.
keep your guns on him, men.
gillette, fetch some irons.
well, well.
jack sparrow, isn't it?
captain jack sparrow,
if you please, sir.
well, i don't see your ship...
...captain.
i'm in the market, as it were.
he said he'd come to commandeer one.
i told you he was telling the truth.
these are his, sir.
no additional shots nor powder.
a compass that doesn't point north.
and i half expected it
to be made of wood.
you are, without doubt,
the worst pirate i've heard of.
but you have heard of me.
commodore, i really must protest!
carefully, lieutenant.
pirate or not, this man saved my life!
one good deed is not enough to redeem
a man of a lifetime of wickedness!
but it seems enough to condemn him.
indeed.
finally.
wait, don't shoot!
i knew you'd warm up to me.
commodore norrington,
my effects, please.
and my hat.
commodore.
- elizabeth. it is elizabeth, isn't it?
- it's miss swann.
miss swann, if you'd be so kind.
come, dear, we don't have all day.
now, if you'll be very kind.
easy on the goods, darling.
you're despicable.
sticks and stones, love.
i saved your life, you save mine.
we're square.
gentlemen...
...my lady...
...you will always remember this
as the day you almost caught...
...captain jack sparrow!
whoa!
now, will you shoot him?
open fire!
ahh!
burn his heels!
take steady aim.
fire!
take cover, men!
gillette...
...mr. sparrow has a dawn
appointment with the gallows.
i would hate for him to miss it.
search upstairs!
look lively, men!
whoa!
right where i left you.
not where i left you.
you're the one they're hunting.
the pirate!
you seem somewhat familiar.
have i threatened you before?
i make a point of avoiding
familiarity with pirates.
ah...
it would be a shame to put
a black mark on your record.
so if you'll excuse me...
do you think this wise, boy?
crossing blades with a pirate?
you threatened miss swann.
only a little.
you know what you're doing,
i'll give you that. excellent form.
but how's your footwork?
if i step here...
very good.
and now i step again.
ta.
that is a wonderful trick.
except, once again,
you are between me and my way out.
and now...
...you have no weapon.
who makes all these?
i do.
and i practice with them...
...three hours a day.
you need to find yourself a girl, mate.
or... perhaps the reason
you practice three hours a day
is that you already found one,
and are otherwise incapable
of wooing said strumpet.
you're not a eunuch, are you?
i practice three hours a day
so that when i meet a pirate,
i can kill him!
you cheated.
pirate.
- move away!
- no.
please move?
no!
i cannot just step aside
and let you escape.
this shot is not meant for you.
there he is! over here!
excellent work, mr. brown.
you've assisted in the capture
of a dangerous fugitive.
just doing my civic duty, sir.
i trust you will always remember
that this is the day
captain jack sparrow almost escaped.
take him away.
- come here, boy!
- smell it?
- come here, boy!
- you want a nice, juicy bone?
- hey!
- come here, boy!
- come here, boy!
- you can keep doing that forever.
the dog is never going to move.
well, excuse us if we haven't resigned
ourselves to the gallows just yet!
come on!
there you go, miss.
it was a difficult day for you,
i'm sure.
i suspected commodore norrington
would propose,
but i must admit,
i wasn't entirely prepared for it.
i meant you being
threatened by that pirate!
sounds terrifying!
oh... yes, it was terrifying.
but... the commodore proposed!
fancy that.
now that's a smart match, miss,
if it's not too bold to say.
it is a smart match.
he's a fine man.
he's what any woman
should dream of marrying.
well, that will turner,
he's a fine man too.
that is too bold.
well, beggin' your pardon, miss.
it was not my place.
has my daughter given
you an answer yet?
no, she hasn't.
well, she has had a very trying day.
ghastly weather, don't you think?
bleak. really bleak.
what's that?
cannon fire!
return fire!
i know those guns!
it's the pearl!
black pearl?
i've heard stories.
she's been preying on ships and
settlements for near ten years.
never leaves any survivors.
no survivors.
then where do the stories
come from, i wonder?
clear the dock!
mama!
hoist your oars!
come on, you!
sight the muzzle flash.
aim for the flashes.
i need a full spread, fore and aft.
mr. stevens, more cartridges!
governor!
barricade yourself in my office.
good god!
that's an order.
don't!
hello, chum.
up there! go!
miss! they've come to kidnap you!
- what?
- you're the governor's daughter!
in here!
they haven't seen you. hide, and the
first chance you get, run to the fort!
got ya! haven't i?
no! no! it's hot!
- i'm burning!
- come on!
come on, me lads!
come out.
we know you're here, poppet.
poppet.
come out...
...and we promise we won't hurt you.
eh?
we will find you, poppet.
you've got something of ours,
and it calls to us.
the gold calls to us.
the gold.
hello, poppet.
parley!
what?
parley.
i invoke the right of parley.
according to the code of brethren, set
down by pirates morgan and bartholomew,
- you have to take me to your captain.
- i know the code.
if an adversary demands parley,
you can do them no harm
- until the parley is complete.
- to blazes with the code!
she wants to be taken to the captain.
and she'll go, without a fuss.
we must honor the code.
say goodbye!
goodbye.
- come on!
- elizabeth!
well!
out of my way, scum!
my sympathies, friend.
you've no manner of luck at all.
come on, doggy!
it's just you and me now.
it's you and old jack.
come on.
come on. that's a boy!
good boy. come get your bone!
that's a good boy.
come on, a bit closer, a bit closer.
that's it! that's it, doggy!
come on, you filthy,
slimy, mangy cur!
don't do that. no, no, no!
i didn't mean it! i didn't...
this ain't the armory!
well, well, well.
look what we have here, twigg.
captain jack sparrow.
last time i saw you,
you were all alone
on a godforsaken island,
shrinking into the distance.
his fortunes aren't improved much.
worry about your own fortunes,
gentlemen.
the deepest circle of hell
is reserved for betrayers
and mutineers.
so there is a curse.
that's interesting.
you know nothing of hell.
that's very interesting.
i didn't know we was takin' on captives.
she's invoked the right of parley
with captain barbossa.
- i am here to negotia...
- you will speak when spoken to!
and ye will not lay a hand on those
under the protection of parley.
aye, sir.
my apologies, miss.
captain barbossa,
i am here to negotiate the cessation
of hostilities against port royal.
a lot of long words in there, miss.
we are naught but humble pirates.
what is it that you want?
i want you to leave
and never come back.
i'm disinclined
to acquiesce to your request.
means "no."
very well.
i'll drop it.
me holds are burstin' with swag!
that bit of shine matters to us?
why?
it's what you've been searching for.
i recognize the ship.
i saw it eight years ago
on the crossing from england!
did you now?
fine.
i suppose if it is worthless,
then there's no point in me keeping it.
no!
you have a name, missy?
elizabeth...
...turner.
i'm a maid in the governor's household.
miss turner!
turner!
bootstrap!
and how does a maid come
to own a trinket such as that?
family heirloom, perhaps?
i didn't steal it,
if that's what you mean.
very well. you hand it over,
we'll put your town to our rudder,
and ne'er return.
our bargain?
still the guns and stow 'em.
signal the men, set the flags
and make good to clear port.
wait! you have to take me to shore.
according to the code of
the order of the brethren...
your return to shore was not part
of our negotiations nor our agreements,
so i must do nothin'.
secondly, you must be a pirate
for the pirate's code to apply,
and you're not, and thirdly...
...the code is more of what
you'd call a guideline,
instead of actual rules.
welcome aboard the black pearl,
miss turner.
they've taken her!
they've taken elizabeth!
mr. murtogg, remove this man.
we have to hunt them down!
we must save her!
and where do you propose we start?
if you have any information concerning
my daughter, please share it.
that jack sparrow!
he talked about the black pearl.
mentioned it is more what he did.
ask him where it is! make a deal
with him, he could lead us to it.
no.
the pirates who invaded this fort
left sparrow locked in his cell,
ergo they are not his allies.
governor, we will establish
their most likely course...
that's not good enough!
mr. turner...
...you are not a military man,
you are not a sailor.
you are a blacksmith.
and this is not the moment
for rash actions!
do not make the mistake of thinking
you are the only man here
who cares for elizabeth.
please...
you! sparrow!
aye?
you are familiar with that ship,
the black pearl?
i've heard of it.
where does it make berth?
have you not heard the stories?
captain barbossa
and his crew of miscreants
sail from the dreaded isla de muerte.
it's an island that
cannot be found, except
by those who already know where it is.
the ship's real enough,
therefore its anchorage must be
a real place. where is it?
why ask me?
because you're a pirate.
and you want to turn
pirate yourself. ls that it?
never!
they took miss swann.
oh. so it is that you found a girl!
i see.
if you're intending to brave all,
hasten to her rescue,
and so win fair lady's heart...
...you'll have to do it alone, mate.
i see no profit in it for me.
i can get you out of here.
how's that? the key's run off.
i helped build these cells.
these are half-pin barrel hinges.
with the right leverage,
and the proper application of strength,
the door will lift free.
what's your name?
will turner.
that would be short for william,
i imagine.
good, strong name.
no doubt named for your father?
yes.
uh-huh.
well, mr. turner,
i've changed me mind.
if you spring me from this cell,
i swear, on pain of death,
i shall take you to the black pearl,
and your bonny lass.
do we have an accord?
- agreed.
- agreed.
get me out.
- hurry! someone will have heard that.
- not without my effects.
we're going to steal the ship?
that ship?
commandeer.
we're going to commandeer that ship.
nautical term.
one question about your business, boy,
or there's no use going.
this girl...
...how far are you willing to go
to save her?
i'd die for her.
oh, good.
no worries then.
this is either madness or brilliance.
it's remarkable how often
those two traits coincide.
everyone stay calm!
we're taking over the ship.
aye! avast!
this ship cannot be crewed by two men.
you'll never make it out of the bay.
son...
...i'm captain jack sparrow.
savvy?
commodore!
- sir!
- they're taking the dauntless!
commodore!
they're taking the ship!
sparrow and turner!
they're taking the dauntless!
rash, turner.
too rash.
that is, without doubt,
the worst pirate i have ever seen.
here they come.
bring her around!
bring her around!
search every cabin, every hold,
down to the bilges.
check the aft!
sailors, back to the interceptor!
now!
quickly, men
whoa!
thank you, commodore,
for getting us ready to make way.
we'd have had a hard time
of it by ourselves.
set topsails and clear up this mess.
with the wind a quarter astern,
we won't catch them!
i don't need to. just get them
in range of the long nines.
hands, come about! run out the guns!
bring out the guns!
we are to fire on our own ship, sir?
i'd rather see her at the bottom of the
ocean than in the hands of a pirate.
commodore! he's disabled
the rudder chain, sir.
abandon ship!
let go the gear
and sheet home.
that's got to be the best pirate
i've ever seen.
so it would seem.
when i was a lad,
living in england,
my mother raised me by herself.
after she died, i came out here,
looking for my father.
is that so?
my father,
bill turner?
at the jail, it was only after you
learned my name that you agreed to help.
since that's what i wanted,
i didn't press the matter.
i'm not a simpleton, jack.
you knew my father.
i knew him.
probably one of the few
who knew him as william turner.
everyone else just called him
"bootstrap," or "bootstrap bill."
bootstrap?
good man.
good pirate.
i swear, you look just like him.
it's not true.
he was a merchant sailor.
a good, respectable man
who obeyed the law.
he was a bloody pirate, a scallywag.
my father was not a pirate!
put it away, son.
it's not worth you getting beat again.
you didn't beat me.
you ignored the rules of engagement.
in a fair fight, i'd kill you.
that's not much incentive
for me to fight fair, is it?
now as long as you're just
hanging there, pay attention.
the only rules
that really matter are these:
what a man can do,
and what a man can't do.
for instance,
you can accept that your father
was a pirate and a good man,
or you can't.
pirate is in your blood, boy, so
you'll have to square with that someday.
now, me, for example.
i could let you drown,
but i can't bring this ship into tortuga
all by me onesies. savvy?
so...
can you sail under
the command of a pirate?
or can you not?
tortuga?
tortuga.
more importantly, it is indeed
a sad life that has never
breathed deep
the sweet, proliferous bouquet
that is tortuga. savvy?
what do you think?
it'll linger.
i'll tell you, mate, if every town
in the world were like this one,
no man would ever feel unwanted.
scarlett!
not sure i deserved that.
giselle!
who was she?
what?
i may have deserved that.
curse you for breathing,
you slack-jawed idiot!
mother's love!
jack!
you should know better than to
wake a man when he's sleepin'.
- it's bad luck.
- fortunately, i know how to counter it.
the man who did the waking buys
the man who was sleeping a drink,
and the man who was sleeping drinks
it while listening to a proposition
from the man who did the waking.
aye, that'll about do it.
blast! i'm already awake!
that was for the smell.
eh...
keep a sharp eye.
now...
...what's the nature
of this venture of your'n?
i'm going after the black pearl.
i know where it's going to be,
and i'm gonna take it.
jack,
it's a fool's errand!
well, you know better than me
the tales of the black pearl!
that's why i know
what barbossa is up to.
all i need is a crew.
what i hear tell of captain barbossa,
he's not a man to suffer fools,
nor strike a bargain with one!
i'd say it's a good thing
i'm not a fool then.
prove me wrong!
what makes you think barbossa
will give up his ship to you?
let's just say
it's a matter of leverage, eh?
hm?
mm.
huh?
hm...
mm-hm-hm.
the kid?
that is the child
of bootstrap bill turner.
his only child. savvy?
is he now?
leverage, says you.
i think i feel
a change in the wind, says i.
- mm.
- i'll find us a crew.
there's bound to be some sailors
on this rock, crazy as you.
one can only hope.
- take what you can!
- give nothin' back!
you'll be dining with the captain,
and he requests you wear this.
tell the captain i'm "disinclined
to acquiesce to his request."
he said you'd say that.
he also said, if that be the case...
...you'll be dining with the crew,
and you'll be naked.
fine.
there's no need to stand on ceremony
no call to impress anyone.
you must be hungry.
try the wine.
and the apples. one of those next.
it's poisoned.
there would be no sense
to be killing you.
then release me. you have your trinket.
i'm of no further value to you.
you don't know what this is,
do you?
it's a pirate medallion.
this is aztec gold.
one of 882 identical pieces
they delivered in a stone chest
to cortés himself.
blood money paid to stem the slaughter
he wreaked upon them with his armies.
but the greed of cortés was insatiable.
so the heathen gods
placed upon the gold...
...a terrible curse.
any mortal that removes but
a single piece from that stone chest...
...shall be punished for eternity.
i hardly believe in ghost stories
any more, captain barbossa.
aye.
that's exactly what i thought
when we were first told the tale.
buried on an isle of the dead
what cannot be found,
except for those who know where it is.
find it, we did.
there be the chest.
inside be the gold.
and we took 'em all!
we spent 'em and traded 'em,
and frittered 'em away
on drink and food
and pleasurable company.
the more we gave 'em away,
the more we came to realize...
...the drink would not satisfy.
food turned to ash in our mouths...
...and all the pleasurable company
in the world
could not slake our lust.
we are cursed men, miss turner.
compelled by greed we were, but now...
...we are consumed by it.
there is one way we can end our curse.
all the scattered pieces
of the aztec gold
must be restored,
and the blood repaid.
thanks to ye,
we have the final piece.
and the... blood to be repaid?
that's why there's no sense
to be killing ya.
yet.
apple?
ha-ha. hah!
arrgh!
no!
i'm curious.
after killing me, what is it
you're planning on doing next?
look!
the moonlight shows us
for what we really are.
we are not among the living
and so we cannot die.
but neither are we dead.
for too long i've been parched of thirst
and unable to quench it.
too long i've been starvin' to death,
and haven't died!
i feel nothing.
not the wind on my face,
nor the spray of the sea...
...nor the warmth of a woman's flesh.
you best start believing
in ghost stories, miss turner.
you're in one!
what are you looking at?
back to work!
feast your eyes, captain.
all of them,
faithful hands before the mast.
every man worth his salt...
...and crazy to boot.
so this is your able-bodied crew?
you, sailor!
cotton, sir.
mr. cotton.
do you have the courage and fortitude
to follow orders and stay true
in the face of danger and death?
mr. cotton!
answer, man!
he's a mute, sir.
poor devil had his tongue cut out.
so he trained the parrot
to talk for him.
no one's yet figured how.
mr. cotton's parrot.
same question.
- wind in your sails.
- wind in your sails.
mostly, we figure that means "yes."
of course it does.
satisfied?
well, you've proved they're mad!
and what's the benefit for us?
anamaria!
i suppose you didn't deserve
that one, either.
no, that one i deserved.
you stole my boat!
actually...
borrowed. borrowed, without permission,
but with every intention
of bringing it back to you.
but you didn't!
you'll get another one!
i will!
a better one.
a better one!
- that one!
- what one?
that one?
aye. that one.
- what say you?
- aye!
aye!
anchors away!
no, no, no, no, no!
it's frightful bad luck
to bring a woman aboard, sir.
it'll be far worse not to have her.
how can we sail to an island
that nobody can find,
with a compass that doesn't work?
aye, the compass doesn't point north,
but we're not trying
to find north, are we?
we should drop canvas, sir.
she can hold a bit longer.
what's in your head that's put you
in such a fine mood, captain?
we're catching up.
time to go, poppet.
dead men tell no tales...
puts a chill in the bones,
how many honest sailors
have been claimed by this passage.
how is it that jack
came by that compass?
not a lot's known about jack sparrow
'fore he showed up in tortuga
with a mind to go after
the treasure of isla de muerte.
that was before i met him,
back when he was captain
of the black pearl.
what?
he failed to mention that.
he plays things closer to the vest now.
and a hard-learned lesson it was.
three days out on the venture,
the first mate says,
"everything's an equal share.
that should mean the location
of the treasure too,"
so jack gives up the bearings.
that night, there was a mutiny.
they marooned jack on an island
and left him to die.
but not before he'd
gone mad with the heat.
ah...
so that's the reason for all the...
reason's got nothing to do with it.
now, will, when a pirate's marooned,
he's given a pistol with a single shot.
one shot...
well, that won't do much good hunting,
nor to be rescued.
but after three weeks
of a starving belly and thirst,
that pistol starts to look
real friendly.
but jack, he escaped the island,
and still has that single shot.
oh, he won't use it, though,
save on one man.
his mutinous first mate.
- barbossa.
- aye.
- how did jack get off the island?
- well, i'll tell ye.
he waded out into the shallows,
and he waited there three days
and three nights,
till all manner of sea creatures
came acclimated to his presence.
and on the fourth morning,
he roped a couple of sea turtles,
lashed them together and made a raft.
- he roped a couple of sea turtles.
- aye.
sea turtles!
what did he use for rope?
human hair.
from my back.
let go the anchor!
lower the anchor line!
young mr. turner and i are to go ashore.
captain.
what if the worst should happen?
- keep to the code.
- aye. the code.
move.
ten years of hoarding swag!
and now we finally get to spend it!
oh.
once we're quit of the curse,
we'll be rich men...
...and you can buy an eye what
actually fits and is made of glass.
this one does splinter
something terrible!
stop rubbing it!
oh!
what code is gibbs to keep to
if the worst should happen?
the pirates' code.
any man who falls behind...
...is left behind.
no heroes amongst thieves, eh?
you know, for having
such a bleak outlook on pirates,
you're well on your way
to becoming one.
sprung a man from jail...
...commandeered a ship of the fleet,
sailed with a buccaneer crew
out of tortuga...
...and you're completely
obsessed with treasure!
that's not true.
i am not obsessed with treasure.
not all treasure
is silver and gold, mate.
gentlemen, the time has come!
hurrah!
salvation is nigh!
yeah!
- our torment is near an end!
- elizabeth.
for ten years,
we've been tested and tried,
and each man-jack of you here
has proved his mettle 100 times over.
and 100 times again!
yeah!
suffered, i have!
punished, we were,
the lot of us,
disproportionate to our crime!
right!
here it is!
the cursed treasure of cortés himself.
every last piece that went astray,
we have returned.
save for this!
- yeah!
- jack!
not yet!
we'll wait for the opportune moment.
...despairing
of ever finding the lass.
when's that?
when it's of greatest profit to you?
may i ask you something?
have i ever given you
reason not to trust me?
do us a favor.
i know it's difficult for you,
but please, stay here,
and try not to do anything stupid.
and who among us
has paid the blood sacrifice
- owed to the heathen gods?
- aye!
and whose blood must yet be paid?
hers!
you know the first thing i'm going
to do after the curse is lifted?
eat a whole bushel of apples!
begun by blood,
by blood undone.
sorry, jack.
i'm not going to be your leverage.
that's it?
waste not.
did it work?
- i don't feel no different.
- how do we tell?
you're not dead!
no.
he shot me!
it didn't work!
the curse is still upon us!
you! maid! your father,
what was his name?
was your father william turner?
no.
where's his child? the child that sailed
from england eight years ago?
the child in whose veins flows
the blood of william turner?
where?
you two!
- you brought us the wrong person!
- yeah!
no!
she had the medallion!
she's the proper age!
she said her name
was turner. you heard her!
- i think she lied to us!
- yeah!
you brought us here for nothing!
i won't take questionin' or second
guesses, not from you, mr. twigg!
who's to blame him? every decision
you made has led us from bad to worse!
it was you who sent
bootstrap to the depths!
yeah!
and it's you who brought us
here in the first place!
if any coward here dare challenge me,
let him speak!
i say, we cut her throat,
and spill all her blood!
just in case.
- yeah!
- yeah!
yeah!
the medallion!
she's taken it!
get after her,
you feckless pack of ingrates!
- where's the oars?
- there's no oars!
the oars have gone missing!
find them!
you!
you're supposed to be dead!
am i not?
oh.
puh-la-lem.
puh-la-lie-lay-lool.
pah-lee-nee...
...parsnip... par-sley...
...par... partner, pardoner...
parley?
that's the one! parley!
parley!
parley?!
damn to the depths whatever
muttonhead thought up parley!
that would be the french.
not more pirates!
welcome aboard, miss elizabeth.
mr. gibbs?
hey, boy, where be jack?
jack? jack sparrow?
he fell behind.
keep to the code!
- weigh anchor!
- hoist the sails!
split-quick, you dibbies!
how the blazes
did you get off that island?
when you marooned me on
that godforsaken spit of land,
you forgot one
very important thing, mate.
i'm captain jack sparrow.
ah, well, i won't be
making that mistake...
...again.
gents, you all remember
captain jack sparrow?
aye.
kill him.
the girl's blood didn't work, did it?
hold your fire!
you know whose blood we need?
i know whose blood you need.
what sort of a man
trades a man's life for a ship?
a pirate.
here.
let me.
thank you.
you said you gave barbossa
my name as yours.
why?
i don't know.
i'm sorry. a blacksmith's hands.
- i know they're rough.
- no... i mean, yes, they are, but...
but don't stop.
elizabeth!
it's yours.
i thought i'd lost it
the day they rescued me.
it was a gift from my father.
he sent it to me.
why did you take it?
because i was afraid
that you were a pirate.
that would've been awful.
it wasn't your blood they needed.
it was my father's blood.
my blood.
the blood of a pirate.
will, i'm so sorry.
please forgive me.
so you expect to leave me standin' on
some beach, with nothing but a name
and your word it's the one i need,
and watch you sail away in my ship?
no.
i expect to leave you standing on some
beach with absolutely no name at all,
watching me sail away on my ship,
and then i'll shout
the name back to you.
savvy?
that still leaves the problem
of me standing on some beach,
with naught but a name and your word
it's the one i need.
of the two of us,
i am the only one who
hasn't committed mutiny.
therefore, my word is
the one we'll be trusting.
although...
i suppose i should be thanking you
because, in fact,
if you hadn't betrayed me
and left me to die,
i would have an equal share
in that curse, same as you.
funny ol' world, isn't it?
hm.
captain! we're coming up
on the interceptor.
i'm having a thought here, barbossa.
what say we run up a flag of truce,
i scurry over to the interceptor,
and i negotiate the return of your
medallion. what say you to that?
you see, jack, that's exactly
the attitude that lost you the pearl.
people are easier to search
when they're dead.
lock him in the brig.
hands aloft to loose ta'gallants!
with this wind dead astern,
she'll carry every sail we've got.
- what's happening?
- the black pearl!
she's gaining on us!
this is the fastest ship
in the caribbean!
you can tell them that
after they've caught us!
we're shallower on the draft, right?
aye.
can't we lose them amongst those shoals?
we don't have to outrun 'em long.
just long enough.
lighten the ship!
stem to stern!
anything we can afford to lose,
see that it's lost!
apparently, there's a leak.
haul on the main brace!
make ready the guns!
and run out the sweeps.
we're gonna need that.
it was a good plan, up till now.
gibbs!
we have to make a stand.
we must fight!
- load the guns!
- with what?
anything! everything!
anything we have left!
load the guns!
case shot and langrage!
nails and crushed glass!
with a will!
the pearl's gonna luff up
on our port quarter!
she'll rake us without ever
presenting a target!
lower the anchor on the right side.
on the starboard side!
- it has the element of surprise.
- you're daft, lady!
you both are!
daft like jack!
lower the starboard anchor!
do it, you gobs, or it's you
we'll load into the cannons!
aye!
let go!
they're club haulin'!
hard a port!
rack the starboard oars!
hard a port!
keep her steady, man.
now!
fire!
stop blowing holes in my ship!
we could use a few more ideas, lass!
it's your turn!
we need us a devil's dowry!
we'll give them her!
she's not what they're after.
the medallion!
strike your colors,
you bloomin' cockroaches!
hands, grapnels, at the ready!
prepare to board!
ahh!
pistols and cutlasses, men!
koehler and twigg
to the powder magazine!
and the rest of you,
bring me the medallion!
hey! hey!
hey! below!
thanks very much.
ha-haa!
whoa!
jack!
bloody empty!
that's not very nice.
where is the medallion?
wretch!
ah...
where is dear william?
will!
- will!
- elizabeth!
monkey!
i can't move it!
will!
elizabeth!
will!
why, thank you, jack.
you're welcome.
not you. we named the monkey jack.
gents! our hope is restored!
yeah!
any of you so much
as thinks the word parley,
i'll have your guts for garters!
will!
stop it! stop it!
welcome back, miss.
you took advantage of
our hospitality last time.
it holds fair now
that you return the favor!
no! no!
barbossa!
will.
she goes free!
what's in your head, boy?
she goes free.
you've only got one shot,
and we can't die.
don't do anything stupid!
you can't.
i can.
like that.
who are you?
no one! he's no one!
a distant cousin of my aunt's
nephew, twice removed.
- lovely singing voice, though.
- eunuch!
my name is will turner!
my father was bootstrap bill turner.
his blood runs in my veins.
it's the spitting image
of ol' bootstrap bill,
come back to haunt us!
on my word, do as i say,
or i'll pull this trigger,
and be lost to davy jones' locker!
name your terms, mr. turner.
elizabeth goes free!
yes, we know that one.
anything else?
and the crew!
the crew are not to be harmed!
agreed.
go on, poppet. walk the plank.
barbossa, you lying bastard!
you swore she'd go free!
don't dare impugn me honor, boy!
i agreed she'd go free.
it was you who failed to specify
when or where.
though it does seem a shame to lose
something so fine, don't it, lads?
aye.
so i'll be havin' that dress
back before you go.
i always liked you.
goes with your black heart!
mm. it's still warm.
off you go!
come on!
too long!
i really rather hoped
we were past all this.
jack.
jack!
did ya not notice?
that be the same island we made you
governor of on our last little trip.
i did notice.
perhaps you'll be able to conjure up
another miraculous escape,
but i doubt it.
off you go.
last time you left me
a pistol with one shot.
by the powers, you're right!
where be jack's pistol?
bring it forward.
seeing as there's two of us,
a gentleman...
...would give us a pair of pistols.
it'll be one pistol, as before,
and you can be the gentleman
and shoot the lady,
and starve to death yourself!
that's the second time i've had to watch
that man sail away with my ship.
you were marooned on this island
before, weren't you?
we can escape the same way!
to what point and purpose, young missy?
the black pearl is gone,
and unless you have a rudder and
a lot of sails hidden in that bodice...
unlikely...
young mr. turner will be dead
long before you can reach him.
but you're captain jack sparrow!
you vanished from under the eyes of
seven agents of the east india company!
you sacked nassau port
without even firing a shot!
are you the pirate
i've read about or not?
how did you escape last time?
last time...
...i was here a grand total
of three days, all right?
last time...
...the rum runners used this island
as a cache.
they came by and i was able
to barter passage off.
from the looks of things,
they've long been out of business.
you probably have your bloody friend
norrington to thank for that.
so that's it then?
that's the secret, grand adventure
of the infamous jack sparrow!
you spent three days,
lying on a beach, drinking rum.
welcome to the caribbean, love.
♪ we're devils
we're black sheep
♪ we're really bad eggs
♪ drink up, me hearties
yo ho
♪ yo ho, yo ho
a pirate's life for me
i love this song!
really bad eggs!
ooh...
when i get the pearl back,
i'm gonna teach it to the whole crew,
and we'll sing it all the time!
and you will be positively the most
fearsome pirates in the spanish main!
not just the spanish main, love.
the entire ocean!
the entire world!
wherever we want to go, we go.
that's what a ship is, you know.
it's not just a keel and a hull
and a deck and sails.
that's what a ship needs.
but what a ship is...
what the black pearl really is...
...is freedom.
jack...
it must be really terrible for you
to be trapped on this island.
oh, yes.
but the company is...
...infinitely better than last time,
and the...
...scenery has definitely improved.
- mr. sparrow!
i'm not entirely sure i've had
enough rum to allow that kind of talk.
i know exactly what you mean, love.
to freedom!
to the black pearl.
hm?
no!
not good! stop!
not good!
what are you doing?
you've burned all the food, the shade...
...the rum!
- yes, the rum is gone.
why is the rum gone?
one, because it is a vile drink
that turns even the most respectable
men into scoundrels.
two, that signal
is over 1,000 feet high.
the entire royal navy
is out looking for me.
do you think there is even
the slightest chance
they won't see it?
but why is the rum gone?
just wait, captain sparrow.
you give it one hour, maybe two,
keep a weather eye open, and you
will see white sails on that horizon.
"must've been terrible for you
to be trapped here, jack."
"must've been terrible for you..."
well, it bloody is now!
there'll be no
living with her after this.
- we've got to save will!
- no! you're safe now.
we will return to
port royal immediately,
not go gallivanting after pirates!
then we condemn him to death!
the boy's fate is regrettable...
...but then, so was his decision
to engage in piracy.
to rescue me! to prevent anything
from happening to me!
if i may be so bold as to interject
my professional opinion,
the pearl was listing
near to scuppers after the battle.
it's very unlikely she'd be able
to make good time.
think about it.
the black pearl.
the last real pirate threat
in the caribbean, mate.
how can you pass that up?
by remembering that i serve others,
mr. sparrow,
- not only myself.
- commodore, i beg you!
please do this!
for me!
as a wedding gift.
elizabeth?
are you accepting
the commodore's proposal?
i am.
a wedding! i love weddings!
drinks all around!
i know. "clap him in irons," right?
mr. sparrow...
...you will accompany
these fine men to the helm
and provide us with a bearing
to isla de muerta.
you'll then spend the rest of the voyage
contemplating all possible meanings
of the phrase "silent as the grave."
do i make myself clear?
inescapably clear.
shiver me timbers!
cotton says you missed a bit.
you knew william turner?
old bootstrap bill.
we knew him.
never sat well with bootstrap,
what we did to jack sparrow,
the mutiny and all.
he said it wasn't right with the code.
that's why he sent off a piece
of the treasure to you, as it were.
he said we deserved to be cursed...
...and remain cursed.
stupid blighter!
good man.
but, as you can imagine, that
didn't sit too well with the captain.
that didn't sit too well
with the captain at all!
- tell him what barbossa did.
- i'm telling the story!
so... what the captain did...
...he strapped a cannon
to bootstrap's bootstraps.
bootstrap's bootstraps.
last we saw of ol' bill turner...
...he was sinking to
the crushin' black oblivion
of davy jones' locker!
'course it was only after that
we learned we needed his blood
to lift the curse.
that's what you'd call ironic.
bring him!
i don't care for the situation.
any attempt to storm the caves
could turn into an ambush.
not if you're the one
doing the ambushing.
i go in and convince barbossa to send
his men out in their little boats.
you and your men
return to the dauntless
and blast the bejesus out of them
with your little cannons.
what do you have to lose?
nothing i'd lament being rid of.
now, to be quite honest with you,
there's still a slight risk
to those aboard the dauntless,
which includes
the future mrs. commodore.
- it's for your safety!
- don't care what the commodore ordered!
i have to tell him!
the pirates! they're cursed!
they can't be killed!
don't worry, miss.
he's already informed of that.
a little mermaid flopped up on deck
and told him the whole story!
this is jack sparrow's doing!
no reason to fret.
just a prick of the finger,
a few drops of blood...
no mistakes this time.
he's only half turner.
we spill it all!
guess there is reason to fret.
beg your pardon, mate.
beg your pardon.
- begun by blood...
- excuse me.
by blood un...
jack!
it's not possible!
not probable.
where's elizabeth?
she's safe, just like i promised.
she's all set to marry norrington,
just like she promised,
and you get to die for her,
just like you promised.
so we're all men of our word, really.
except for elizabeth,
who is, in fact, a woman.
shut up! you're next!
you don't want to be doing that, mate.
no, i really think i do.
your funeral.
and why don't i want to be doing it?
oh, because...
because the hms dauntless,
the pride of the royal navy,
is floating just off shore,
waiting for you.
what we doing here?
the pirates come out,
unprepared and unawares.
we catch 'em in a crossfire,
and send 'em down to see old hob.
i know why we're here. i meant...
...why aren't we doing what it was...
what mr. sparrow said we should do?
with the cannons and all?
because it was mr. sparrow who said it.
you think he wasn't telling the truth?
just hear me out, mate.
you order your men to row out to the
dauntless, they do what they do best...
robert's your uncle, fanny's your aunt.
there you are with two ships.
the makings of your very own fleet.
'course, you'll take the grandest
as your flagship, and who's to argue?
but what of the pearl?
name me captain.
i'll sail under your colors,
i'll give you ten percent of me plunder,
and you'll get to
introduce yourself as...
...commodore barbossa.
savvy?
i suppose, in exchange, you'll be
- wanting me not to kill the whelp.
- no. not at all!
by all means, kill the whelp!
just not yet.
wait to lift the curse
until the opportune moment.
for instance...
...after you've killed norrington's men.
every...
...last...
...one.
you've been planning this
from the beginning!
ever since you learned my name!
yeah.
i want 50 percent of your plunder.
- 15!
- 40!
and i'll buy you the hat.
a really big one.
commodore.
we have an accord.
all hands to the boats!
apologies.
you give the orders.
gents...
...take a walk!
not to the boats?
hold fire!
this is just like what
the greeks done at troy!
'cept they was in a horse,
instead of dresses.
wooden horse.
a moment, please.
elizabeth?
i just want you to know, i...
i believe you made a very
good decision today.
couldn't be more proud of you!
but, you know,
even a good decision,
if made for the wrong reasons,
can be a wrong decision.
lieutenant.
yoo-hoo.
elizabeth?
are you there?
elizabeth, are you even listening to me?
oh, what have you done?
- yoo-hoo.
- stop that! i already feel like a fool!
look nice, though.
do i look nice now?!
i must admit, jack.
i thought i had you figured.
but it turns out you're
a hard man to predict.
me, i'm dishonest.
and a dishonest man you can
always trust to be dishonest.
honestly...
...it's the honest ones
you want to watch out for.
'cause you can never predict
when they're going to do
something incredibly...
...stupid.
ha-ha!
ha-ha!
ha!
you're off the edge of the map, mate.
here, there be monsters!
what would you pick to eat first?
i think we should decide now,
just so we're ready when the time comes!
what was that?
oh.
shh!
it's elizabeth!
make for the ship! move!
ahh!
to the ship!
marines, arms!
you can't beat me, jack.
that's interesting!
i couldn't resist, mate.
oh, no.
sorry!
so, what now, jack sparrow?
are we to be two immortals,
locked in an epic battle
until judgment day,
when the trumpets sound?
hm?
or you could surrender.
ahh!
ah-ha-ha-ha-ha.
all of you with me!
will is in that cave,
and we must save him!
ready, and... heave!
please, i need your help! come on!
any port in a storm.
cotton's right. we've got the pearl!
what about jack?
are you just gonna leave him?
jack owes us a ship!
there's the code to consider.
the code?
you're pirates!
hang the code
and hang the rules!
they're more like guidelines, anyway.
bloody pirates!
- oi!
- what?
is it supposed to be doing that?
they're stealing our ship!
bloody pirates!
boarders away!
come on!
no! me eye!
no!
ha!
i'm gonna teach you the meaning of pain!
you like pain?
try wearing a corset.
whose side is jack on?
at the moment?
no fair!
ten years you carry that pistol,
and now you waste your shot!
he didn't waste it.
i feel...
...cold.
oh... ugh! oh!
parley?
the ship is ours, gentlemen.
huzzah! huzzah!
huzzah!
we should return to the dauntless.
your fiancé will be wanting
to know you're safe.
if you were waiting for
the opportune moment...
...that was it.
now if you'd be so kind,
i'd be much obliged
if you'd drop me off at my ship.
i'm sorry, jack.
they done what's right by them.
can't expect more than that.
jack sparrow!
- we have learned that you...
- captain! captain jack sparrow.
...for your willful commission
of crimes against the crown.
said crimes being numerous in quantity,
and sinister in nature.
the most egregious of these
to be cited herewith:
- piracy, smuggling...
- this is wrong.
commodore norrington
is bound by the law,
as are we all.
...impersonating an officer
of the spanish royal navy,
impersonating a cleric
of the church of england...
oh, yes!
sailing under false colors,
arson, kidnapping, looting, poaching,
brigandage, pilfering,
depravity, depredation,
and general lawlessness.
and for these crimes,
you have been sentenced to be,
on this day,
hung by the neck, until dead.
may god have mercy on your soul.
governor swann.
commodore.
elizabeth.
i should've told you every day,
from the moment i met you.
i love you.
oi, watch yourself!
marines!
i can't breathe!
elizabeth!
move!
goodness sake!
you men! with me!
move!
come on!
come on, men!
i thought we might have to endure some
manner of ill-conceived escape attempt.
but not from you.
on our return to port royal,
i granted you clemency.
and this is how you thank me?
by throwing in your lot with him?
he's a pirate!
and a good man.
if all i've achieved here
is that the hangman
will own two pairs
of boots instead of one,
so be it.
at least my conscience will be clear.
you forget your place, turner.
it's right here,
between you and jack.
as is mine.
elizabeth!
lower your weapons.
for goodness sake, put them down!
so this is where
your heart truly lies, then.
it is.
well! i'm actually feeling
rather good about this.
i think we've all arrived
at a very special place, eh?
- oh.
- spiritually.
ecumenically.
grammatically.
i want you to know that
i was rooting for you, mate.
know that.
elizabeth.
it would never have worked
between us, darling.
i'm sorry.
will!
nice hat.
friends!
this the day that you will always
remember as the day that...
idiot! he's nowhere to go
but back to the noose!
sail ho!
what's your plan of action?
sir?
perhaps on the rare occasion
pursuing the right course
demands an act of piracy,
piracy itself can be the right course?
mr. turner!
i will accept the consequences
of my actions.
this is a beautiful sword.
i would expect the man who made it
to show the same care and devotion
in every aspect of his life.
thank you.
commodore!
what about sparrow?
oh, i think we can afford
to give him one day's head start.
so...
this is the path you've chosen, is it?
after all...
...he is a blacksmith.
no.
he's a pirate.
heave!
thought you were supposed
to keep to the code, eh?
we figured they were more actual...
...guidelines.
thank you.
captain sparrow.
the black pearl is yours!
on deck, you scabrous dogs!
hands to braces!
let go and haul to run free.
now...
bring me that horizon.
♪ ...and really bad eggs
♪ drink up, me hearties
yo ho ♪