george, wake up.
- george!
- it's saturday.
i know, but it's the first day of soccer.
it's our first game.
soccer?
i can't today. i caught a cold while sleeping.
you'll be fine.
come on, come on, it'll be great.
we're going to play like brazilians.
- here you go.
- thanks, mom.
stuart, don't forget your water bottle.
george....
don't forget your cleats.
you look especially beautiful today.
some people just know how to wear oatmeal.
okay, open up.
did you hear that? she said "blah-blah."
i can't believe it.
her first word.
where's the baby book? i'm writing it down.
i'm not sure that's technically a word.
of course it is.
but your uncle crenshaw says
that every little starts talking by nine months.
in uncle crenshaw's case, never stops.
are you both coming to the game?
wouldn't miss it.
frederick...
...this soccer game's making me very....
- proud?
- anxious. especially about....
- i'm fine.
- he's fine.
all those boys stomping around with cleats.
what if someone....
oh, honey. he's a little.
all littles are natural athletes.
- do you need....
- could you?
okay, that's it for you.
snow, food.
food? is it tuna? or herring?
or, dare i say it, is it lox?
oh! please be lox!
snow, that's for you.
- boys, are we ready to play some soccer?
- you bet, dad.
oh, great. it's glop.
look what i'm reduced to.
i'm a handi wipe with hair.
wallace! get up! there we go!
that's right! dig! dig!
go downfield! downfield!
you guys, spread out! spread out!
- well, george is getting a workout.
- yeah!
what bothers me is that every kid
has had a chance to play except stuart.
there's plenty of time.
plenty of time? there's 40 seconds.
he did an excellent job
of handing out the orange slices.
that's not as easy as it looks.
okay, i'm glad he's not in the game.
i don't want him to get hurt.
it's pee-wee soccer. nobody gets hurt.
irwin, are you okay?
are you all right, irwin?
do i look all right?
here. come on.
better substitute.
tie game. we could play with just 10.
but we have george, so it's like having nine.
wallace, we'll have none of that.
come on, coach.
stuart! go in for irwin!
mom! dad! i'm going in!
yeah, stuart!
oh, dear.
all right, stuart, watch your tail out there.
don't worry, i won't let you down.
now, go get them.
let's go, let's go! come on!
over here! i'm open!
i got it! i got it!
- i'm going to snatch him off the field.
- honey, honey.
knowing boys as i do,
i think he might find that a little...
embarrassing.
get it, george!
go after it!
pass me the ball, lame-o. come on.
george, shoot!
i got it! i got it!
shoot!
i got it! i got it!
yeah, i did it!
i have to start wearing a cup.
he just looked so small out there.
so lacking in bigness.
does he really have to go back next week?
honey, we have to give him room to grow.
i do. i let him slice his own banana.
with a spoon.
i let him drive his car to school.
no other mother does that.
with george walking beside him
every step of the way.
how much more room do i have to give him?
a little more than you're giving him now.
maybe mom was right.
maybe i shouldn't be playing soccer anymore.
what does she want you to go out for?
painting or dancing.
i guess it's my fault.
i'm sorry i kicked you into the goal.
that's okay. you won the game.
that's the main thing.
no. the main thing is i hit wallace in the face.
bogeys, 12:00! i got him, brooklyn!
wouldn't it be cool if i actually flew this thing?
yeah. there's only one problem.
mom.
- hello, mrs. little.
- hi, will.
- is george home?
- he's in with stuart.
we just need to tighten her up
and she's ready to fly.
hi, george. hi, stuart.
- hi, will.
- hi.
you want to take a break for a while?
i brought my ps2.
yeah, okay.
but what about the plane?
i want to play with will for a while.
play with snowbell.
oh, well. guess i'll have to finish it myself.
if i can just...
oh, dear.
hey, what's that noise?
sounds like a lawnmower.
inside the house?
stuart!
stuart, what are you doing?
i'm not doing anything!
pull the brake!
get the book!
this is cool.
all my brother does is jam crayons up his nose.
it says, "on takeoff, pull back on the throttle."
takeoff? i'm in the air!
snowbell, get out of the way!
please, don't hurt me!
what's going on?
stuart's just flying in the house.
flying in the house?
at least he's indoors, nothing bad can happen.
watch out!
hit the dirt!
stuart!
duck!
- stuart, are you all right?
- are you okay?
i'm okay.
everything's fine.
fine? stuart, you destroyed it.
- i'm sorry i wracked it, george!
- i'm sure we can fix it with some glue.
no, we can't. that's going in the trash.
it's much too dangerous.
thanks, stuart.
why don't you take the boys home?
i think stuart and i need to have a talk.
good idea.
come on, boys. let's go home.
she treats me like a baby.
i'll fix you both some lunch.
she just loves you so much.
it's hard for her to think of you in danger.
oh, this has been a bad day.
mom's mad, george won't play with me....
i know. but every cloud has a silver lining.
doesn't that make them kind of heavy?
no, it's an expression, stuart.
the thing about being a little is
that you can look at any situation...
...no matter how bleak, how hopeless...
...and still see the bright side. the silver lining.
like in this situation,
the silver lining would be...
help me, dad, because i'm struggling.
george has found a new friend.
that means you could find a new friend, too.
you're a lot better at this than i am.
i've been a little a lot longer than you have.
you'll get the hang of it.
meantime, keep your chin up...
...your back straight and your heart open.
- then what?
- one step at a time.
and canada is separate
from the united states because...
...canadians like to be alone.
review tomorrow, test on friday.
and please take your leftover lunches with you.
my husband is tired of me coming home
smelling like salami.
tony, would you like to come over
to my house this afternoon?
sorry, pal. i've got karate.
hey, mark.
guitar lessons.
hey stuart, some of the guys are going
over to will's house to play basketball.
can i come?
they didn't exactly mention
that you were invited.
oh, that's okay. i'm busy anyway.
just tell mom i walked you home, ok?
i owe you one.
sure.
whoa!
miss?
miss?
are you alive?
she's alive.
out of the way, please.
injured bird coming through!
what's going on?
my wing.
where am i? hey! where's the falcon?
what falcon?
that falcon! drive! get out of here!
oh, my!
get lost, you disgusting vulture!
eat my feathers, you vile buzzard!
do we really want to antagonize him?
oh, boy, we've got a problem.
no, you can make it. don't slow down.
you did it.
yeah. i did.
so, who do i have to thank?
forgive me. my name is stuart. stuart little.
i'm margalo. just margalo.
margalo.
you're so strong. are you an athlete?
well, yeah.
i play a little soccer...
...fly airplanes...
...race boats.
you can put me down now.
my legs are fine. it's my wing that's hurt.
oh. yeah. of course.
there used to be bandages in here.
- hey, why don't we try your scarf?
- good idea.
my pin, it's....
must have happened
when that falcon smashed into me.
it was part of our nest when i was a baby.
i've had it my whole life.
it's the only thing i have left of my mother's.
gee, that's too bad.
yeah.
there. how's that?
that's much better, thank you.
so tell me, stuart little,
do you actually live here?
oh, yeah. i'm a real little. i'm the middle child.
the middle little.
cute.
so, where do you live?
- you know, here and there.
- you mean you don't have a home?
once, we lived in a box. well, not really a box.
it was one of those things
where people keep their jewelry, you know?
a jewelry box?
yes! that's what it must have been.
a jewelry box.
it was wonderful.
well, i've taken too much of your time.
i'd better go before it gets dark.
no, wait. you can't go out there.
not while you're hurt. you should stay here.
i couldn't impose.
i mean, you'd really do that for me?
sure, i have just the thing. i'll be right back.
- meanwhile, you can use my cat's bed.
- you have a cat?
don't worry about snowbell.
he wouldn't hurt a fly.
those flies really come back on you.
i try to eat right and yet i still feel bloated.
maybe more food will help.
hi there.
sorry. didn't mean to scare you!
scare me? that's a laugh.
hear that? that was a laugh.
hairball. major hairball.
and yet we continue to lick ourselves.
unbelievable.
hey, snowbell. meet margalo.
she'll be staying with us for a while.
staying? are you out of your mind?
stuart, you can't just drag stray birds in here.
do you think this is a halfway house?
look at her, she's filthy.
no offense. she could have germs.
and how do you know she's not a vagrant
or a thief? get rid of her.
we're home. sorry we're late.
- little hi, little low.
- little hey, little ho.
what the heck was that?
that's just how we greet each other.
interesting.
nauseating is more like it.
you're in for it now, missy.
mother little hates when animals
walk in here off the street.
when she sees this, she's going to throw a fit.
such a pretty little birdie.
maybe it's just my friends she hates.
- i found her.
- found me? he did more than that.
he saved my life.
he did?
- from a falcon.
- what was that?
stuart saved this little bird from a falcon.
a falcon? they are fierce creatures.
why does the city have falcons?
that shouldn't be allowed. write a letter.
on the other hand, we have a hero here.
way to go, stuart.
- hey, dad.
- what?
silver lining.
it's a guy thing.
is it?
isn't it nice that stuart has a friend?
i don't think stuart thinks of her as a friend.
- what do you mean?
- i mean he's smitten.
he's infatuated. he's bedazzled.
stuart? but he's a baby.
boys start having crushes really young.
frederick, did you have many crushes?
i'm still having one.
so, margalo, can i get you anything else?
whip you up an omelet? pop you a tart?
stuart, i'm full.
full? you eat like a bird.
come on, stuart, time for school.
i'm not going to school.
i'm staying home to take care of margalo.
guess again. you are going to school,
and i'll take care of margalo.
look both ways when you cross the street...
...wear galoshes and, in art class,
don't run with scissors.
i'll get your backpack.
mothers... you know.
- well, i don't really know.
- no?
see, my mom just kind of one day...
...wasn't there anymore.
so you've been completely
on your own all your life?
- you bet.
- i'll bet it's been scary.
no, it's been an adventure.
i wish i had some adventures.
i'm only allowed to paint.
hey, life is an adventure.
just walking out that door is an adventure.
come on, stu. we're late.
go for it, kid.
the adventure begins.
that feels like enough adventure for one day.
hey, look! the yankees won.
there we go.
can you say, "walk with mommy"?
"mommy"?
"walk"?
nothing.
margalo, martha and i are going out for
a bit. can i bring you anything?
no, thanks.
say, "bye-bye, birdie."
say, "bye-bye." martha. say, "bye-bye, birdie."
fresh air.
remember me?
you scared me.
what can i say? i'm a scary guy.
so, margalo, you case the joint?
any valuables? come on, thrill me. chill me.
they ain't got much.
the mom's got a ring, but it's only two carats.
all right, fine.
what else have they got?
well, you know, not that much.
i mean, they mostly just have each other.
a moment while i vomit.
why don't we just try somewhere else?
because you're set up here.
they trust you. they like you.
and maybe...
...you like them.
hey, margalo, come on.
don't con a conman.
nobody else ever invited me to live with them.
oh, really? who found a pitiful orphan bird...
...and plucked her out of the gutter?
who shared his food with her...
... and, i hasten to add,
taught her a trade? who?
- you did.
- i did. right.
well, then, straighten up and fly right.
and remember, you are here on business.
you're not here to play around.
come on, falcon! when i'm on a job,
i never play around!
are you cold?
i guess when the weather gets too cold,
you'll just fly south for the winter?
well, to tell you the truth, i've never flown south.
it's kind of a dream of mine.
get out of this cold, windy city,
catch that jet stream....
fruit trees, millions of new birds to meet.
- i hear it's paradise.
- then how come you haven't gone?
something's always stopping me.
something's always stopping me, too.
everybody around here thinks
i'm too small to accomplish anything.
hey, the way i see it, you're as big as you feel.
yeah. boy, i'm really glad you fell into my car.
i mean, you know... i mean i'm not
glad you fell. i just...
want some more popcorn?
okay.
what?
my pin.
it's fixed. how--
on my way home from school,
i drive right past where you crashed.
it was no big deal.
i mean, there was finding it...
... figuring out how the pieces fit together...
... and you know, fixing it.
and no big deal. just...
oh, scottie.
... one, two, three.
good as new.
no, stuart, it's not.
it's much, much better.
- stay with me.
- all the time.
did you really think i wouldn't find out?
what are you talking about?
i'm talking about you
and your little mouse friend.
big mistake! never make a friend i can eat.
now, get me that ring!
or the mouse is lunch.
- i'll do the dishes.
- you did them last night.
for you, i'd do dishes every night.
that way, i don't have to change the baby.
she just dropped her dolly.
i'll just...
- frederick!
- what?
- my ring. it's gone.
- what do you mean?
it's gone!
- are you absolutely...
- positive.
unless...
i'll call the plumber!
what's going on?
mom's ring went down the drain.
i can't reach it.
hey! what about me?
i can do it. let me go, dad.
- go where?
- down the drain.
i can bring it back up. it's an
adventure.
i don't know. it's awfully dark down there.
and smelly. and cold.
but it's mom's ring. she loves that ring.
come on, dad. let me try.
ok, now, if it gets too cold, or too scary...
... you just tell us.
don't worry, dad. i can handle it.
- or yank on the string, we'll pull you up.
- will do.
how's it so far?
wet. there's a lot of slimy stuff
all over the walls.
- what does it look like?
- like the inside of your nose.
- can you see the bottom yet?
- no, just more pipe.
and everything we ate for dinner last week.
and the pipe seems to go on and on.
well, the plumber said...
what's going on?
is that a new top?
you know, you have such taste.
simple elegance is what i call it.
what's on the other end of that string?
- this string?
- yes.
well, now, don't get excited,
but someone that you and i love...
...has volunteered to go down the drain
to get your ring.
- stuart?
- good guess, mom.
stuart? you let our son go
down the kitchen drain?
now, eleanor, don't be upset.
it's been well thought out. if there's
a problem, i pull on the string and...
now you can be upset.
are you okay? can you hear me?
hurry! i'm slipping.
- get more string.
- great.
there must be string here.
- there is no more.
- what else can we use?
- spaghetti?
- we're out of spaghetti.
- well, do we have macaroni?
- that's too short.
- we can tie it together with...
- no.
hurry!
hang on, stuart!
- margalo, what are you doing?
- stuart, i'm coming! grab on!
lower! lower!
i got it!
- are you all right?
- are you hurt?
don't scare me like that.
margalo, you're the best friend i ever had.
what if someone had accidentally
turned on the garbage disposal?
i would not have let that happen.
- you let him go down the drain.
- he wanted to go.
if martha wanted to go up the chimney...
...or george wanted to go into the toilet,
would you let them?
i love stuart as much as you do.
i just don't happen to be quite as....
emotional? irrational?
what were you going to say?
i forget.
i know i'm overprotective, it's just...
...i can't stand the idea of stuart getting hurt.
i'm sorry, stuart.
what?
you people sure like your meat loaf.
you find the ring?
everything but.
has anyone seen margalo?
i can't find her anywhere.
maybe she just went for a walk
or a little flight around the neighborhood.
sure, you know, to strengthen her wing.
yeah, maybe. but why'd she leave me her pin?
oh, you know, stuart...
...margalo is kind of a free spirit.
maybe she just felt it was time to go.
without even saying goodbye?
what are you doing?
i think i know what happened.
i think that falcon got her.
- yeah?
- i'm going to find her.
and don't try to talk me out of it.
i've made up my mind.
are you crazy? you can't go out there.
because i'm too small? let me tell you
something, george, you're as big as you feel.
all right, then let me come with you.
no, i need you to stay and cover for me.
cover for you? how?
make something up. you're smart.
stuart, she's just a bird.
no, george, she's my friend.
and when you're friends with stuart little,
you're friends for life.
well, if you won't let me come,
at least get somebody to go with you.
snow! snowbell!
the good silverware's in the dining room.
take whatever you want, but don't hurt me.
it's me. stuart.
you. this better be important.
margalo's still missing.
i should've been more specific.
i meant important to me.
i'm going to look for her. i
hoped you'd come with me.
look, stuart, do yourself a favor.
buy a parakeet and forget her.
i can't forget her. she's in terrible
trouble and i have to help her.
i mean what am i, a man or a...
...mouse?
is that a trick question?
come on, it's important. you got to help me.
and why would i do that?
well, because we're family...
...and because i'd do the same for you.
and if you don't, and the littles ask where i'm
gone, george'll tell them you ate me.
what?
why you little rat!
you know something?
everybody thinks you're so nice.
you're not so nice.
come on! it'll be fun. it's an adventure.
hey! mario andretti, slow down.
let's pace ourselves.
i'm gonna have a heart attack.
i think i'm having a thrombosis
and i don't even know what it means.
george! stuart! breakfast!
get it while it's hot.
say, "mama."
say, "dada."
say anything?
'morning, george.
where's stuart?
he already left.
he did? without eating breakfast?
he had to get to school early...
... because he's in a school play.
really?
yes. he plays a mouse. and they
rehearse every morning before school.
why didn't he tell us?
he forgot. you know, being
worried about margalo.
right.
good. this'll keep his mind off it.
got to go.
say, "oatmeal."
oh, boy. this is a sign, stuart.
like the burning bush.
except it's a carburetor and i'm not moses.
but it's telling us something.
let your people go!
- we're not giving up.
- oh, why not?
giving up is fun. and look at
all the time you save.
i'm telling you, if more people gave up,
there'd be fewer wars.
bill.
george.
hi, mom.
hi. where's stuart?
you mean he's not home?
oh, i just remembered. he told me to
tell you that he's rehearsing again.
at will's house. and he's
sleeping over there tonight.
sleepover? on a school night?
hey, that's what he said. got to go.
hello?
hey, will. it's me, george. if my mom
calls, stuart's at your house, okay?
hold on a second.
hello?
will, hi. it's mrs. little. may
i speak with stuart, please?
- stuart?
- you know, my son.
oh, stuart. you mean now?
well, now is when i'm calling.
oh, he just went in the bathroom.
i think he'll be a while. he brought a magazine.
- well, then, is your mother there?
- hold on a second.
- i told her.
- did she buy it?
yeah, but now she wants to speak to my mom.
what will i tell her?
make something up. you're smart.
if i was smart, i wouldn't be in this situation.
she can't come to the phone right now.
she's in the bathroom, too.
but not the same bathroom!
- just let her know i called. thanks.
- okay, mrs. little.
- it's all clear.
- i owe you one.
- now will you tell me what's going on?
- it's too complicated. later.
little hi, little low.
little hey, little ho.
- boys home?
- well, george is.
but stuart is rehearsing his play.
then he's sleeping over at will's house.
- he's going without george?
- i think it'll give him room to grow.
oh, stuart, we've been walking for hours.
i can't take another step.
you know me, i hate to be negative.
but when i walk this much, i chafe.
also, i hate to bring this up...
... but i need to go tinky.
how about the alley?
i'm a house cat. we're fastidious creatures.
we don't just yell, "bomb's away!"
and go wherever we are!
oh, look, let's face it. we'll never find her.
if only we knew someone
who really knew the city.
yeah, someone who knows
the city's disgusting underbelly.
who do i know that's disgusting?
don't threaten me! what i could
tell the health inspector...
... would close you down in a new york minute!
hey, monty!
snowbell! what are you doing here?
- we've been looking all over for you.
- we need your help.
hey, snow, buddy, are you two still friends
or can i eat him?
- no, monty, you can't eat him.
- please.
no! now, pay attention.
what do you know about a bird called falcon?
falcon? oh, that's a bad guy.
you don't want to fool with him.
you know where we can find him?
you don't want to find him.
you don't want anything to do with him.
trust me.
he'd eat you so fast you'd be piled up in poop
before you could yell for help.
falcons are vicious.
they grab you by your neck and carry you
so high, you can't even see the ground.
then they drop you. and by thew time you hit the
pavement, they drink what's left through a straw.
snowbell, are you all right?
oh, yeah. in fact, good news:
i no longer need a litter box.
ha ha ha. mop up on aisle three. silly!
stu, listen. this whole thing
has been a groove and a gas...
... but it's important to know when the fun's over.
you don't want to be that last pathetic person
who leaves a party.
i told you. i'm not giving up.
we're going to find the falcon.
all right, then. it's your funeral.
okay, listen. listen carefully.
the falcon lives across the park...
... at the very tiptop of the pishkin building.
not many people go up there.
and even fewer return.
well, here we are, snowbell. this is it.
- snowbell?
- "salmon, catfish, tuna."
why do they taunt me?
snowbell, how can you think of food
at a time like this? stay on track, will you?
i'm nervous. when i'm nervous, i eat.
because i know in my growling gut that
if anything happens to you, i'll be blamed.
i'm sure they already know we're gone
and plan to replace me with a hamster.
don't worry. george has us covered.
george? george doesn't know
poop from applesauce.
and i say that with a great deal of affection.
- hello, little residence.
- oh, george. i'm glad you answered.
who is it? can you speak louder, please?
george, it's me, stuart.
stuart, where are you? how are you? did you
find her? are you all right? how's snowbell?
when'll you be home? mom and dad
are asking lots of questions.
so are you.
i only have a second. i just want you
to know that we're on the trail...
... and with any luck at all, we'll be
home by dinner time. and, george...
- ...thanks for covering for me.
- sure.
but where are you?
now, listen closely.
we're at the pishkin building.
please deposit $0.35 for the next five minutes.
- snowbell, i need more change.
- what do i look like, a fanny pack?
stuart, stuart, are you still there?
george, is that stuart?
let me think. yeah.
well, where is he? i thought
he was coming home.
he is. later. he and will just
need to rehearse some more.
in fact, i just left him at will's.
hello, mrs. little. is george home?
- will, i found it!
- found what?
- the calculator.
- the calculator?
- will, where's stuart?
- stuart?
it's all right. she knows about the play.
it's supposed to be a surprise.
i had to tell her so she'd know stuart's
at your house. we're going back over there.
oh, yeah. right. it's going to be great.
i just need to get the calculator?
- to figure out how long to rehearse.
- it's a very complicated play.
- come on. let's go.
- see you later, mrs. little.
george, don't forget you two
have a soccer game later.
we'll meet you there!
i can't handle this. i'm too stressed.
all this lying. i've never lied before.
that's why she believes you.
- boy, are we in trouble.
- "we"?
yeah, "we." he didn't spend the night
rehearsing at my house.
what are you planning to do,
mighty mouse, scale the wall?
i'll think of something.
so long, snowbell!
you've got guts, kid.
guts and spunk.
not to mention moxie.
you've got guts, spunk and moxie.
okay. here we go.
all right, falcon. hand her over
and nobody gets hurt.
margalo, uou up here?
is anybody here?
i'm here.
i came for my friend margalo.
if you've hurt her, i'll...
- you'll what?
- tell me right now. is she all right?
why don't you ask her yourself,
whiskers? margalo?
margalo, run!
fly away while i've got him covered.
what are you waiting for?
this kid's priceless. tell me,
cheese-face, does this sound familiar?
"oh, my wing. i don't think i can fly."
what are you talking about?
i can't drill through the wood. she
scammed you. she played you like a harp.
margalo, what does he mean?
okay, now it's getting sad.
maybe this will clear things up.
my mom's ring.
i'm so sorry. i never wanted to hurt you.
but, margalo, why?
don't be upset, mouse-boy.
she has conned smarter than you.
or did you think you were special?
a real friend?
i didn't lie about that, stuart.
you are my friend.
then come with me.
she's not going anywhere.
oh, yes, she is.
was that your best shot?
now, let me show you mine.
don't hurt him, falcon!
i won't hurt him. the sidewalk will!
can't we talk this over?
no! stuart!
let me go! no, falcon! no!
a few days in here should provide you
with an attitude adjustment.
stuart, what have i done?
i'll bet something terrible has happened.
the littles will kill me.
i know, i'll bring home another mouse
in a snazzy outfit...
... teach him to drive a sports car
and pass him off as stuart.
who am i kidding?
i have to get up there. but how?
i hope i live to regret this. ooo!
stuart? yoo-hoo?
stuart? come out, come out wherever you are.
please don't jump out from behind anything.
remember, i have a strong stomach
but a very weak heart.
here, mousie-mousie.
snowbell? is that you? is that really you?
- margalo? where are you?
- in the can.
oh, okay. i'll wait.
no, in the paint can.
why are you in there?
is this some kind of trick?
just get me out.
is stuart in there, too?
no, snowbell, he's dead.
what? stuart is dead?
falcon killed him.
no. he can't be, he's...
i was supposed to protect him.
i wish it was me who had been killed.
really?
no. but i am very unhappy!
oh, dear. i'm dumped on a boat.
i'm on a garbage barge. i got to get off.
hello there!
i'm over here! on the barge! can you hear me?
help!
i'm not supposed to be here!
i need to get off!
help me!
help!
rita, hi. i was in the neighborhood.
i thought i'd pick up the boys.
- george and will?
- george and stuart.
george is here, but i haven't seen stuart.
but he slept over here last night.
no.
george!
what are you going to do now?
which way's canada?
this is terrible.
i just want to go home.
i know a little is supposed
to always see a silver lining.
maybe this means i'm not really a little.
maybe i'm just stuart nobody.
stuart nothing.
there is no silver lining!
oh, no. what have i done?
my plane.
my plane!
the silver lining! this is it!
- all right, george, where is he?
- and this time, the truth.
i'm not sure.
it is never okay to lie to your parents.
is it okay to break a promise to your brother?
it's wrong to promise your brother
that you'll lie to your parents.
listen to the tone of my voice.
tell us where stuart is.
it was a promise. brother to brother.
george, i understand. i have a brother.
but if he was in danger, that would
matter more to me than the promise.
how would we all feel if anything
happened to stuart?
he's at the pishkin building.
- dad.
- what?
- am i in trouble?
- no, son. you're in big trouble.
- mom, dad, i'm really sorry.
- you should be.
for all we know, stuart could be out there now,
lying face down with his...
or, he could be fine.
we don't have to assume the worst.
after all, it's not the little way.
yes, you're right. he could be puttering home
right now in his shiny little car.
smiling and happy.
his whiskers fluttering in the breeze.
- mom.
- yes, george.
i don't think he's puttering home.
who would do this?
tiny little vandals.
that miserable falcon!
from this day forward, i vow revenge.
if that falcon were here right now,
i'd rip his throat out.
i'd scratch his face off. i'd...
snowbell, that's him.
don't hurt me.
kill the bird, not me.
i'm going to be falcon poop.
well, well, well. the canary is out of her cage.
and how nice. she's brought
a friend for dinner.
too bad i don't like canned food.
snowbell, get out!
can't. stuck. too fat!
don't do it, falcon. or else!
do what? what's he doing?
or else what?
or else you'll lose this.
put that down, margalo.
i'm through doing what you tell me to do.
i'm leaving you, falcon, forever.
oh, and what do you think you'll be without me?
free.
big mistake. i'll be back for you, fur-ball.
don't hurry!
- stuart! you're alive!
- so far!
where'd you get the plane?
a garbage dump.
sorry i asked.
- i hope we're not too late.
- keep your eyes peeled. he could be anywhere.
careful now. one step at a time.
that's it. you're going to make it. yeah!
i'm alive. i'm alive.
stuart! is that you? take me with you!
what about me? how will i get down from here?
i think this is it. turn here.
okey-dokey. no problem.
hey, look! it's stuart.
stop the car!
stuart!
look at that bird. he's bigger than me.
we got to save him. come on.
it's the littles. i'm saved!
wait! it's me!
follow that flying mouse.
- no problem.
- hey-little, ho-little...
... hoo-little, hey-hottle, ho-wottle, wo-wittle.
there he is!
if we get out of this,
i'm sticking to painting and dancing.
hey, lady! get out of the way!
he's closing in.
oh, my goodness.
keep it running.
okey-dokey. no problem.
- stuart!
- he can't hear you.
i think we lost him.
going up?
frederick, i feel so helpless.
a mouse needs to know his limitations.
stuart! pull up!
i can't! it's stuck!
well, try harder!
margalo! get out! save yourself!
no, stuart! if we go, we go together!
stuart! pull up!
- pull up, stuart!
- stuart, pull up!
you should've stayed
in your little hole, mouse-boy.
stuart, we can't outrun him.
then we'll just have to face him.
it's too dangerous. i won't let you do it.
but i have to try. i'll be back for you later.
what do you mean?
stuart! don't do it!
party's over, fur-face.
what's he doing?
they will crash!
stuart! turn! run away!
bye-bye, birdbrain!
oh, dear.
got you.
can't i get a decent meal in this city?
thank you.
stuart! are you okay?
i am now. margalo saved me.
we saved each other.
what did you think you were doing?
- you almost gave me a heart attack.
- i'm sorry, mom.
- you ran away from home.
- i know.
and you had george lie to us.
yeah.
then why am i so proud of you?
mrs. little, this belongs to you.
my ring.
yeah, i took it.
and now she's giving it back.
i'm just happy to have all of you back.
snowbell!
you made it.
thank goodness you're all right.
snowbell, where have you been?
you wouldn't believe what stuart
and margalo have been through.
snowbell, you should have seen it.
these two were so brave.
let's go home.
and how about me? i played no part in this?
well, i have had enough!
i'm staying right here, folks!
oh, yeah. you'll never see me again!
snow, want some tuna when we get home?
tuna? i love these people.
wait! wait for me!
i guess they're flying south for the winter?
i guess.
you've always dreamed of going, haven't you?
but falcon never let you.
every year i'd just watch all the other birds go.
the ones who were free.
you're free.
stuart, we'd be so far apart.
it wouldn't change a thing.
well....
- you're sure of the way? we can call aaa.
- we can get you maps, discount coupons.
there's a place in south carolina
where they do the best pecan pie.
i'm a bird. instinct should take over.
i guess you've been waiting for this a long time.
all my life. only...
only what, dear?
well, now it's not just talk.
now, it's the real thing.
are you scared?
the world's pretty big, and i'm pretty small.
somebody once told me,
"you're as big as you feel."
just spread your wings...
... and soar.
i'll miss you, stuart.
i'll miss you, too.
i'll miss all of you.
you, too, snowbell.
i'm not going to cry.
little hi, little low.
little hey, little ho.
stuart?
yeah, dad?
what's the silver lining this time?
she'll be back in the spring.
bye-bye, birdie.
- did you hear that?
- her first words! she spoke!
- of course she did.
- i knew she could do it.
big deal. when she can fall from a tree
and land on her feet, then i'll be impressed.
