<i>my name's ralph,</i>
<i>and i'm a bad guy.</i>
<i>let's see. i'm nine feet tall.</i>
<i>i weigh 643 pounds,</i>
<i>got a bit of a temper on me.</i>
<i>hey, you moved my stump!</i>
<i>my passion level's
very near the surface,</i>
<i>i guess, not gonna lie.</i>
<i>anyhoo, what else, uh...</i>
<i>i'm a wrecker. i wreck thing.</i>
<i>professionally.</i>
<i>i'm gonna wreck it!</i>
<i>i'm very good at what i do.</i>
<i>probably the best i know.</i>
<i>the thing is, fixing</i>
<i>is the name of the game.</i>
<i>literally, fix-it felix, jr.</i>
<i>fix-it, felix!</i>
<i>i can fix it!</i>
<i>so, yeah, naturally,</i>
<i>the guy with the name</i>
<i>fix-it felix is the good guy.</i>
<i>he's nice enough</i>
<i>as good guys go.</i>
<i>definitely fixes</i>
<i>stuff really well.</i>
<i>but, if you've</i>
<i>got a magic hammer</i>
<i>from your father,</i>
<i>how hard can it be?</i>
<i>if he was a regular contractor</i>
<i>carpenter guy,</i>
<i>i guarantee you,</i>
<i>you would not be able</i>
<i>to fix the damage</i>
<i>that i do as quickly.</i>
<i>and when felix does</i>
<i>a good job, he gets a medal.</i>
<i>but are there medals for</i>
<i>wrecking stuff really well?</i>
<i>to that i say, "ha!"</i>
<i>and, no, there aren't.</i>
<i>thirty years i've</i>
<i>been doing this.</i>
<i>and i've seen a lot of other</i>
<i>games come and go.</i>
<i>how sad.
think about those guys at asteroids?.</i>
<i>boom! gone.</i> centipede?
<i>who knows where</i>
<i>that guy is, you know?</i>
<i>look, a steady arcade gig</i>
<i>is nothing to sneeze at.</i>
<i>i'm very lucky.</i>
<i>it's just, i gotta say,</i>
<i>it becomes kinda hard</i>
<i>to love your job...</i>
<i>when no one else seems to like you for doing it.</i>
all clear!
the arcade is closed!
shoryuken!
whoo! what a day! so, you want
to head to tapper's, ken?
if you're buying, buddy.
quitting time!
<i>i don't know.</i>
<i>maybe i wouldn't be</i>
<i>feeling this way.</i>
<i>if things were</i>
<i>different after work.</i>
<i>but it is what it is.</i>
good job, everyone!
<i>felix and the nicelanders</i>
<i>go hang out in their homes,</i>
<i>which he's just fixed.</i>
<i>and everyone, you know,</i>
<i>they go to their homes,</i>
<i>i go to mine,</i>
<i>which happens to be a dump.</i>
<i>and when i say "a dump".</i>
<i>i don't mean like</i>
<i>a shabby place.</i>
<i>i mean an actual dump,</i>
<i>where the garbage goes,</i>
<i>and a bunch of bricks</i>
<i>and smashed building parts.</i>
<i>that's what i call home.</i>
<i>i guess i can't</i>
<i>bellyache too much.</i>
<i>i got my bricks,</i>
<i>i got my stump.</i>
<i>it looks uncomfortable.</i>
<i>it's actually fine. i'm good.</i>
<i>but if i'm really</i>
<i>honest with myself...</i>
<i>i see felix up there</i>
<i>getting patted on the back,</i>
<i>people are giving him pie</i>
<i>and thanking him.</i>
<i>and so happy</i>
<i>to see him all the time.</i>
sometimes i think...
man, it sure must be nice
being the good guy.
nice share, ralph.
as fellow bad guys,
we've all felt
what you're feeling.
and we've come
to terms with it.
- really?
- right here.
i am zangief. i am bad guy.
- hi, zangief!
- hi, zangief.
i relate to you, ralph.
when i hit bottom,
i was crushing man's skull
like sparrow egg
between my thighs.
and i think, "why do you have
to be so bad, zangief?"
"why can't you be
more like good guy?"
then i have moment of clarity.
if zangief is good guy,
who'll crush man's skull
like sparrow's egg
between thighs?
and i say, "zangief,
you are bad guy",
"but this does not mean
you are 'bad' guy."
right. i'm sorry.
you lost me there.
- zombie! bad guy!
- hi, zombie.
hi, zombie.
zangief saying
labels not make you happy.
good! bad!
you must love you.
yeah! inside here! yes.
okay. all right, i get you.
watch out. it's dripping.
question, ralph.
we've been asking you
to bad-anon for years now.
and tonight you
finally show up.
- why is that?
- i don't know.
i just felt like coming.
i mean, i suppose it has something
to do with the fact that...
well, today is the 30th
anniversary of my game.
well, happy anniversary, ralph.
thanks, satan.
it's sateen, actually.
got it. but here's the thing.
i don't want to be
the bad guy anymore.
you can't mess with
the program, ralph.
you're not going turbo,
are you?
turbo? no, i'm not going
turbo! come on, guys!
is it turbo to want a friend?
or a medal?
or a piece of pie
every once in a while?
is it turbo to want
more out of life?
yes!
ralph, ralph, we get it.
but we can't change who we are.
and the sooner you accept that,
the better off your game
and your life will be.
hey. one game at a time, ralph.
now let's close out with
the bad guy affirmation.
i'm bad, and that's good.
i will never be good,
and that's not bad.
there's no one
i'd rather be than me.
okay, gang, see you next week.
listen, i can't do
snacks next week.
hang in there, ralph.
hey, zombie,
don't forget your hatchets.
there you go.
step aside, sir.
random security check.
random my behind!
you always stop me.
i'm just a surge protector
doing my job, sir.
- name?
- lara croft.
- name?
- wreck-it ralph!
and where are you coming from?
<i>pac-man</i>.
did you bring
any fruit with you?
no! no. no fruit.
okay, then.
where are you heading?
<i>fix-it felix, jr.</i>
- anything to declare?
- i hate you.
i get that a lot. proceed.
bad guy coming!
<i>if you leave your game,</i>
<i>stay safe, stay alert,</i>
<i>and whatever you do, don't die.</i>
<i>because if you die</i>
<i>outside your own game,</i>
<i>you don't regenerate.</i>
<i>ever. game ove.</i>
here you go, buddy.
it's fresh.
straight from pac-man's.
hang in there, guys.
name?
"happy 30th anniversary"?
they're having
a party without me.
pac-man? they invited pac-man?
that cherry-chasing dot-muncher
isn't even part of this game!
great party, felix.
why, thank you, friend.
felix. you're needed on
the dance floor!
whoo!
fix-it felix!
whoo-whoo! fix-it felix!
i'll bet that's mario.
fashionably late, per the norm.
i'll get it, felix.
it's ralph!
he'll wreck the party!
hide the stemware!
get rid of him, felix.
oh, right. i'll go talk to him.
carry on, everyone.
ralph, can i help you?
hey, felix.
just wanted to check on you.
i saw a big explosion
or something go
over the building there.
those were just fireworks.
fireworks. okay. phewf.
somebody's birthday, or...
well, it's more
of an anniversary.
the 30th anniversary
of our game, actually.
what? is that today?
i know!
i'm such a dummy with dates.
anyway, congratulations.
thank you, ralph.
and to you, too.
hi. just a heads-up, felix.
they're bringing out the cake
in a few shakes.
- hey, glen.
- ralph.
cake? heard about this cake stuff.
never had it.
no one ever seems to throw it out.
so it never ends up in the dump.
i never actually tasted it.
i've always wanted to try cake.
i don't suppose you'd like to
come in and have a slice, would you?
hey-o, everybody!
i'm okay. i'm okay.
fit as a fiddle.
now, you all know ralph.
evening.
evening, nell, lucy,
don, dana...
- deanna.
- big gene!
why is he here?
he's just here
for a slice of cake.
and i'm a big part of the game,
technically speaking.
why are you here, gene?
oh look! the cake!
well, i'll be dipped.
you've really outdone yourself, mary.
oh, and look!
there's all of us at the top.
each apartment is
everyone's favorite flavor.
norwood's is red velvet.
guilty!
and lemon for lucy,
rum cake for gene,
- and for felix...
- hey, mary.
um...
what's the flavor of that mud
that i'm stuck in there?
chocolate.
i've never been
real fond of chocolate.
well, i did not know that.
one other little thing.
i hate to be picky, but
this angry little guy here...
- my cake!
- ...might be a lot happier
if you put him up here
with everyone else.
see that? look at that smile.
no, no. you see, ralph,
there's no room
for you up here.
what about this?
we can make room.
here. we could
take turns. easy.
how about we just eat the cake?
hang on. felix needs
to be on the roof.
because he's about
to get his medal!
then how about we just
take that medal.
and give it to ralph for once?
would that be the
end of the world, gene?
now you're just
being ridiculous.
only good guys win medals,
and you, sir, are no good guy.
i could be a good guy
if i wanted to,
and i could win a medal!
and when you do,
come and talk to us.
and then would you finally let me be
on top of the cake with you guys?
if you won a medal,
we'd let you live
up here in the penthouse!
but it will never happen.
because you're just the bad guy
who wrecks the building.
no, i'm not.
yes, you are!
no, i'm not!
yes, you are.
all right, gene. you know what?
i'm gonna win a medal.
i am gonna win a medal!
the shiniest medal
this place has ever seen!
a medal that will be so good
that it will make felix's
medals wet their pants!
and good night!
thank you for the party.
- is he serious?
- oh please!
where's a bad guy
going to win a medal?
of course he's not serious.
i've never been more serious
about anything in my life.
that's why i came
straight here, tapper.
you've never given me a bum steer.
now, come on. where can a guy
like me go and win a medal?
i don't think such
a game exists, ralph.
come on. you know people.
there's got to be...
tapper, i need a root beer.
coming! hold that thought.
okay. as you were saying.
i was saying, i can't spend another 30 years
living alone in the garbage.
i'm not going back
without a medal.
well, i don't know
what to tell you.
maybe somebody
left a medal here.
you're welcome to dig
through the lost and found.
okay, let's see
what we got here.
shoo! shoo!
go on, get out of here.
mushroom? no.
what is this? no.
come on, zangief! gross.
what am i doing?
- hey, excuse you!
- we are humanity's last hope.
our mission?
destroy all cy-bugs.
we are humanity's last hope.
you okay there, space cadet?
we've only been
plugged in a week.
and every day it's,
"climb the building, then fight bugs."
"climb the building, fight more bugs!"
yeah, yeah. right. look.
easy on the overalls, spaceman.
it's tough all over, all right?
and all for what?
a lousy medal?
medal? you win a medal?
yeah, medal of heroes.
ooh. is it shiny?
pretty shiny.
ooh! and it says "hero" on it?
uh-huh.
and you say you win it
by climbing a building?
- and fighting bugs!
- right, bugs.
listen. is there any chance
i could go with you to your game
and you know, maybe get one of those medals?
- negatory.
- does that mean maybe?
no! look, only the bravest
and the best serve in our corps.
bug!
we are humanity's last hope.
<i>attention. the arcade will open</i>
<i>in five minutes.</i>
<i>please report to your games.</i>
i can't feel my legs.
what is all this stuff?
smells like ralph in here.
okay. all right.
what was it called again?
hero's something.
<i>duty. hero's duty.</i>
there it is.
sorry, q*bert. it's me, ralph.
shh!
the wall.
morning, kids. come on in.
good to see you. good to see you.
you, too, little fella.
<i>quarter alert! quarter alert!</i>
<i>this is not a drill.</i>
ooh! sweet golden medal!
<i>on a planet with no name,</i>
<i>a top-secret experiment</i>
<i>has gone horribly wrong.</i>
<i>you are humanity's last hope.</i>
rooting-tooting, ready for
shooting!
all right.
now listen up, because i'm
only going to say this once.
fear is
a four-letter word, ladies.
if you want to go pee-pee
in your big-boy slacks,
keep it to yourself.
it's make your mamas proud time!
i love my mama!
heads up! first-person shooter,
coming through!
ooh, robot!
boop, boop, boop.
<i>game play in three,</i>
<i>two, one.</i>
<i>we are humanity's last hope.</i>
<i>our mission?</i>
destroy all cy-bugs.
you ready, rookie?
let's find out.
sweet mother hubbard!
no, no, no! wait a second! aah!
cy-bug, twelve o'clock.
take it, newbie.
no, no! wait, wait!
watch it, rookie!
these monsters become what they eat.
my gun! give me that back.
shoot the eggs
before they hatch!
no!
something's coming
out of their bottom!
<i>- gross!
- markowski!</i>
<i>get back in formation!</i>
<i>all right, ladies,</i>
<i>the kitten whispers</i>
<i>and tickle fights stop now.</i>
the entrance to the lab
is straight ahead.
- i'll meet you guys inside!
- no!
sanctuary! sanctuary!
i thought this was going
to be like <i>centipede!</i>
when did video games
become so violent and scary?
<i>please, get me out of here!</i>
take her!
<i>game over.</i>
what a rip-off!
get off me!
it's game over. stop it!
beacon up!
cease fire! cease fire!
<i>attention!</i>
<i>return to start position.</i>
<i>return to start position.</i>
here, let me help you.
sorry about that.
yeah, you must be upset.
- markowski.
- who?
whoa! yeah, me. i'm markowski.
what's the first rule
of <i>hero's duty?</i>
no cuts, no butts, no coconuts?
never interfere with
the first-person shooter.
our job is to get the gamers
to the top of that building.
so they can get a medal,
and that's it!
so stick to the program,
soldier!
right. right. aye, aye.
<i>quarter alert! quarter alert!</i>
all right, pussy willows.
back to start positions!
yeah, right. no way i'm going
through that again.
so that's where they
keep the medal huh?
new racers daily.
sweet! i got next game.
go away, kid!
- we're going to play all nine of today's racers!
- yeah!
sorry.
where's the wrecking guy?
where's ralph?
he should be wrecking the building.
shh! stick with the program.
<i>fix-it, felix!</i>
<i>i can fix it!</i>
ralph! quarter alert! game on!
do something, felix!
just act natural. i'll fix it.
ralph! ralph!
what the...
ralph? ralph!
oh my land! where is he?
mr. litwak!
what's the trouble, sweetheart?
the game's busted.
<i>i can fix it! i can fix it!</i>
oh boy.
looks like the game's
gone cuckoo, like my nana.
sorry, sweetie.
here's your quarter back.
but what about the game?
i'll have someone
look at it tomorrow...
but if he can't fix it,
it might be time
to put old ralph
and felix out to pasture.
like my nana.
ladies and gentlemen,
we're out of order.
sweet mercy!
without ralph, we're doomed!
they're going to pull our plug!
okay, everybody, calm down.
ralph probably fell asleep
in the washroom of tapper's again.
see? there he is now.
why, it's q*bert.
what brings you here, neighbor?
what's he saying, felix?
stand by. my q*bert-ese
is a little rusty.
ralph's gone turbo!
ooh!
shiny.
<i>attention!</i>
<i>the arcade is now closed.</i>
did you get
a load of markowski?
shut your chew holes.
cy-bug.
taste it!
slick tiddlywinking, pint-size.
i'm fix-it felix, jr., ma'am.
from the game <i>fix-it felix, jr.</i>
jiminey jaminey!
look at that high definition.
your face!
it's amazing!
flattery don't charge
these batteries, civilian.
now, state your business.
i'm looking for my
colleague, wreck-it ralph?
never heard of him.
well, q*bert saw him
come in here.
impossible.
nothing gets past me.
that came from the tower.
nice eggs. nice eggs!
okay. that was easy.
<i>congratulations, soldier.</i>
<i>it is my honor to</i>
<i>bestow upon you</i>
<i>the medal of heroes.</i>
wow!
no way!
<i>ten-hut!</i>
wow!
<i>history will long revere</i>
<i>your courage and sacrifice.</i>
well, thank you!
<i>you have etched</i>
<i>in the rock of virtue.</i>
<i>a legacy beyond compare.</i>
thanks, guys. at ease!
<i>you are the universe's</i>
<i>greatest hero.</i>
oops!
<i>the living embodiment of</i>
<i>all this corps represent.</i>
<i>bravery. integrity.</i>
<i>grace under pressure.</i>
<i>and above all, dignity.</i>
<i>escape pod activated.</i>
get off my face!
incoming!
- ralph!
- cy-bug!
a-ha!
no!
<i>sayonara</i>, sucker!
"sugar rush"?
no!
this is that candy go-kart game
over by the whack-a-mole.
i gotta get out of here.
oh no! my medal!
no, no, no, no, my medal!
no, no, my medal!
hi, mister.
hello.
man, you scared me, kid.
i nearly soiled myself.
what's your name?
ralph. wreck-it ralph.
you're not from here, are you?
no, well, yeah. i mean,
i mean not from right in this area.
i'm just doing some work here.
what kind of work?
some routine
candy tree trimming.
you probably
want to stand back.
in fact, this whole area
is technically closed
while we're trimming.
- who's "we"?
- candy tree department.
where is everybody else?
it's just me today.
so you just meant
like the royal "we"?
yep. that's right.
hey, are you a hobo?
no. i'm not a hobo,
but i am busy.
okay? so you go home.
what's that? didn't hear you.
your breath is so bad
it made my ears numb.
listen, i tried to be nice.
i tried to be nice.
- you're mimicking me.
- you're mimicking me!
- okay.
- okay.
that is rude,
and this conversation is over.
and this conversation is over.
i wouldn't grab that
branch if i were you.
i'm from the candy tree
department, so i know what...
it's a double stripe.
double stripes break. guh-doy!
why are your hands
so freakishly big?
i don't know. why are you
so freakishly annoying?
why are you so freakishly...
sweet mother of monkey milk!
a gold coin!
don't even think about it.
that is mine.
race you for it! hey!
i don't have to race for it
because it's mine!
double stripe! come back here!
the winner!
give it back! give it!
whoa!
double stripe.
thank you!
wait! let me talk to you
for one second.
okay. here's the thing.
i'm not from
the candy tree department.
lying to a child.
shame on you, ralph.
but i wasn't lying about
the medal. that is my medal!
that's why i was climbing
the tree. it's mine!
it's precious to me.
that thing is my ticket
to a better life.
yeah, well, now it's my ticket.
- what the...
- see you, chump!
come back! i'll find you!
i will find you!
double stripe!
nowhere to hide!
yeah, he banged around in here
like some kind of hot shot,
then he went barreling down
into that sweet little game
like a crazy person.
<i>"sugar rush"</i>
cy-bugs would chew up that game
faster than a chicken hawk in
a coop of crippled roosters.
- what was that, now?
- what are you, thick?
there was a cy-bug
on that shuttle!
do you even know
what a cy-bug is?
i can't say that i do, ma'am.
cy-bugs are like a virus.
they don't know
they're in the game.
all they know is eat,
kill, multiply.
without a beacon to stop them,
they'll consume <i>sugar rush.</i>
but do you think
they'll stop there?
- yes!
- wrong!
viruses do not stop!
once those cy-bugs
finish off <i>sugar rush</i>,
they'll invade every other
game until this arcade
is nothing but a smoking husk
of forgotten dreams.
kohut! my cruiser.
jeepers. is she
always this intense?
it's not her fault.
she's programmed with the most
tragic back-story ever.
the one day she didn't do
a perimeter check...
<i>her wedding day.</i>
wait, ma'am!
i'm going with you.
like fun you are, short stack.
you die outside your game,
you don't regenerate.
well, neither do you, ma'am.
and it is my job to fix
what ralph wrecks.
and i cannot ask you
to risk your life
cleaning up his mess.
no flex on this one, ma'am.
i am coming along with you.
<i>citizens of sugar rush...</i>
just in time.
<i>all hail our</i>
<i>rightful ruler, king candy.</i>
<i>hello, my royal subjects!</i>
<i>ha-ha! have some candy!</i>
<i>thank you for that stirring</i>
<i>introduction, sour bill.</i>
<i>and thank you to</i>
<i>today's avatars.</i>
<i>it was a wonderful</i>
<i>day of racing. it was.</i>
<i>but now the arcade is closed,</i>
<i>so it's time to</i>
<i>wipe the slate clean.</i>
<i>and race to decide</i>
<i>our new roster.</i>
<i>the first nine racers</i>
<i>across that finish line</i>
<i>will represent sugar rush</i>
<i>as tomorrow's avatars!</i>
race! race! race!
<i>yes. okay, calm down.</i>
<i>listen! this event is</i>
<i>pay-to-play. we all know this.</i>
<i>the fee to compete</i>
<i>is one gold coin</i>
<i>from your previous winnings,</i>
<i>if you've ever won,</i>
<i>which i have.</i>
<i>let me go first!</i>
<i>king candy!</i>
<i>taffyta muttonfudge!</i>
stay sweet!
<i>adorabeezle winterpop!</i>
<i>gloyd orangeboar!</i>
little stealer!
wait till i catch that brat.
<i>minty zaki. snowanna rainbeau.</i>
<i>rancis fluggerbutter.</i>
<i>jubileena bing-bing.</i>
<i>swizzle malarkey.</i>
<i>candlehead.</i>
sour bill, who's that last one?
<i>vanellope von schweetz!</i>
yippee! i'm in the race!
<i>vanellope?</i>
the glitch!
<i>now, now!</i>
<i>everything is all right!</i>
<i>security!</i>
come here, kid!
we're not going to hurt you,
you little freak!
get back here!
slow down!
slow down a little bit.
you! give me back
my medal right now!
- oh boy!
- go!
<i>what is that?</i>
come on! go! roll!
<i>careful! what are you doing?</i>
come back here!
i can't move!
now we got him!
oh good, the cops.
she went that way!
hold still! take that!
what are you doing?
<i>okay, folks.</i>
<i>calm down!</i>
<i>everything's all right.</i>
<i>the monster's been caught!</i>
<i>we'll repair all the damage.</i>
<i>don't worry. we will have our race
before the arcade open.</i>
and i'm in it. yes!
there's no way that i am
racing with a glitch.
rancis, candlehead, come on.
sour bill, that glitch
cannot be allowed to race!
and bring that thing
to my castle.
guys! she took...
♪ o-re-o, oreee-o ♪
sour bill,
de-taffify this monster
so we can see what
we're up against here.
kay.
milk my duds!
it's wreck-it ralph?
yeah. who are you,
the guy that makes the donuts?
please. no. i'm king candy!
i see you're a fan of pink.
salmon. salmon,
that's obviously sal...
what are you doing here?
look, your candiness, this is
just a big misunderstanding.
just get me
out of this cupcake,
i'll get my medal,
and i'll be out of your way.
your medal?
bad guys don't win medals.
well, this one did.
i earned it
over in <i>hero's duty</i>.
you game-jumped?
ralph, you're not
going turbo, are you?
what? no, no.
because if you think you can
come in here to my kingdom
and take over my game, you've
got another thing coming!
easy, your puffiness.
it's not my fault
one of your children
of the candy corn
stole my medal.
"children of the candy corn"?
who'd...
the glitch!
the coin she used to buy
her way into the race.
that was your medal?
she did what? i need that back!
well, i'm afraid i can't
help you. it's gone, you know.
it's nothing but code now.
it will stay that way until
someone wins the cup
at the end of the race.
maybe i'll have
to have a little talk
with the winner then.
is that a threat i smell?
beyond the halitosis you
so obviously suffer from.
listen, nilly-wafer, i'm not
leaving without my medal!
yes, you are.
wynchel, duncan,
get him out of that cupcake
and on the first train back home.
and if i ever see you here again,
wreck-it ralph,
i'll lock you in my fungeon.
fungeon?
fun dungeon, you know?
it's a play on words.
it's the...
never mind! now i've got a glitch
to deal with, thanks to you.
goodbye, wreck-it ralph!
it hasn't been a pleasure.
this thing is hard as a rock.
i can see that.
- get the tools.
- what tools?
quiet, you!
what? no!
- take it easy, big boy!
- stay away from me!
he's getting away!
quick! call out the devil dogs.
chocolate. i hate chocolate!
i gotta get my medal back.
the pot goes to
the winning racer!
hey, kids! can i talk
to you for a second?
hello, fellow racers!
it's that little
crumb snatcher.
candlehead, taffyta,
rancis, you're looking well.
came by to check out the competition, huh?
well, here it is,
the lickity split!
sheesh. looks like
she built it herself.
i built it myself.
fastest pedal-power,
west of the whac-a-mole.
check her out.
oh vanellope, it's so... you.
but you have to back
out of the race. yeah.
oh no, i don't,
because i paid my fee
and i'm on the board...
so, yeah,
i'm definitely racing.
yeah, well, king candy says
glitches can't race.
i'm not a glitch, taffyta.
i've just got pixslexia, okay?
the rules are there for a reason, vanellope.
to protect us. say i'm you.
i'm in my weird little car
and i'm driving.
and i actually feel
kind of cool for once.
and then, all of a sudden, oh no.
i'm glitching!
- hey!
- see?
you're an accident
just waiting to happen.
oh no! i glitched, too!
uncool.
stop it! stop!
you're breaking it!
please!
i just want to
race like you guys.
you will never be a racer
because you're a glitch.
and that's all you'll ever be!
hey! leave her alone!
let's get out of here!
scram,
you rotten little cavities!
before i throw you in the mud!
what are you looking at?
you're welcome,
you rotten little thief.
i'm not a thief!
i just borrowed your stupid coin.
i was going to give it back to
you as soon as i won the race.
it's not a coin. it is a medal.
coin, medal, whatever.
just go back to your own dumb
game and win another one.
i can't. i didn't win it
in my game.
i won it in <i>hero's duty.</i>
<i>hero's doodie?</i>
it's not that kind of duty.
i bet you really got to watch
where you step
in a game called <i>hero's doodie!</i>
what did you win
the medal for, wiping?
i hope you washed your hands
after you handled that medal.
- listen!
- one more, one more.
why did the hero
flush the toilet?
- say "why"?
- why?
because it was his doodie!
how dare you insult
<i>hero's duty?</i>
you little guttersnipe!
i earned that medal.
you better get it back
for me toot-sweet, sister!
well, unless you've got
a go-kart
hidden in the fat folds
of your neck,
i can't help you!
what a moron.
hey, genius! it's a jawbreaker.
you're never going to break...
enjoy your little tantrum,
diaper baby?
leave me alone.
look, you want that medal,
right? and i want to race.
so here's what i'm thinking.
you help me get a new kart...
a real kart...
and i'll win the race
and get you back your medal.
you want me to help you?
all you gotta do is
break something for me.
come on.
what do you say, friend?
we are not friends.
come on, pal. you son of a gun.
come on, buddy.
let's shake on it.
come on, chumbo.
ralph, my man. my main man.
hey!
my arm's getting tired.
do we have a deal or not?
you better win.
well, i'll say this much,
they don't call your friend
"wreck-it" for nothing.
there's the shuttle.
is he in there?
nope. lucky for him.
otherwise i would have
slapped his corpse.
no cy-bug, either.
gotta find it before
it lays its filthy eggs.
it came this way,
but the sugar particles
in the atmosphere
are jamming my sensor.
can't get a read on it.
so what is it with this
wreck-it joker?
why did he go awol?
i wish i knew, ma'am.
he was acting
all squirrelly last night...
going on about
cake and medals...
but i never thought
he'd go turbo.
"go turbo"?
that's right, you guys
just got plugged in.
well, back when the arcade
first opened,
turbotime <i>was by far</i>
<i>the most popular game.</i>
<i>and turbo... turbo-tastic!</i>
<i>- he loved the attention.</i>
<i>- turbo-tastic!</i>
<i>so, when </i>roadblasters
<i>got plugged in</i>
<i>and stole turbo's thunder...</i>
new game. all right!
<i>boy, was he jealous.</i>
<i>so jealous that he</i>
<i>abandoned his game</i>
<i>and tried to take</i>
<i>over the new one.</i>
these are the greatest graphics
i've ever seen!
<i>turbo-tastic!</i>
- hey. is that...
- that looks like turbo.
what's turbo doing
in this game? aw, come on!
mr. litwak!
<i>turbo ended up putting</i>
<i>both games and himself</i>
<i>out of order, for good.</i>
yes, the selfish man
is like a mangy dog
chasing a cautionary tale.
i know, right?
that's why i have
to get ralph home.
or the same thing's gonna
happen to my game.
what is this?
- "nesquik-sand"?
- quicksand?
i'll hop out and grab you
one of those vines.
i can't hop. i'm hop-less.
this is hopeless!
we're going to drown here.
stop thrashing. stop moving.
you're making us sink faster.
we're going to die!
get a hold of yourself!
the vines. they're laffy taffy.
they're attracted to whatever
makes them laugh.
here, hit me again.
that's not funny enough.
harder!
look, you're a nice guy.
i can't...
no, ma'am! the arcade
is depending on us.
now do your duty.
that's an ord...
it's working! hit me again.
ooh, your eye.
i can fix it. now...
san fran-tastic! again!
you mean business!
yikes on bikes!
wow! we're... killing... them!
comedy gold!
all right, enough with
the goo-goo eyes.
we've got work to do. let's go.
we lost the cy-bug.
come on. we'll get
a better view from the air.
you think you can
fix that shuttle?
can do.
shh!
all right, do your thing,
knuckles. bust it open!
what's this? you're a full-on
criminal, aren't you?
hey, we shook on it.
thank you, jeeves.
what is this place?
where are the karts?
you gotta make one.
what? no, no.
look, kid, bad idea. trust me.
i don't make things.
i break things.
well, it looks like you're
going to be stepping outside
your comfort zone, then, gladys.
ooh, this is a good one!
<i>welcome to the bakery!
let's bake a kart!</i>
what is this, another game?
yeah, well, it's a mini-game.
<i>you have one minute to win it.</i>
what? come on, ralph!
<i>go! mixing.</i>
<i>put the ingredients in the bowl.</i>
<i>and throw away the trash.</i>
hairbrush. no!
underpants. no, no!
you're getting
all the wrong stuff, kid.
i'm trying!
let me up there.
i'll do it. no. yes.
gross. milk. yes, yes, yes.
<i>batter up!</i>
come on!
no sleeping on the job!
<i>baking! pump up the heat</i>
<i>and hold the perfect temperature.</i>
ralph, a little help here?
i'm on it.
yeah, no problem.
give me this thing here.
okay, good. little more.
yeah, that's it!
hold it, hold it, hold it.
yes! come on. get up, ralph!
fifteen seconds!
<i>decorating! wheels first.</i>
- how many?
- four, doy!
got it.
now frosting.
a buttload of frosting!
no problem.
<i>time's up! congratulations.</i>
<i>you did it, and here's your kart!</i>
look, kid...
i tried to warn you.
i can't make things.
i just break...
i love it.
you do?
i love it.
i love it!
i love it! i love it!
look, it's got a real engine!
and look at these wheels.
i love it!
i finally have a real kart!
come on. a work of art
like this must be signed.
cream puffs.
this is beard papa.
the glitch is in the bakery!
get me king candy!
what? you have teeth?
i don't think i've ever
seen you smile before.
i'm not smiling. i was...
i'm gassy, okay?
hold it right there, glitch!
and wreck-it ralph?
start the kart! start the kart!
what are you waiting for?
come on. let's go!
i don't know how to
drive a real kart.
you don't what?
are you hurt, sire?
no, he just glazed me.
get them!
gangway!
stop, in the name of the king!
that's me!
get off the road!
head for diet cola mountain!
- drive into the wall!
- what?
right there, between the two
sugar-free lollipops!
- are you crazy?
- just do it!
where did they go?
they should have just turned.
find that glitch!
destroy that kart!
she can't be allowed to race!
so let me get this straight.
you don't know how to drive.
well, no, not technically.
- i just thought that...
- what did you think?
"i'll just magically
win the race"
"just because
i really want to!"
look, wise guy.
i know i'm a racer.
i can feel it in my code.
that's it! i'm never
getting my medal back.
what is the big whoop about
that crummy medal anyway?
the big whoop?
well, this may come as a shock
to you, but in my game,
i'm the bad guy
and i live in the garbage.
- cool.
- no. not cool.
unhygienic and lonely
and boring.
and that crummy medal
was going to change all that.
i go home with that baby
around my neck
and i'll get a penthouse. pies.
ice sculptures. fireworks!
it's grown-up stuff.
you wouldn't understand.
no, i get it!
that's exactly what racing
would do for me!
- well, guess what?
- what?
news flash! neither one of us
is getting what we want!
what was that?
"diet cola hot springs."
"watch out for falling mentos."
yeah! check it out. look!
whoa!
you gotta watch out for the splash.
that stuff is broiling hot.
yeah, i got that. thank you.
what is this dump?
i think it's some sort of
unfinished bonus level.
yeah. it's pretty cool, huh?
i found that secret opening,
and now i live here.
see? look, look, look.
welcome to my home!
i sleep in these
candy wrappers.
i bundle myself up like
a little homeless lady.
by yourself?
with all this garbage around you?
well, yeah.
i mean, everyone here says
i'm just a mistake,
and that i wasn't even supposed to exist.
what do you expect?
listen, kid...
i know it's none of my business,
but why do you even
stick around this game?
you really don't know anything, do you?
glitches can't leave their games.
it's one of the joys of being me.
hey, what are you doing?
come on!
i know it's a dump,
but it's all i got.
if you're going to be a racer,
you have to learn how to drive.
and you can't do that without a track.
whoa!
all right, now.
let's hustle up.
we've got some driving to do.
i'm going to learn to drive!
i'm going to learn to drive!
wait. do you know how to drive?
yeah! i mean,
i haven't done it, but...
look, i flew
a spaceship today, okay?
you crashed it.
just get in. how hard
can it be? okay...
start it up.
there we go. so there are
some buttons on the floor.
- pedals.
- pedals. right.
now, that's the go pedal.
that i believe is the stopper.
and this... wait.
what is this?
that doesn't do anything.
ooh, what does this
joystick do?
okay, good.
let's try that again.
<i>♪ i've been looking for
a driver who is qualified ♪</i>
<i>♪ so if you think that you're the one
step into my ride ♪</i>
<i>♪ i'm a fine-tuned supersonic speed machine ♪</i>
<i>♪ got a sunroof top and a gangster lead ♪</i>
<i>♪ so if you feel it,
let me know, know, know ♪</i>
<i>♪ so start me up
and watch me go, go, go, go ♪</i>
<i>♪ get you where you wanna go,
if you know what i mean ♪</i>
<i>♪ got a ride that's smoother than a limousine ♪</i>
<i>♪ 'cause it's 0 to 60 in 3.5 ♪</i>
push pedal shift it.
<i>♪ baby, you got the keys ♪</i>
that's good. keep going!
shift it again!
<i>♪ now shut up and drive, drive, drive ♪</i>
<i>♪ shut up and drive, drive, drive ♪</i>
i told you,
racing's in my code!
<i>♪ so if you feel it,
let me know, know, know ♪</i>
i got that medal in the bag!
hey, ralphie, watch this!
<i>♪ get you where you wanna go,
if you know what i mean ♪</i>
<i>♪ got a ride that's smoother than a limousine ♪</i>
whoo-hoo!
<i>♪ 'cause it's 0 to 60 in 3.5 ♪</i>
<i>♪ baby, you got the keys ♪</i>
- look out!
- whoa!
<i>♪ shut up and drive, drive, drive ♪</i>
hot cola!
<i>♪ now shut up and drive ♪</i>
so how did i do?
um...
well, you almost blew up
the whole mountain.
right, right.
that's a good note.
you got to get that
glitch under control, kid.
okay, i will, i will.
and then you think
i got a chance?
um...
tiny.
yes, i'm going to win!
i'm going to win!
i'm going to win!
- top shelf.
- top shelf.
did you find her?
tell me you found her.
you didn't?
go. leave me.
up, up, down, down...
start!
the code. it's the sweet
lifeblood of the game.
where are you? let's see...
stadium, no. jumbotron.
ha-ha! there it is.
the winner's cup.
one of these things is not
like the others... it's you!
we're going to give you
a nice new home.
success!
sour bill, i'm going out.
you're in charge of the castle
until i get back.
your face is still red.
you might want to hit it
again with your hammer.
oh, that's not blunt force trauma, ma'am.
that's just the honey glow
in my cheeks.
okay.
ma'am, i just gotta tell you...
you are one dynamite gal.
wow, you are one dynamite gal.
one dynamite gal.
dynamite gal.
dynamite gal.
dynamite...
get out.
all i said is
you're a dynamite gal.
i said get out!
jiminey jaminey.
yes?
i'm fix-it felix, jr., sir,
from the game <i>fix-it felix, jr.</i>
have you seen my friend ralph?
wreck-it ralph?
yes. yes, that's him!
should have locked him up
when we had the chance.
locked him up?
i'm not making
the same mistake with you.
hurry, hurry!
let's go. time's a-wastin'.
come on, ralph!
this is it.
this is really happening.
i almost don't believe it.
i mean, i have dreamt about it
for so long, and now...
and now... now i think i'm
going to puke, actually.
i mean, i think i might puke.
you know, like a "vurp."
a what?
vomit and a burp together,
and you can taste it,
and it's just like rising up.
this is so exciting!
yes, it is. it's exciting.
am i ready to be a real racer?
ralph, what if the gamers
don't like me?
who doesn't love a brat
with dirty hair? come on.
those people are going
to love you. you know why?
- because you're a winner.
- i'm a winner.
- and you're adorable!
- i'm adorable!
and everyone loves
an adorable winner!
yeah!
okay, come on. listen to me.
if you get nervous,
just keep telling yourself,
"i must win ralph's medal
or his life will be ruined."
- and have fun. got it?
- got it.
whoa!
wait!
hold on!
where are you going?
i forgot something!
i'll be right back!
kids.
ralph! there you are. hello!
you! i come alone, unarmed.
i've had enough of you,
pillow pants!
please. calm down!
please, look. don't!
i'm going to beat
the filling out of you!
you wouldn't hit a guy
with glasses, would you? ha!
you hit a guy with glasses.
that's... well played.
what do you want, candy?
listen, i just want to
talk to you.
i'm not interested in anything
you have to say.
but how about this?
are you interested in this?
my medal. how did you...
it doesn't matter.
it's yours! go ahead, take it.
whoa.
all i ask
is that you hear me out.
about what?
ralph, do you know
what the hardest part
about being a king is?
doing what's right,
no matter what.
get to the point.
point being, i need your help.
sad as it is, vanellope
cannot be allowed to race.
why are you people
so against her?
i'm not against her!
i'm trying to protect her!
if vanellope wins that race,
<i>she'll be added</i>
<i>to the race roster.</i>
<i>then gamers can choose her</i>
<i>as their avatar.</i>
<i>and when they see her glitching</i>
<i>and twitching</i>
<i>and just being herself,</i>
<i>they'll think our game</i>
<i>is broken.</i>
<i>we'll be put</i>
<i>out of order for good.</i>
<i>all my subjects</i>
<i>will be homeless.</i>
<i>but there's one who cannot</i>
<i>escape because she's a glitch.</i>
help! somebody, help! help!
<i>and when the game's plug is pulled,</i>
no!
she'll die with it.
you don't know
that will happen.
the gamers could love her.
and if they don't?
i know it's tough,
but heroes have to make
the tough choices, don't they?
she can't race, ralph,
but she won't listen to me.
so can i count on you to talk
a little sense into her?
very good.
i'll give you two
some time alone.
i'm back!
did you miss me?
yeah...
can we talk for a second?
wait. first, kneel down.
- what? no, we really...
- will you just do it?
okay.
- now, close your eyes.
- vanellope...
shush! close them!
okay. open them up.
"to stinkbrain". gee, thanks.
turn it over.
i made it for you.
just in case we don't win.
not that i think there's even
a remote chance
we're not going to win.
thanks, kid. listen...
now rise, my royal chump.
i've got a date with destiny.
ralph, come on.
move your molasses.
um...
- i've been thinking.
- that's dangerous.
who cares about this
stupid race anyway? right?
that's not very funny, ralph.
no, i'm serious,
and it was really fun
to build the car and everything...
but maybe you shouldn't do it.
hello? is ralph in there?
i'd like to speak to him,
please.
look, what i'm saying is
you can't be a racer.
what?
why would you...
wait a minute.
no!
where did you get this?
look, i'm going to be
straight with you, kid.
i've been talking
to king candy.
- king candy?
- yeah.
you sold me out?
no, i didn't... listen.
you don't understand.
no, i understand plenty.
traitor!
i'm not a traitor. listen.
you're a rat!
and i don't need you, and
i can win the race on my own.
but i'm trying
to save your skin, kid!
put me down! let me go!
no, you listen to me.
do you know what's gonna happen
when the players see you glitching?
they gonna think the game's broken.
i don't care! you're a liar!
no! you better care, because if
your game goes out of order,
- you go down with the ship, little sister!
- i'm not listening to you!
get out of my way!
i'm going to that race!
no, you're not!
take me down from here,
ralph, right now!
no. i'm doing this
for your own good!
wait, wait, wait.
no. no.
no, no, no, no, no!
please, ralph!
no!
stop it! stop it! no!
you really are a bad guy.
hello? anybody home?
felix? mary?
well, you actually went and did it.
gene. where is everybody?
they're gone.
after felix went to find you
and then didn't come back...
everyone panicked
and abandoned ship.
but i'm here now.
it's too late, ralph.
litwak's pulling our plug
in the morning.
but never let it be said
that i'm not a man of my word.
the place is yours, ralph.
enjoy.
gene, wait! wait!
listen, this is not
what i wanted!
well, what did you want, ralph?
i don't know. i just...
i was just tired of
living alone in the garbage.
well, now you can live alone
in the penthouse.
hey, cough drop.
explain something to me.
if vanellope was never meant to exist,
then why is her picture on
the side of the game console?
what's going on
in this candy-coated
heart of darkness?
nothing.
- talk!
- no.
- i'll lick you.
- you wouldn't.
yeah?
that's like sandpaper!
wonder how many
licks it will take
to get to your center?
it'll take it to my grave!
fair enough.
they call you
sour bill for a reason.
- had enough yet?
- okay, okay. i'll talk, i'll talk!
vanellope was a racer
until king candy tried to delete her code!
<i>tried to delete her code?</i>
<i>so that's why she's a glitch!</i>
<i>why is he doing this to her?</i>
i don't know!
suit yourself.
no, no, no!
i swear i don't know!
<i>he literally locked up</i>
<i>our memories.</i>
<i>and i cannot remember!</i>
<i>nobody can!</i>
but i do know this.
he'll do anything
to keep her from racing.
because if she crosses
the finish line,
the game will reset and
she won't be a glitch anymore!
where is she now?
in the fungeon
with fix-it felix.
felix?
i'm sorry! that's all i know!
that's all i know, i swear!
now, please, don't put me back
in your filthy mouth again!
stick around.
yes, okay, i will. i will.
thank you!
come on.
i know you're out there.
saccharine-saturated nightmare!
but... where?
doomsday and armageddon just
had a baby and it is ugly!
hello? hello?
somebody! anybody!
please let me out!
what's he say?
i'm gonna wreck it!
why do i fix
everything i touch?
bam!
- felix!
- ralph!
i'm so glad to see you!
wait. no, i'm not.
what do you have to say for yourself?
wait! i don't want to hear it.
i'm not talking to you!
okay, don't talk. that's fine.
but you have to fix
this go-kart for me pronto.
i don't have to do boo!
forgive my potty mouth.
i'm just so, so cross with you!
do you have any idea
what you put me through?
i ran higgledy-piggledy all
over creation looking for you.
i almost drowned
in chocolate milk-mix!
and then... i met
the most dynamite gal.
she gives me the honey
glow something awful.
but she rebuffed my affections.
and then i got thrown in jail!
felix, pull yourself together.
no! ralph. you don't know what
it's like to be rejected
and treated like a criminal!
yes, i do.
that's every day of my life.
it is?
which is why i ran off and tried
to be a good guy, but i'm not!
i'm just a bad guy,
and i need your help.
there's a little girl
whose only hope is this kart.
please, felix, fix it.
and i promise i will never try
to be good again.
i know, i know, i'm an idiot.
- and?
- and a real numskull.
- and?
- a selfish diaper baby.
and?
and...
a stinkbrain?
the stinkiest brain ever.
<i>my sweet subjects,</i>
<i>i can without a pinch</i>
<i>of hesitation assure you</i>
<i>that i have never been</i>
<i>so happy in all my life</i>
<i>to say the following words:</i>
<i>let the random roster race commence!</i>
okay, remember,
you don't have to win.
just cross that finish line,
and you'll be a real racer.
i'm already a real racer.
and i'm going to win.
<i>power up!</i>
whoa!
<i>a la mode!</i>
<i>sweet seekers!</i>
have some candy.
behind you!
in front of you!
- it's the glitch!
- the glitch?
light them up, candlehead.
<i>what's this? cherry bombs!</i>
i told you. you're just
an accident waiting to happen.
my candle!
all right.
gotta keep it under control.
no more glitching.
okay, kid.
let's finish this thing
without any more surprises.
hope you're happy, junkpile.
this game is going down,
and it's all your fault.
my lady, you came back.
can it, fix-it!
that cy-bug you brought
with you multiplied.
no. it died in the taffy
swamp. believe me, i...
bullroar.
listen up, people. head to
game central station now!
move it! let's go! let's go!
go! go! go!
no!
get off of my track!
hey!
what, are you crazy!
i forbid you to cross
that finish line!
knock it off!
ralph, look!
kid!
stop it!
i'm not letting you undo
all my hard work!
is that...
no way!
what the... who are you?
i'm turbo,
the greatest racer ever!
and i did not reprogram
this world to let you
and that halitosis-riddled warthog
take it away from me!
turbo-tastic.
end of the line, glitch!
glitch. that's it.
come on, vanellope.
i know you said
you wouldn't do it again.
but you're going to do it one more time.
just focus and concentrate.
and glitch!
sweet mother of monkey milk!
i did it!
no!
bring it home, kid!
the finish line is wide open!
no!
kid! are you okay?
i'm fine. i'm fine.
let's finish this race!
oh my land.
all right. come on.
we gotta get out of here.
but i didn't cross
the finish line!
there is no finish line!
move it or lose it, people.
everybody, out. now!
ralph, it's not going to work!
we gotta try!
kid!
ralph, i told you
i can't leave the game.
- come on. get through.
- ralph! stop!
it's got to work!
stop, it's no use.
it's okay, ralph.
all right, fix-it.
that's everyone. now, we've
got to blow up this exit.
just go. go without me.
- but what about this game?
- nothing we can do about it.
without a beacon, there's no way
to stop these monsters.
beacon?
stay with felix.
let me borrow that thing, lady.
- ralph! where are you going?
- i got some wrecking to do!
i'll meet you
at the finish line!
no! wait!
fix-it, get behind me!
come on!
one more! one...
welcome to the boss level!
turbo.
because of you, ralph,
i'm now the most powerful
virus in the arcade!
i can take over
any game i want.
i should thank you.
but it would be more fun
to kill you.
get back here, little guy!
have some candy!
where do you think
you're going?
i'm not through with you yet.
up we go!
no!
ralph!
fall back.
kid!
vanellope!
look at that.
it's your little friend.
let's watch her die together,
shall we?
no!
it's game over for both of you.
no. just for me!
- ralph!
- vanellope!
i'm bad, and that's good.
i will never be good,
and that's not bad.
there's no one i'd rather be...
than me.
kid!
don't worry.
i got it under control.
you fools! why are you
going into the light...
no! no, no, no. yes...
no! yes... no!
go into the light!
whoa!
chocolate?
it's chocolate!
i love chocolate!
beautiful chocolate!
yeah!
you did it, ralph!
way to go, brother!
i... excuse...
all fixed.
- you ready for this?
- as ready as i'll ever be.
whoa!
what's with
all the magic sparkles?
princess vanellope?
now i remember.
all hail the rightful ruler of
<i>sugar rush...</i>
princess vanellope.
i remember. she's our princess!
oh! that's right!
we are so sorry
about the way we treated you.
yeah, those were jokes!
i was just doing
what taffyta told me to do!
tut-tut.
as your merciful princess,
i hereby decree
that everyone who was ever
mean to me shall be
executed.
what? no, please!
oh my land.
this place just got interesting.
i don't want to die!
i'm just kidding.
stop crying, taffyta.
i'm trying, but it won't stop.
wow.
so this is the real you.
princess.
aw, ralph, what are you, nuts?
come on. this isn't me.
this is me.
look, the code may say
i'm a princess.
but i know who
i really am, ralph,
i'm a racer with
the greatest superpower ever.
i was here, i was there.
i was glitching
through the walls.
i'm not giving that up.
um, pardon me for asking,
but without a princess,
who's going to lead us?
yeah. who?
me. i'm thinking
more along the lines of
a constitutional democracy.
president vanellope von schweetz.
has a nice ring to it,
don't you think?
fix-it, wreck-it,
the arcade's about to open.
let's move 'em out.
you know, you could just stay here
and live in the castle.
you'd have your own wing
where no one would ever
complain about your stench.
or treat you bad ever again.
you could be happy.
i'm already happy.
i've got the coolest friend in the world.
and besides,
i've got a job to do, too.
it may not be as fancy
as being president,
but it's my duty.
and it's a big duty!
ralph, are you coming, brother?
see ya later, president fart feathers.
<i>au revoir, admiral nnderpants.</i>
and farewell,
baroness boogerface.
goodbye, major body odor!
- <i>hasta la vista</i> you...
- ralph!
- all right. to be continued.
- yeah!
hooray!
<i>i'm gonna wreck it!</i>
hey! ralph's back!
isn't that great!
the gang's all here!
so, i'm happy to report,
and you'll be happy to hear,
i'm taking life
one game at a time.
all right! yeah, ralph!
<i>of course,</i>
<i>the job hasn't changed.</i>
<i>but, news flash,</i>
<i>the nicelanders</i>
<i>are being nice to me!</i>
<i>and that got me thinking about</i>
<i>those poor guys left</i>
<i>without a game.</i>
- <i>so here's what we did.</i>
- <i>we're gonna wreck it!</i>
<i>we asked them to help ust</i>
<i>on the bonus levels.</i>
<i>we can fix it!</i>
<i>i'm telling you guy: we haven't been</i>
<i>this popular in years.</i>
<i>it's crazy. wow!</i>
<i>the gamers say we're "retro",</i>
<i>which i think means</i>
<i>"old but cool".</i>
<i>and i decided that</i>
<i>living in the dump</i>
<i>wasn't making me</i>
<i>feel very good,</i>
<i>so i cleaned it up,</i>
<i>built myself a little shack.</i>
<i>and a couple</i>
<i>for the new guys, too.</i>
<i>well, with a little help</i>
<i>from felix.</i>
<i>oh. and guess who was the best man</i>
<i>at his and calhoun's wedding.</i>
<i>that's right, my friends,</i>
<i>old ham hands himself.</i>
<i>very elegant affair.</i>
<i>you should've seen it.</i>
<i>lot of grandeur.</i>
<i>and not a single bug.</i>
<i>and let's just say,</i>
<i>some tears were shed.</i>
<i>and you gotta say,</i>
<i>the best part of my day</i>
<i>is when i get thrown off the roof.</i>
<i>because when the nicelanders lift me up,</i>
<i>i get a perfect view of <i> sugar rush.
<i>and i can see vanellope racing.</i>
<i>yes!</i>
<i>the kid's a natural.</i>
<i>and the players love her,</i>
<i>glitch and all.</i>
<i>just like i knew they would.</i>
<i>turns out i don't need a medal</i>
<i>to tell me i'm a good guy.</i>
<i>'cause if that</i>
<i>little kid likes me...</i>
<i>how bad can i be?</i>
<i>♪ when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ switch on the sky
and the stars glow for you ♪</i>
<i>♪ go see the world
'cause it's all so brand new ♪</i>
<i>♪ don't close your eyes
'cause your future's ready to shine ♪</i>
<i>♪ it's just a matter of time,
before we learn how to fly ♪</i>
<i>♪ welcome to the rhythm of the night ♪</i>
<i>♪ there's something in the air
you can't deny ♪</i>
<i>♪ it's been fun
but now i've got to go ♪</i>
<i>♪ life is way too short to take it slow ♪</i>
<i>♪ but before i go and hit the road ♪</i>
<i>♪ i gotta know, 'til then,
when can we do this again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can we do this again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ i gotta know,
when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ joined at the hip,
yeah your sidekick needs you ♪</i>
<i>♪ life is a trip down the road that leads you ♪</i>
<i>♪ look all around at all the mountains
you haven't climbed ♪</i>
<i>♪ it's just a matter of time,
before we learn how to fly ♪</i>
<i>♪ welcome to the rhythm of the night ♪</i>
<i>♪ there's something in the air you can't deny ♪</i>
<i>♪ it's been fun
but now i've got to go ♪</i>
<i>♪ life is way too short to take it slow ♪</i>
<i>♪ but before i go and hit the road ♪</i>
<i>♪ i gotta know, 'til then,
when can we do this again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can we do this again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ i gotta know,
when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ don't close your eyes
'cause your future's ready to shine ♪</i>
<i>♪ it's just a matter of time,
before we learn how to fly ♪</i>
<i>♪ welcome to the rhythm of the night ♪</i>
<i>♪ there's something in the air you can't deny ♪</i>
<i>♪ so let me know before i wave goodbye ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can we do this again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can we do this again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ yeah, it's been fun
but now i've got to go ♪</i>
<i>♪ life is way too short to take it slow ♪</i>
<i>♪ but before i go and hit the road
tell me when ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can i see you again? ♪</i>
<i>♪ when can i see you again? ♪</i>
♪ <i>donna michi datte,<i> ♪
all roads
♪ <i>massugu janai darou<i> ♪
aren’t straight
♪ <i>sou magarikunette<i> ♪
yes, they’re windy
♪ <i>dekoboko shiteru hazusa<i> ♪
and bumpy most likely
♪ <i>tsurai koto tokiniwa aruyone<i> ♪
things can get rough from time to time
♪ <i>bokutachi wa soredemo hashiruyo<i> ♪
we’ll keep running though
♪ <i>amai mono demo ikaga?<i> ♪
would you care for something sweet?
<i>♪ s-u-g-a-r
jump into your racing car ♪</i>
<i>♪ it’s a sugar rush!
sugar rush! ♪</i>
<i>♪ s-u-g-a-r
jump into your racing car ♪</i>
<i>♪ it’s a sugar rush!
sugar rush! ♪</i>
♪ <i>kanashiku nattara<i> ♪
if you get sad
♪ <i>mabuta wo tojite goran<i> ♪
just close your eyes
♪ <i>hora yume no naka nara<i> ♪
see, in your dreams
♪ <i>namida mo wasurerareru<i> ♪
you can forget your tears
♪ <i>moshi kokode ensuto shitatte<i> ♪
even if our engine stalls here
♪ <i>bokutachi wa awatetari shinai<i> ♪
we won’t panic
♪ <i>amaimono demo ikaga?<i> ♪
would you care for something sweet?
<i>♪ s-u-g-a-r
jump into your racing car ♪</i>
<i>♪ it’s a sugar rush!
sugar rush! ♪</i>
<i>♪ s-u-g-a-r
jump into your racing car ♪</i>
<i>♪ it’s a sugar rush!
sugar rush! ♪</i>
<i>♪ come down the highway ♪</i>
♪ <i>kakemeguruyo<i> ♪
running through
<i>♪ open road ♪</i>
♪ <i>genki no gasoline<i> ♪
gasoline of energy
<i>♪ s-u-g-a-r
jump into your racing car ♪</i>
<i>♪ it’s a sugar rush!
sugar rush! ♪</i>
<i>♪ s-u-g-a-r
jump into your racing car ♪</i>
<i>♪ it’s a sugar rush!
sugar rush! ♪</i>
♪ <i>wreck-it ralph is a giant of a man</i> ♪
♪ <i>nine feet tall with really big hands</i> ♪
♪ <i>living in a stump on his very own land</i> ♪
♪ <i>until his world went crazy</i> ♪
♪ <i>he was minding his own business
on the day they came</i> ♪
♪ <i>they showed a piece of paper
saying “eminent domain”</i> ♪
♪ <i>they built an apartment building
saying progress was to blame</i> ♪
♪ <i>so he got mad
and he turned bad</i> ♪
♪ <i>brick by brick he’s gonna take his land back</i> ♪
♪ <i>wreck it, wreck-it ralph,
as fast as you can</i> ♪
♪ <i>you know you can do it
with your colossal hands</i> ♪
♪ <i>so don’t let fix-it felix
and that building stand</i> ♪
♪ <i>i wreck it
i fix it</i> ♪
♪ <i>you fixed it!</i> ♪
♪ <i>fix-it felix is a really great guy</i> ♪
♪ <i>watch him get all turbocharged
when he eats a pie</i> ♪
♪ <i>not just a superintendent,
he’s a super super guy</i> ♪
♪ <i>and everybody loves him</i> ♪
♪ <i>with his trusty tool belt
and steel-toed shoes</i> ♪
♪ <i>nicelanders believe that
felix just can’t lose</i> ♪
♪ <i>so when wreck-it ralph
starts to come unglued</i> ♪
♪ <i>he doesn’t get mad
‘cause he’s so rad</i> ♪
♪ <i>brick by brick he’s gonna build it back</i> ♪
♪ <i>fix it, fix-it felix,
as fast as you can</i> ♪
♪ <i>use the magic hammer
you got from your old man</i> ♪
♪ <i>‘cause you know wreck-it ralph
won’t let that building stand</i> ♪
♪ <i>i wreck it
i fix it</i> ♪
♪ <i>you fixed it!</i> ♪